<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Steinlein</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22054</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dietz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">I</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ullmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Experimentelle Ökologie und Ökosystembiologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2685201</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The polycarpic perennial Bunias orientalis L. (Brassicaceae) introduced to Central Europe in the 18th century recently entered a phase of rapid spread accompanied by sudden establishments of extensive dominance stands mainly on roadside locations. We studied vegetation structure and expansion rate of B. orientalis stands and performed a series of experiments to investigate key factors that underlie the colonizing and establishment of B. orientalis. Reiterated observations exposed a high current expansion rate of B. orientalis populations and vegetation surveys of B. orientalis stands showed that these stands were mainly composed of Artemisietea and Arrhenateretea species. Regeneration experiments with root fragments revealed high regeneration capacities: root fragments of 3 cm length showed 93% regeneration, varying water content (10-50% water loss) and separation into root cortex and root stele yielded regeneration of 30 to 50%. In a field study high regrowth after mowing with varying mowing intensity indicates B. orientalis to be well adapted to disturbed sites as its preferential locations for development of dominance stands. Vegetative growth parameters were studied in two controlled growth experiments with elevated nutrient availabilities. B. orientalis exhibited a high sensitivity to nutrient addition and rosette sizes of maximal 90 cm were reached. Biomass was comparable or even higher than that of native ruderals grown in the same experiment. Measurements of reproductive parameters revealed a high reproductive effort (0.2 to 0.45 g g(-1)) even under intense mowing regimes, resulting in a dense seed bank with maximal values of about 400 fruits (congruent to 550 seeds) l(-1) soil. With respect to colonization and establishment of B. orientalis the results of our study enable the formulation of three hypotheses.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>KLUWER ACADEMIC PUBL</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1996</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>regeneration</topic><topic>Bunias orientalis</topic><topic>colonization</topic><topic>relative growth rate</topic><topic>disturbance</topic><topic>invasion</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>VEGETATIO</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0042-3106</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1573-5052</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1996VJ80900007</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/BF00045206</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>125</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">73-82</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Steinlein, T., Dietz, H., &amp;amp; Ullmann, I. (1996). Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages. &lt;em&gt;VEGETATIO&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;125&lt;/em&gt;(1), 73-82.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Steinlein, Thomas, Dietz, H, and Ullmann, I. “Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages”. &lt;em&gt;VEGETATIO&lt;/em&gt; 125.1 (1996): 73-82.</mla>
<lncs>Steinlein, T., Dietz, H., Ullmann, I.: Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages. VEGETATIO. 125, 73-82 (1996).</lncs>
<ieee>T. Steinlein, H. Dietz, and I. Ullmann, “Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages”, &lt;em&gt;VEGETATIO&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 125, 1996,  pp. 73-82.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Steinlein, Thomas, Dietz, H, and Ullmann, I. 1996. “Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages”. &lt;em&gt;VEGETATIO&lt;/em&gt; 125 (1): 73-82.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Steinlein, T., Dietz, H., and Ullmann, I. (1996). Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages. &lt;em&gt;VEGETATIO&lt;/em&gt; 125, 73-82.</frontiers>
<apa>Steinlein, T., Dietz, H., &amp;amp; Ullmann, I. (1996). Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages. &lt;em&gt;VEGETATIO&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;125&lt;/em&gt;(1), 73-82.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Steinlein, H.  Dietz, and I.  Ullmann, “Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages”, &lt;em&gt;VEGETATIO&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1996&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;125&lt;/em&gt;, 73-82.</angewandte-chemie>
<aps>T.  Steinlein, H.  Dietz, and I.  Ullmann, Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages, VEGETATIO &lt;strong&gt;125&lt;/strong&gt;, 73-82 (1996).</aps>
<bio1>Steinlein T, Dietz H, Ullmann I (1996) &lt;br /&gt;Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages.&lt;br /&gt;VEGETATIO 125(1): 73-82.</bio1>
<harvard1>Steinlein, T., Dietz, H., &amp;amp; Ullmann, I., 1996. Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages. &lt;em&gt;VEGETATIO&lt;/em&gt;, 125(1), p 73-82.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Steinlein, T., Dietz, H. &amp;amp; Ullmann, I. (1996). Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages. &lt;em&gt;VEGETATIO&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;125&lt;/em&gt;(1), 73-82. KLUWER ACADEMIC PUBL. doi:10.1007/BF00045206.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Steinlein T, Dietz H, Ullmann I. Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages. &lt;em&gt;VEGETATIO&lt;/em&gt;. 1996;125(1):73-82.</ama>
<default>Steinlein T, Dietz H, Ullmann I (1996) &lt;br /&gt;VEGETATIO 125(1): 73-82.</default>
<wels>Steinlein, T.; Dietz, H.; Ullmann, I. (1996): Growth patterns of the alien perennial Bunias orientalis L (Brassicaceae) underlying its rising dominance in some native plant assemblages &lt;em&gt;VEGETATIO&lt;/em&gt;,125:(1): 73-82.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1638442</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:14:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-12-17T08:18:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1638442</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1638442</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
