<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rudolf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ahlswede</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">10479</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">János</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Körner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Mathematik</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Ahlswede_26.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1780380/2312894</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription><accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1977</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-20806</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">13-22</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Ahlswede, R., &amp;amp; Körner, J. (1977). On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory&lt;/em&gt;, 13-22.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>R. Ahlswede and J. Körner, “On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory&lt;/em&gt;,  Bucuresti: Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România, 1977,  pp.13-22.</ieee>
<mla>Ahlswede, Rudolf, and Körner, János. “On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory&lt;/em&gt;. Bucuresti: Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România, 1977. 13-22.</mla>
<lncs>Ahlswede, R., Körner, J.: On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels. Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory. p. 13-22. Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România, Bucuresti (1977).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Ahlswede, Rudolf, and Körner, János. 1977. “On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory&lt;/em&gt;, 13-22. Bucuresti: Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Ahlswede, R., &amp;amp; Körner, J. (1977). On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory&lt;/em&gt;, 13-22.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Ahlswede, and J.  Körner, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory&lt;/em&gt;, Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România, Bucuresti, &lt;strong&gt;1977&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 13-22.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Ahlswede, R., and Körner, J. (1977). “On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory&lt;/em&gt; (Bucuresti: Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România), 13-22.</frontiers>
<harvard1>Ahlswede, R., &amp;amp; Körner, J., 1977. On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory&lt;/em&gt;.  Bucuresti: Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România, pp. 13-22.</harvard1>
<ama>Ahlswede R, Körner J. On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels. In:  &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory&lt;/em&gt;. Bucuresti: Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România;  1977: 13-22.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Ahlswede, R. &amp;amp; Körner, J. (1977). On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory&lt;/em&gt; (S. 13-22). Bucuresti: Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<aps>R.  Ahlswede and J.  Körner, On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory&lt;/em&gt; (Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România, Bucuresti, 1977), p. 13-22.</aps>
<bio1>Ahlswede R, Körner J (1977) &lt;br /&gt;On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory.  Bucuresti: Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România:  13-22.</bio1>
<wels>Ahlswede, R.; Körner, J. (1977): On the connection between the entropies of input and output distributions of discrete memoryless channels. In: Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory. Bucuresti: Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România.  S. 13-22.</wels>
<default>Ahlswede R, Körner J (1977)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the fifth Conference on Probability Theory. Bucuresti: Ed. Acad. Republicii Socialiste România:  13-22.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1780380</recordIdentifier><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-01-26T08:38:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1780380</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1780380</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
