<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space.</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mathias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Albert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">24825</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Pertti</namePart><namePart type="family">Joenniemi</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Arbeitsbereich 4 - Politik und Gesellschaft</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">5656050</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>NordREFO</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1997</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim.</title></titleInfo>
<part><extent unit="pages">85-118</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Albert, M. (1997): South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space. In: Pertti Joenniemi (Hrsg.):  Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim.. Stockholm: NordREFO.  S. 85-118.</wels>
<default>Albert M (1997)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim. Joenniemi  P (Ed);Stockholm: NordREFO:  85-118.</default>
<ama>Albert M. South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space. In: Joenniemi  P, ed. &lt;em&gt;Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim.&lt;/em&gt; Stockholm: NordREFO;  1997: 85-118.</ama>
<harvard1>Albert, M., 1997. South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space. In P.  Joenniemi, ed. &lt;em&gt;Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim.&lt;/em&gt;  Stockholm: NordREFO, pp. 85-118.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Albert, M. (1997). South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space. &lt;em&gt;Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim.&lt;/em&gt; (S. 85-118). Stockholm: NordREFO.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Albert M (1997) &lt;br /&gt;South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim. Joenniemi  P (Ed); Stockholm: NordREFO:  85-118.</bio1>
<aps>M.  Albert, South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space., in &lt;em&gt;Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim.&lt;/em&gt;, edited by P.  Joenniemi (NordREFO, Stockholm, 1997), p. 85-118.</aps>
<apa>Albert, M. (1997). South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space. In P.  Joenniemi (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim.&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 85-118). Stockholm: NordREFO.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Albert, in &lt;em&gt;Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim.&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: P. Joenniemi), Nordrefo, Stockholm, &lt;strong&gt;1997&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 85-118.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Albert, M. (1997). “South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space.” in &lt;em&gt;Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim.&lt;/em&gt;, ed. P.  Joenniemi (Stockholm: NordREFO), 85-118.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Albert, Mathias. 1997. “South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space.”. In &lt;em&gt;Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim.&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Pertti Joenniemi, 85-118. Stockholm: NordREFO.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee>M. Albert, “South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space.”, &lt;em&gt;Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim.&lt;/em&gt;, P. Joenniemi, ed.,  Stockholm: NordREFO, 1997,  pp.85-118.</ieee>
<mla>Albert, Mathias. “South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space.”. &lt;em&gt;Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim.&lt;/em&gt; Ed. Pertti Joenniemi. Stockholm: NordREFO, 1997. 85-118.</mla>
<lncs>Albert, M.: South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space. In: Joenniemi , P. (ed.) Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim. p. 85-118. NordREFO, Stockholm (1997).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Albert, M. (1997). South of Norden or Norden’s South? Germany and Baltic Political Space. In P.  Joenniemi (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Neo-Nationalism or Regionalism? The Restructuring of Political Space Around the Baltic Rim.&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 85-118). Stockholm: NordREFO.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1921393</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-29T11:17:48Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-12-02T19:28:03Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1921393</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1921393</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
