<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heinz-Hermann</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Büker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Friedrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grützmacher</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">41603</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Maria Elisa</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Crestoni</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ricci</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Chemie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10018</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The differences in the gas-phase basicities (GBs) of isomers can be used for a semi-quantitative mixture analysis. For this &apos;&apos;gas-phase titration&apos;&apos; method, the mixture of isomers is completely protonated in the external ion source of a FT-ion cyclotron resonance spectrometry (ICR) spectrometer and undergoes selective, stepwise deprotonation by reactions with appropriate bases within the FT-ICR cell. This method is demonstrated by the analysis of a mixture of three isomeric alkylpyridines differing in GB by 4 kJ mol(-1). &apos;&apos;Gas-phase titration&apos;&apos; is employed to detect the isomerization of gaseous para-xylenium ions XpH+ into the more stable ortho and meta isomers XoH+ and XmH+ by 1,2-methyl shifts around the aromatic ring. Strongly exoenergetic protonation of para-xylene X-p in the external ion source by chemical ionization (CI) (methane) and gas-phase titration of the resulting XH+ after transfer into the FT-ICR cell reveals isomerization of XpH+ into a mixture of less than or equal to 15 mol% XpH+, 25 +/- 3 mol% XoH+, and 60 +/- 4 mol% XmH+. The degree of isomerization depends clearly on the exoenergicity of the initial protonation and is significantly reduced for XH+ ions generated by CI (dimethyl ether). This effect is confirmed by an investigation of the controlled protonation of X-p by selected proton donors AH(+) (A = C2H5CN, CH3OH, C6H6, C3H6, H2O, C2H4) in the FT-ICR cell. This study shows that the chemical nature of A is also important for the degree of isomerization. The results are explained convincingly by assuming isomerization of the XpH+ ions through multiple 1,2-methyl shifts within a long lived ion/ molecule complex [A ... H+Xp], formed by proton transfer from AH(+) to X-p. The rearrangement is driven by the excess energy of the complex as a result of exothermic proton transfer and electrostatic activation of the complex, and competes with the dissociation of the excited complex. (C) 1997 Elsevier Science B.V.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1997</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>analysis</topic><topic>mixture</topic><topic>2-methyl shift</topic><topic>1</topic><topic>alkylarenium ions</topic><topic>proton transfer reaction</topic><topic>ion/molecule reaction</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0168-1176</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1997WV22200013</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/S0168-1176(96)04518-1</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>160</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1-3</number></detail><extent unit="pages">167-181</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Büker, H. - H., Grützmacher, H. - F., Crestoni, M. E., &amp;amp; Ricci, A. (1997). Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration. &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;160&lt;/em&gt;(1-3), 167-181.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs>Büker, H.-H., Grützmacher, H.-F., Crestoni, M.E., Ricci, A.: Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration. INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES. 160, 167-181 (1997).</lncs>
<mla>Büker, Heinz-Hermann, Grützmacher, Hans-Friedrich, Crestoni, Maria Elisa, and Ricci, Andreina. “Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration”. &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES&lt;/em&gt; 160.1-3 (1997): 167-181.</mla>
<ieee>H.-H. Büker, et al., “Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration”, &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 160, 1997,  pp. 167-181.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Büker, Heinz-Hermann, Grützmacher, Hans-Friedrich, Crestoni, Maria Elisa, and Ricci, Andreina. 1997. “Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration”. &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES&lt;/em&gt; 160 (1-3): 167-181.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Büker, H. - H., Grützmacher, H. - F., Crestoni, M. E., and Ricci, A. (1997). Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration. &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES&lt;/em&gt; 160, 167-181.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>H. - H.  Büker, H. - F.  Grützmacher, M. E.  Crestoni, and A.  Ricci, “Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration”, &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1997&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;160&lt;/em&gt;, 167-181.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Büker, H. - H., Grützmacher, H. - F., Crestoni, M. E., &amp;amp; Ricci, A. (1997). Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration. &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;160&lt;/em&gt;(1-3), 167-181.</apa>
<bio1>Büker H-H, Grützmacher H-F, Crestoni ME, Ricci A (1997) &lt;br /&gt;Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration.&lt;br /&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES 160(1-3): 167-181.</bio1>
<aps>H. - H.  Büker, et al., Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration, INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES &lt;strong&gt;160&lt;/strong&gt;, 167-181 (1997).</aps>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Büker, H.-H., Grützmacher, H.-F., Crestoni, M.E. &amp;amp; Ricci, A. (1997). Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration. &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;160&lt;/em&gt;(1-3), 167-181. ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV. doi:10.1016/S0168-1176(96)04518-1.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Büker, H.-H., et al., 1997. Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration. &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES&lt;/em&gt;, 160(1-3), p 167-181.</harvard1>
<ama>Büker H-H, Grützmacher H-F, Crestoni ME, Ricci A. Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration. &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES&lt;/em&gt;. 1997;160(1-3):167-181.</ama>
<default>Büker H-H, Grützmacher H-F, Crestoni ME, Ricci A (1997) &lt;br /&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES 160(1-3): 167-181.</default>
<wels>Büker, H. - H.; Grützmacher, H. - F.; Crestoni, M. E.; Ricci, A. (1997): Proton induced methyl group shifts in gaseous xylenium ions. Distinguishing isomers by gas-phase titration &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MASS SPECTROMETRY AND ION PROCESSES&lt;/em&gt;,160:(1-3): 167-181.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1637366</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:14:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-01-10T15:51:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1637366</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1637366</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
