<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Joanna</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pfaff-Czarnecka</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">15296</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">David N.</namePart><namePart type="family">Gellner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Krishna</namePart><namePart type="family">Hatchethu</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">5656060</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>Sage</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-0-7619-3650-3</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">71-104</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Pfaff-Czarnecka J (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours. Gellner DN, Hatchethu K (Eds); Governance, conflict and civic action series, 1. New Delhi: Sage:  71-104.</bio1>
<aps> J.  Pfaff-Czarnecka, Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence, in &lt;em&gt;Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours&lt;/em&gt;, edited by D. N.  Gellner and K.  Hatchethu, Governance, conflict and civic action series, &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; (Sage, New Delhi, 2008), p. 71-104.</aps>
<ama>Pfaff-Czarnecka J. Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence. In: Gellner DN, Hatchethu K, eds. &lt;em&gt;Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours&lt;/em&gt;. Governance, conflict and civic action series. Vol 1. New Delhi: Sage;  2008: 71-104.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Pfaff-Czarnecka, J. (2008). Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence (Governance, conflict and civic action series). &lt;em&gt;Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours&lt;/em&gt; (S. 71-104). New Delhi: Sage.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Pfaff-Czarnecka, J., 2008. Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence. In D. N.  Gellner &amp;amp; K.  Hatchethu, eds. &lt;em&gt;Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours&lt;/em&gt;. Governance, conflict and civic action series. no.1  New Delhi: Sage, pp. 71-104.</harvard1>
<default>Pfaff-Czarnecka J (2008)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours. Gellner DN, Hatchethu K (Eds); Governance, conflict and civic action series, 1. New Delhi: Sage:  71-104.</default>
<wels>Pfaff-Czarnecka, J. (2008): Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence. In: David N. Gellner; Krishna Hatchethu (Hrsg.):  Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours. New Delhi: Sage. (Governance, conflict and civic action series, 1).  S. 71-104.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Pfaff-Czarnecka, J. (2008). Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence. In D. N.  Gellner &amp;amp; K.  Hatchethu (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Governance, conflict and civic action series: Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 71-104). New Delhi: Sage.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs> Pfaff-Czarnecka, J.: Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence. In: Gellner, D.N. and Hatchethu, K. (eds.) Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours. Governance, conflict and civic action series. 1, p. 71-104. Sage, New Delhi (2008).</lncs>
<mla>Pfaff-Czarnecka, Joanna. “Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence”. &lt;em&gt;Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. David N. Gellner and Krishna Hatchethu. New Delhi: Sage, 2008.Vol. 1. Governance, conflict and civic action series. 71-104.</mla>
<ieee> J. Pfaff-Czarnecka, “Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence”, &lt;em&gt;Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours&lt;/em&gt;, D.N. Gellner and K. Hatchethu, eds., Governance, conflict and civic action series, vol. 1,  New Delhi: Sage, 2008,  pp.71-104.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Pfaff-Czarnecka, Joanna. 2008. “Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence”. In &lt;em&gt;Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours&lt;/em&gt;, ed. David N. Gellner and Krishna Hatchethu, 1:71-104. Governance, conflict and civic action series. New Delhi: Sage.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Pfaff-Czarnecka, J. (2008). “Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence” in &lt;em&gt;Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours&lt;/em&gt;, Gellner, D. N., and Hatchethu, K. eds. Governance, conflict and civic action series, vol. 1, (New Delhi: Sage), 71-104.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Pfaff-Czarnecka, in &lt;em&gt;Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: D.N. Gellner, K. Hatchethu), Sage, New Delhi, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 71-104.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Pfaff-Czarnecka, J. (2008). Distributional Coalitions in Nepal: An Essay on Democratization, Capture, and (Lack of) Confidence. In D. N.  Gellner &amp;amp; K.  Hatchethu (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Governance, conflict and civic action series: Vol. 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Local Democracy in South Asia: Microprocesses of Democratization in Nepal and its Neighbours&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 71-104). New Delhi: Sage.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1860748</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-08-03T10:03:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-08-03T10:03:03Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1860748</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1860748</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
