<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M. F.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Del Papa</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pistorio</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">L. J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Balague</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">W. O.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Draghi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">C.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wegener</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Perticari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Niehaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21913</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lagares</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">40200282</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2685540</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The acid tolerance of Sinorhizobium meliloti in culture media and in soils is considered a useful criteria to select for strains with improved survival in agricultural acidic soils. Using a glass tube system with gamma-irradiated soil at different pH values, we analysed the survival of two different alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia: S. meliloti (pH(limit) for growth 5.6-6.0) and the acid-tolerant Rhizobium sp. LPU83, closely related to the strain Rhizobium sp. Or191 (pH(limit) for growth below 5.0). Although the acid-tolerant rhizobia showed a slightly better survival during the first months in acid soil (pH=5.6), none of the strains could be detected 2 months after inoculation (bacterial counts were below 10(3) colony-forming units (cfu)/30 g of soil). The inclusion of two alfalfa plants/glass tube with soil, however, supported the persistence of both types of rhizobia at pH 5.6 for over 2 months with counts higher than 9x10(6) cfu/30 g of soil. Remarkably, in the presence of alfalfa the cell densities reached by S. meliloti were higher than those reached by strain LPU83, which started to decline 1 week after inoculation. Although more acid-sensitive in the culture medium than the Or191-like rhizobia, in the presence of the host plant the S. meliloti strains showed to be better adapted to the free-living condition, irrespective of the pH of the soil.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2003</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>alfalfa</topic><topic>glass tube system</topic><topic>soil acidity</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Biology and Fertility of Soils</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0178-2762</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1432-0789</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000187186400007</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/s00374-003-0690-6</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>39</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">112-116</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee>M.F. Del Papa, et al., “A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics”, &lt;em&gt;Biology and Fertility of Soils&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 39, 2003,  pp. 112-116.</ieee>
<lncs>Del Papa, M.F., Pistorio, M., Balague, L.J., Draghi, W.O., Wegener, C., Perticari, A., Niehaus, K., Lagares, A.: A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics. Biology and Fertility of Soils. 39, 112-116 (2003).</lncs>
<mla>Del Papa, M. F., Pistorio, M., Balague, L. J., Draghi, W. O., Wegener, C., Perticari, A., Niehaus, Karsten, and Lagares, A. “A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics”. &lt;em&gt;Biology and Fertility of Soils&lt;/em&gt; 39.2 (2003): 112-116.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Del Papa, M. F., Pistorio, M., Balague, L. J., Draghi, W. O., Wegener, C., Perticari, A., Niehaus, K., et al. (2003). A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics. &lt;em&gt;Biology and Fertility of Soils&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;39&lt;/em&gt;(2), 112-116.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>M. F.  Del Papa, M.  Pistorio, L. J.  Balague, W. O.  Draghi, C.  Wegener, A.  Perticari, K.  Niehaus, and A.  Lagares, “A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics”, &lt;em&gt;Biology and Fertility of Soils&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2003&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;39&lt;/em&gt;, 112-116.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Del Papa, M. F., Pistorio, M., Balague, L. J., Draghi, W. O., Wegener, C., Perticari, A., Niehaus, K., et al. (2003). A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics. &lt;em&gt;Biology and Fertility of Soils&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;39&lt;/em&gt;(2), 112-116.</apa>
<frontiers>Del Papa, M. F., Pistorio, M., Balague, L. J., Draghi, W. O., Wegener, C., Perticari, A., Niehaus, K., and Lagares, A. (2003). A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics. &lt;em&gt;Biology and Fertility of Soils&lt;/em&gt; 39, 112-116.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Del Papa, M. F., Pistorio, M., Balague, L. J., Draghi, W. O., Wegener, C., Perticari, A., Niehaus, Karsten, and Lagares, A. 2003. “A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics”. &lt;em&gt;Biology and Fertility of Soils&lt;/em&gt; 39 (2): 112-116.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Del Papa MF, Pistorio M, Balague LJ, et al. A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics. &lt;em&gt;Biology and Fertility of Soils&lt;/em&gt;. 2003;39(2):112-116.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Del Papa, M.F., Pistorio, M., Balague, L.J., Draghi, W.O., Wegener, C., Perticari, A., Niehaus, K. &amp;amp; Lagares, A. (2003). A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics. &lt;em&gt;Biology and Fertility of Soils&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;39&lt;/em&gt;(2), 112-116. Springer. doi:10.1007/s00374-003-0690-6.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Del Papa, M.F., et al., 2003. A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics. &lt;em&gt;Biology and Fertility of Soils&lt;/em&gt;, 39(2), p 112-116.</harvard1>
<bio1>Del Papa MF, Pistorio M, Balague LJ, Draghi WO, Wegener C, Perticari A, Niehaus K, Lagares A (2003) &lt;br /&gt;A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics.&lt;br /&gt;Biology and Fertility of Soils 39(2): 112-116.</bio1>
<aps>M. F.  Del Papa, et al., A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics, Biology and Fertility of Soils &lt;strong&gt;39&lt;/strong&gt;, 112-116 (2003).</aps>
<wels>Del Papa, M. F.; Pistorio, M.; Balague, L. J.; Draghi, W. O.; Wegener, C.; Perticari, A.; Niehaus, K.; Lagares, A. (2003): A microcosm study on the influence of pH and the host-plant on the soil persistence of two alfalfa-nodulating rhizobia with different saprophytic and symbiotic characteristics &lt;em&gt;Biology and Fertility of Soils&lt;/em&gt;,39:(2): 112-116.</wels>
<default>Del Papa MF, Pistorio M, Balague LJ, Draghi WO, Wegener C, Perticari A, Niehaus K, Lagares A (2003) &lt;br /&gt;Biology and Fertility of Soils 39(2): 112-116.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1609443</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:58:37Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-12-22T11:41:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1609443</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1609443</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
