<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Steven Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Watt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Verena</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tellstroem</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Patschkowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">64842</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Karsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Niehaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21913</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">40200282</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2685540</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Three of the most abundant proteins (OmpW, MopB and SodM) of the extracellular proteome of Xanthomonas campestris pv. campestris were analysed in a luminol-based oxidative burst assay to identify novel pathogen-associated molecular patterns (PAMP). Tobacco cell suspension cultures were used as a model system to monitor elicitor induced plant defence reaction. The candidate proteins were isolated from two-dimensional gels prior to application to the oxidative burst assay. The superoxide dismutase (SodM) was the only isolated protein that could elicit a notable hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) production in tobacco cell cultures indicating the initiation of plant defence. An alignment of the SodM sequences from X. campestris pv. campestris and Escherichia coli revealed 55.7% identity and 29% of the sequence were substitutions for amino acids with similar physicochemical properties. By using a commercially available purified E coli derived SodM preparation, it was possible to show that the amino acid sequence of this protein is responsible for the elicitation of an oxidative burst reaction in the tobacco cell culture model. This suggests that the bacterial superoxide dismutase is a novel pathogen-associated molecular pattern. The minimal elicitor active sequence, however, is still elusive. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>two-dimensional gel</topic><topic>superoxide dismutase</topic><topic>plant defence</topic><topic>Xanthomonas campestris pv. campestris</topic><topic>proteome</topic><topic>extracellular</topic><topic>pathogen-associated molecular pattern</topic><topic>electrophoresis</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Journal of Biotechnology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0168-1656</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">16603270</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000241262200009</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/j.jbiotec.2006.02.022</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>126</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">78-86</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Watt, S. A., Tellstroem, V., Patschkowski, T., &amp;amp; Niehaus, K. (2006). Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;126&lt;/em&gt;(1), 78-86.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>S.A. Watt, et al., “Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures”, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 126, Elsevier, 2006,  pp.78-86.</ieee>
<lncs>Watt, S.A., Tellstroem, V., Patschkowski, T., Niehaus, K.: Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures. Journal of Biotechnology. 126, p. 78-86. Elsevier (2006).</lncs>
<mla>Watt, Steven Alexander, Tellstroem, Verena, Patschkowski, Thomas, and Niehaus, Karsten. “Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures”. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;. Elsevier, 2006.Vol. 126. 78-86.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Watt, Steven Alexander, Tellstroem, Verena, Patschkowski, Thomas, and Niehaus, Karsten. 2006. “Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures”. In &lt;em&gt;Journal of Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;, 126:78-86. Elsevier.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<angewandte-chemie>S. A.  Watt, V.  Tellstroem, T.  Patschkowski, and K.  Niehaus, in &lt;em&gt;Journal of Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;, Elsevier, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 78-86.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Watt, S. A., Tellstroem, V., Patschkowski, T., &amp;amp; Niehaus, K. (2006). Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;126&lt;/em&gt;(1), 78-86.</apa>
<frontiers>Watt, S. A., Tellstroem, V., Patschkowski, T., and Niehaus, K. (2006). “Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures” in &lt;em&gt;Journal of Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 126, (Elsevier), 78-86.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Watt, S.A., Tellstroem, V., Patschkowski, T. &amp;amp; Niehaus, K. (2006). Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt; (S. 78-86). Elsevier. doi:10.1016/j.jbiotec.2006.02.022.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Watt, S.A., et al., 2006. Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures. In &lt;em&gt;Journal of Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;. no.126  Elsevier, pp. 78-86.</harvard1>
<ama>Watt SA, Tellstroem V, Patschkowski T, Niehaus K. Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures. In:  &lt;em&gt;Journal of Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 126. Elsevier;  2006: 78-86.</ama>
<bio1>Watt SA, Tellstroem V, Patschkowski T, Niehaus K (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Journal of Biotechnology. 126. Elsevier:  78-86.</bio1>
<aps>S. A.  Watt, et al., Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures, in &lt;em&gt;Journal of Biotechnology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;126&lt;/strong&gt; (Elsevier, 2006), p. 78-86.</aps>
<wels>Watt, S. A.; Tellstroem, V.; Patschkowski, T.; Niehaus, K. (2006): Identification of the bacterial superoxide dismutase (SodM) as plant-inducible elicitor of an oxidative burst reaction in tobacco cell suspension cultures. In: Journal of Biotechnology. Elsevier. (126).  S. 78-86.</wels>
<default>Watt SA, Tellstroem V, Patschkowski T, Niehaus K (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Journal of Biotechnology. 126. Elsevier:  78-86.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1597426</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:18:50Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-12-22T11:33:04Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1597426</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1597426</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
