<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">K</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kratz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hellweg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">19511146</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">W</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eimer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Physikalische Chemie III</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17981</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The structural and dynamic properties of thermosensitive neutral and partially charged colloidal microgels of poly(N-isopropylacrylamide-co-acrylic acid) (PNIPAM/AAc) have been investigated by neutron and light scattering techniques. Introduction of cross-linker induces topological constraints into the polymer network, and hence reduces the swelling capability of the particles as expressed in the variation of their hydrodynamic radii. Small-angle neutron scattering experiments reveal that below the transition temperature the inhomogeneous structure of the microgel consists of local solid-like frozen regions and solution-like regions where the polymer chain behaves as in semidilute polymer solution. The temperature-induced collapse leads to a strongly segregated micro-phase separated particle. The swelling of charged microgels is determined by their charge density, controlled through the amount of acrylic acid comonomer, the pH, and the salt concentration.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1998</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>volume</topic><topic>colloides</topic><topic>scattering</topic><topic>light</topic><topic>microgel</topic><topic>neutron scattering</topic><topic>transitions</topic><topic>phase</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0005-9021</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000077145200018</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/bbpc.19981021119</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>102</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>11</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1603-1608</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Kratz K, Hellweg T, Eimer W (1998)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie. 102. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH:  1603-1608.</default>
<wels>Kratz, K.; Hellweg, T.; Eimer, W. (1998): Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels. In: Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH. (102).  S. 1603-1608.</wels>
<bio1>Kratz K, Hellweg T, Eimer W (1998) &lt;br /&gt;Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie. 102. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH:  1603-1608.</bio1>
<aps>K.  Kratz, T.  Hellweg, and W.  Eimer, Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels, in &lt;em&gt;Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;102&lt;/strong&gt; (WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH, 1998), p. 1603-1608.</aps>
<ama>Kratz K, Hellweg T, Eimer W. Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels. In:  &lt;em&gt;Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 102. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH;  1998: 1603-1608.</ama>
<harvard1>Kratz, K., Hellweg, T., &amp;amp; Eimer, W., 1998. Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels. In &lt;em&gt;Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie&lt;/em&gt;. no.102  WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH, pp. 1603-1608.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kratz, K., Hellweg, T. &amp;amp; Eimer, W. (1998). Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels. &lt;em&gt;Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1603-1608). WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH. doi:10.1002/bbpc.19981021119.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kratz, K, Hellweg, Thomas, and Eimer, W. 1998. “Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels”. In &lt;em&gt;Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie&lt;/em&gt;, 102:1603-1608. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Kratz, K., Hellweg, T., and Eimer, W. (1998). “Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels” in &lt;em&gt;Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 102, (WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH), 1603-1608.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Kratz, T.  Hellweg, and W.  Eimer, in &lt;em&gt;Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie&lt;/em&gt;, Wiley-V C H Verlag Gmbh, &lt;strong&gt;1998&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1603-1608.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Kratz, K., Hellweg, T., &amp;amp; Eimer, W. (1998). Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels. &lt;em&gt;Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;102&lt;/em&gt;(11), 1603-1608.</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kratz, K., Hellweg, T., &amp;amp; Eimer, W. (1998). Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels. &lt;em&gt;Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;102&lt;/em&gt;(11), 1603-1608.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Kratz, K, Hellweg, Thomas, and Eimer, W. “Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels”. &lt;em&gt;Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie&lt;/em&gt;. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH, 1998.Vol. 102. 1603-1608.</mla>
<lncs>Kratz, K., Hellweg, T., Eimer, W.: Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels. Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie. 102, p. 1603-1608. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH (1998).</lncs>
<ieee>K. Kratz, T. Hellweg, and W. Eimer, “Effect of connectivity and charge density on the swelling and local structural and dynamic properties of colloidal PNIPAM microgels”, &lt;em&gt;Berichte der Bunsen-Gesellschaft für Physikalische Chemie&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 102, WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH, 1998,  pp.1603-1608.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1624380</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:20:15Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-10-06T16:03:32Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1624380</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1624380</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
