<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ottl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">R</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Battistuta</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pieper</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tschesche</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">19406</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">W</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bode</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">K</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kuhn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">L</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Moroder</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Biochemie I</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17967</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">A heterotrimeric collagen peptide was designed and synthesized which contains the collagenase cleavage site (P-4-P&apos;(9/10)) of type I collagen linked to a C-terminal cystine-knot, and N-terminally extended with (Gly-Pro-Hyp)(5) triplets for stabilization of the triple-helical conformation, By employing a newly developed regioselective cysteine pairing strategy based exclusively on thiol disulfide exchange reactions, we succeeded in assembling in high yields and in a reproducible manner the triple-stranded cystine peptide, While the single chains showed no tendency to self-association into triple helices, the heterotrimer (alpha 1 alpha 2 alpha 1&apos;) was found to exhibit a typical collagen-like CD spectrum at room temperature and a melting temperature (T-m) of 33 degrees C, This triple-helical collagen-like peptide is cleaved by the full-length human neutrophil collagenase (MMP-8) at a single locus fully confirming the correct raster of the heterotrimer, Its digestion proceeds at rates markedly higher than that of a single alpha 1&apos; chain, Tn contrast, opposite digestion rates were measured with the catalytic Phe(79)-MMP-8 domain of HNC. Moreover, the full-length enzyme exhibits K-m values of 5 mu M and 1 mM for the heterotrimer and the single alpha 1&apos; chain, respectively, which compare well with those reported for collagen type I (similar to 1 mu M), gelatine (similar to 10 mu M) and for octapeptides of the cleavage sequence (greater than or equal to 1 mM), The high affinity of the MMP-8 for the triple-helical heterotrimer and the fast digestion of this collagenous peptide confirm the decisive role of the hemopexin domain in recognition and possibly, partial unfolding of collagen.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1996</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>triple helix</topic><topic>enzymatic</topic><topic>digestion</topic><topic>collagenase</topic><topic>catalytic domain</topic><topic>hemopexin domain</topic><topic>heterotrimer</topic><topic>collagen peptide</topic><topic>synthesis</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>FEBS LETTERS</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0014-5793</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">8946948</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1996VV87800006</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/S0014-5793(96)01212-4</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>398</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">31-36</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Ottl, J., Battistuta, R., Pieper, M., Tschesche, H., Bode, W., Kuhn, K., &amp;amp; Moroder, L. (1996). Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases. &lt;em&gt;FEBS LETTERS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;398&lt;/em&gt;(1), 31-36.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>J. Ottl, et al., “Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases”, &lt;em&gt;FEBS LETTERS&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 398, 1996,  pp. 31-36.</ieee>
<mla>Ottl, J, Battistuta, R, Pieper, M, Tschesche, Harald, Bode, W, Kuhn, K, and Moroder, L. “Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases”. &lt;em&gt;FEBS LETTERS&lt;/em&gt; 398.1 (1996): 31-36.</mla>
<lncs>Ottl, J., Battistuta, R., Pieper, M., Tschesche, H., Bode, W., Kuhn, K., Moroder, L.: Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases. FEBS LETTERS. 398, 31-36 (1996).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Ottl, J, Battistuta, R, Pieper, M, Tschesche, Harald, Bode, W, Kuhn, K, and Moroder, L. 1996. “Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases”. &lt;em&gt;FEBS LETTERS&lt;/em&gt; 398 (1): 31-36.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Ottl, R.  Battistuta, M.  Pieper, H.  Tschesche, W.  Bode, K.  Kuhn, and L.  Moroder, “Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases”, &lt;em&gt;FEBS LETTERS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1996&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;398&lt;/em&gt;, 31-36.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Ottl, J., Battistuta, R., Pieper, M., Tschesche, H., Bode, W., Kuhn, K., &amp;amp; Moroder, L. (1996). Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases. &lt;em&gt;FEBS LETTERS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;398&lt;/em&gt;(1), 31-36.</apa>
<frontiers>Ottl, J., Battistuta, R., Pieper, M., Tschesche, H., Bode, W., Kuhn, K., and Moroder, L. (1996). Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases. &lt;em&gt;FEBS LETTERS&lt;/em&gt; 398, 31-36.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Ottl, J., Battistuta, R., Pieper, M., Tschesche, H., Bode, W., Kuhn, K. &amp;amp; Moroder, L. (1996). Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases. &lt;em&gt;FEBS LETTERS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;398&lt;/em&gt;(1), 31-36. ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV. doi:10.1016/S0014-5793(96)01212-4.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Ottl J, Battistuta R, Pieper M, et al. Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases. &lt;em&gt;FEBS LETTERS&lt;/em&gt;. 1996;398(1):31-36.</ama>
<harvard1>Ottl, J., et al., 1996. Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases. &lt;em&gt;FEBS LETTERS&lt;/em&gt;, 398(1), p 31-36.</harvard1>
<aps>J.  Ottl, et al., Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases, FEBS LETTERS &lt;strong&gt;398&lt;/strong&gt;, 31-36 (1996).</aps>
<bio1>Ottl J, Battistuta R, Pieper M, Tschesche H, Bode W, Kuhn K, Moroder L (1996) &lt;br /&gt;Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases.&lt;br /&gt;FEBS LETTERS 398(1): 31-36.</bio1>
<wels>Ottl, J.; Battistuta, R.; Pieper, M.; Tschesche, H.; Bode, W.; Kuhn, K.; Moroder, L. (1996): Design and synthesis of heterotrimeric collagen peptides with a built-in cystine-knot - Models for collagen catabolism by matrix-metalloproteases &lt;em&gt;FEBS LETTERS&lt;/em&gt;,398:(1): 31-36.</wels>
<default>Ottl J, Battistuta R, Pieper M, Tschesche H, Bode W, Kuhn K, Moroder L (1996) &lt;br /&gt;FEBS LETTERS 398(1): 31-36.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1628600</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:23:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-08T11:02:51Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1628600</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1628600</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
