<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ursula</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Müller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">13182</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Walter R.</namePart><namePart type="family">Heinz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">David N.</namePart><namePart type="family">Ashton</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10068</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>Deutscher Studienverlag</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1991</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-89271-298-0</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">159-168</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>U.  Müller, in &lt;em&gt;The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: W.R. Heinz, D.N. Ashton), Deutscher Studienverlag, Weinheim, &lt;strong&gt;1991&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 159-168.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Müller, U. (1991). The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems? In W. R.  Heinz &amp;amp; D. N.  Ashton (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Status passages and the life course: Vol. 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 159-168). Weinheim: Deutscher Studienverlag.</apa>
<frontiers>Müller, U. (1991). “The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems?” in &lt;em&gt;The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, Heinz, W. R., and Ashton, D. N. eds. Status passages and the life course, vol. 2, (Weinheim: Deutscher Studienverlag), 159-168.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Müller, Ursula. 1991. “The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems?”. In &lt;em&gt;The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Walter R. Heinz and David N. Ashton, 2:159-168. Status passages and the life course. Weinheim: Deutscher Studienverlag.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee> U. Müller, “The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems?”, &lt;em&gt;The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, W.R. Heinz and D.N. Ashton, eds., Status passages and the life course, vol. 2,  Weinheim: Deutscher Studienverlag, 1991,  pp.159-168.</ieee>
<lncs> Müller, U.: The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems? In: Heinz, W.R. and Ashton, D.N. (eds.) The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives. Status passages and the life course. 2, p. 159-168. Deutscher Studienverlag, Weinheim (1991).</lncs>
<mla>Müller, Ursula. “The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems?”. &lt;em&gt;The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Walter R. Heinz and David N. Ashton. Weinheim: Deutscher Studienverlag, 1991.Vol. 2. Status passages and the life course. 159-168.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Müller, U. (1991). The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems? In W. R.  Heinz &amp;amp; D. N.  Ashton (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Status passages and the life course: Vol. 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 159-168). Weinheim: Deutscher Studienverlag.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Müller, U. (1991): The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems? In: Walter R. Heinz; David N. Ashton (Hrsg.):  The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives. Weinheim: Deutscher Studienverlag. (Status passages and the life course, 2).  S. 159-168.</wels>
<default>Müller U (1991)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives. Heinz WR, Ashton DN (Eds); Status passages and the life course, 2. Weinheim: Deutscher Studienverlag:  159-168.</default>
<ama>Müller U. The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems? In: Heinz WR, Ashton DN, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Status passages and the life course. Vol 2. Weinheim: Deutscher Studienverlag;  1991: 159-168.</ama>
<harvard1>Müller, U., 1991. The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems? In W. R.  Heinz &amp;amp; D. N.  Ashton, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Status passages and the life course. no.2  Weinheim: Deutscher Studienverlag, pp. 159-168.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Müller, U. (1991). The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems? (Status passages and the life course). &lt;em&gt;The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (S. 159-168). Weinheim: Deutscher Studienverlag.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<aps> U.  Müller, The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems?, in &lt;em&gt;The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, edited by W. R.  Heinz and D. N.  Ashton, Status passages and the life course, &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; (Deutscher Studienverlag, Weinheim, 1991), p. 159-168.</aps>
<bio1>Müller U (1991) &lt;br /&gt;The Family: Space for Self - Development or Privatization of Social Problems? &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Life Course and Social Change: Comparative Perspectives. Heinz WR, Ashton DN (Eds); Status passages and the life course, 2. Weinheim: Deutscher Studienverlag:  159-168.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1859366</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-08-10T09:32:58Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-08-10T09:32:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1859366</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1859366</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
