<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Caspers</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">5514336</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-4380-0476</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank C.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schroeder</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stephan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Franke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">W. Juergen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Streich</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian C.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Voigt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Verhaltensforschung</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Combining chemical analysis and odour preference tests, we asked whether two closely related sympatric species of sac-winged bats use odour for species recognition. Males of the two sister species Saccopteryx bilineata and Saccopteryx leptura have pouches containing an odoriferous liquid in their antebrachial wing membrane, which is used in S. bilineata during courtship displays. Although both species occasionally share the same daytime roosts and are morphologically similar, there is no evidence for interbreeding. We compared the production and composition of the wing sac odorant in male S. leptura and S. bilineata and performed odour preference tests with female S. bilineata. Similar to male S. bilineata, male S. leptura cleansed and refilled their wing sacs with secretions, but they spent more time each day in doing so than male S. bilineata. Chemical analysis by gas chromatography and mass spectrometry revealed that male Saccopteryx carried species-specific scents in their wing sacs. Binary choice tests confirmed that female S. bilineata preferred the wing sac scents of male S. bilineata to those of the sister species, suggesting that the species specificity of male wing sac scents maintain the pre-mating isolation barrier between these closely related species.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>Springer Science + Business Media</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Species-specific scents</topic><topic>Species recognition</topic><topic>Saccopteryx leptura</topic><topic>Female choice</topic><topic>Bats</topic><topic>Saccopteryx bilineata</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0340-5443</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1432-0762</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000263670900011</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/s00265-009-0708-7</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>63</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>5</number></detail><extent unit="pages">741-749</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Caspers, B.; Schroeder, F. C.; Franke, S.; Streich, W. J.; Voigt, C. C. (2009): Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests &lt;em&gt;BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,63:(5): 741-749.</wels>
<default>Caspers B, Schroeder FC, Franke S, Streich WJ, Voigt CC (2009) &lt;br /&gt;BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY 63(5): 741-749.</default>
<harvard1>Caspers, B., et al., 2009. Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests. &lt;em&gt;BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 63(5), p 741-749.</harvard1>
<ama>Caspers B, Schroeder FC, Franke S, Streich WJ, Voigt CC. Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests. &lt;em&gt;BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. 2009;63(5):741-749.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Caspers, B., Schroeder, F.C., Franke, S., Streich, W.J. &amp;amp; Voigt, C.C. (2009). Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests. &lt;em&gt;BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;63&lt;/em&gt;(5), 741-749. Springer Science + Business Media. doi:10.1007/s00265-009-0708-7.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<aps>B.  Caspers, et al., Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests, BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY &lt;strong&gt;63&lt;/strong&gt;, 741-749 (2009).</aps>
<bio1>Caspers B, Schroeder FC, Franke S, Streich WJ, Voigt CC (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests.&lt;br /&gt;BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY 63(5): 741-749.</bio1>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Caspers, Barbara, Schroeder, Frank C., Franke, Stephan, Streich, W. Juergen, and Voigt, Christian C. 2009. “Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests”. &lt;em&gt;BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 63 (5): 741-749.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Caspers, B., Schroeder, F. C., Franke, S., Streich, W. J., &amp;amp; Voigt, C. C. (2009). Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests. &lt;em&gt;BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;63&lt;/em&gt;(5), 741-749.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Caspers, F. C.  Schroeder, S.  Franke, W. J.  Streich, and C. C.  Voigt, “Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests”, &lt;em&gt;BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;63&lt;/em&gt;, 741-749.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Caspers, B., Schroeder, F. C., Franke, S., Streich, W. J., and Voigt, C. C. (2009). Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests. &lt;em&gt;BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 63, 741-749.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Caspers, B., Schroeder, F. C., Franke, S., Streich, W. J., &amp;amp; Voigt, C. C. (2009). Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests. &lt;em&gt;BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;63&lt;/em&gt;(5), 741-749.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>B. Caspers, et al., “Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests”, &lt;em&gt;BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 63, 2009,  pp. 741-749.</ieee>
<lncs>Caspers, B., Schroeder, F.C., Franke, S., Streich, W.J., Voigt, C.C.: Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests. BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY. 63, 741-749 (2009).</lncs>
<mla>Caspers, Barbara, Schroeder, Frank C., Franke, Stephan, Streich, W. Juergen, and Voigt, Christian C. “Odour-based species recognition in two sympatric species of sac-winged bats (Saccopteryx bilineata, S-leptura): combining chemical analyses, behavioural observations and odour preference tests”. &lt;em&gt;BEHAVIORAL ECOLOGY AND SOCIOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 63.5 (2009): 741-749.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1635483</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:07:39Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-01-12T09:08:34Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1635483</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1635483</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
