<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference abstract</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory.</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wolfgang</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schoeller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">20336</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17982</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2004</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0065-7727</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000223655603190</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>227</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Schoeller, W. (2004): Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory. In: ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY. AMER CHEMICAL SOC. (227).</wels>
<default>Schoeller W (2004)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY. 227. AMER CHEMICAL SOC.</default>
<ama>Schoeller W. Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory. In:  &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 227. AMER CHEMICAL SOC;  2004.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Schoeller, W. (2004). Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory. &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;. AMER CHEMICAL SOC.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Schoeller, W., 2004. Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory. In &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;. no.227  AMER CHEMICAL SOC.</harvard1>
<aps> W.  Schoeller, Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory., in &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;227&lt;/strong&gt; (AMER CHEMICAL SOC, 2004).</aps>
<bio1>Schoeller W (2004) &lt;br /&gt;Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory. &lt;br /&gt;In:  ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY. 227. AMER CHEMICAL SOC.</bio1>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Schoeller, Wolfgang. 2004. “Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory.”. In &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 227. AMER CHEMICAL SOC: 021-COMP.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<angewandte-chemie>W.  Schoeller, in &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;, Amer Chemical Soc, &lt;strong&gt;2004&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Schoeller, W. (2004). Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory. &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;227&lt;/em&gt;.</apa>
<frontiers>Schoeller, W. (2004). “Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory.” in &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 227, (AMER CHEMICAL SOC).</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Schoeller, W. (2004). Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory. &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;227&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee> W. Schoeller, “Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory.”, &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 227, AMER CHEMICAL SOC, 2004.</ieee>
<lncs> Schoeller, W.: Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory. ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY. 227,  AMER CHEMICAL SOC (2004).</lncs>
<mla>Schoeller, Wolfgang. “Biradicals of four-membered heterocycles contaning boron, silicon and phosphorus: A challenge to theory.”. &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;. AMER CHEMICAL SOC, 2004.Vol. 227.</mla>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1605251</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:40:40Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-10-19T07:51:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1605251</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1605251</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
