<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Mohammed A.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kader</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sylvia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lindberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thorsten</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Seidel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">4773911</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dortje</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Golldack</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22121</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Vladislav</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Yemelyanov</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2685177</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Perception of salt stress in plant cells induces a change in the free cytosolic Ca2+, [Ca2+](cyt), which transfers downstream reactions toward salt tolerance. Changes in cytosolic H+ concentration, [H+](cyt), are closely linked to the [Ca2+](cyt) dynamics under various stress signals. In this study, salt-induced changes in [Ca2+](cyt), and [H+](cyt) and vacuolar [H+] concentrations were monitored in single protoplasts of rice (Oryza sativa L. indica cvs. Pokkali and BRRI Dhan29) by fluorescence microscopy. Changes in cytosolic [Ca2+] and [H+] were detected by use of the fluorescent dyes acetoxy methyl ester of calcium-binding benzofuran and acetoxy methyl ester of 2&apos;, 7&apos;-bis-(2-carboxyethyl)-5-(and-6) carboxyfluorescein, respectively, and for vacuolar pH, fluorescent 6-carboxyfluorescein and confocal microscopy were used. Addition of NaCl induced a higher increase in [Ca2+](cyt) in the salt-tolerant cv. Pokkali than in the salt-sensitive cv. BRRI Dhan29. From inhibitor studies, we conclude that the internal stores appear to be the major source for [Ca2+](cyt) increase in Pokkali, although the apoplast is more important in BRRI Dhan29. The [Ca2+](cyt) measurements in rice also suggest that Na+ should be sensed inside the cytosol, before any increase in [Ca2+](cyt) occurs. Moreover, our results with individual mesophyll protoplasts suggest that ionic stress causes an increase in [Ca2+](cyt) and that osmotic stress sharply decreases [Ca2+](cyt) in rice. The [pH](cyt) was differently shifted in the two rice cultivars in response to salt stress and may be coupled to different activities of the H+-ATPases. The changes in vacuolar pH were correlated with the expressional analysis of rice vacuolar H+-ATPase in these two rice cultivars.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>BLACKWELL PUBLISHING</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0031-9317</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1399-3054</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000245645000010</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1111/j.1399-3054.2007.00890.x</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>130</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">99-111</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Kader, M. A.; Lindberg, S.; Seidel, T.; Golldack, D.; Yemelyanov, V. (2007): Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars &lt;em&gt;PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM&lt;/em&gt;,130:(1): 99-111.</wels>
<default>Kader MA, Lindberg S, Seidel T, Golldack D, Yemelyanov V (2007) &lt;br /&gt;PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM 130(1): 99-111.</default>
<ama>Kader MA, Lindberg S, Seidel T, Golldack D, Yemelyanov V. Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars. &lt;em&gt;PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM&lt;/em&gt;. 2007;130(1):99-111.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kader, M.A., Lindberg, S., Seidel, T., Golldack, D. &amp;amp; Yemelyanov, V. (2007). Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars. &lt;em&gt;PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;130&lt;/em&gt;(1), 99-111. BLACKWELL PUBLISHING. doi:10.1111/j.1399-3054.2007.00890.x.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Kader, M.A., et al., 2007. Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars. &lt;em&gt;PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM&lt;/em&gt;, 130(1), p 99-111.</harvard1>
<bio1>Kader MA, Lindberg S, Seidel T, Golldack D, Yemelyanov V (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars.&lt;br /&gt;PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM 130(1): 99-111.</bio1>
<aps>M. A.  Kader, et al., Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars, PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM &lt;strong&gt;130&lt;/strong&gt;, 99-111 (2007).</aps>
<apa>Kader, M. A., Lindberg, S., Seidel, T., Golldack, D., &amp;amp; Yemelyanov, V. (2007). Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars. &lt;em&gt;PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;130&lt;/em&gt;(1), 99-111.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>M. A.  Kader, S.  Lindberg, T.  Seidel, D.  Golldack, and V.  Yemelyanov, “Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars”, &lt;em&gt;PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;130&lt;/em&gt;, 99-111.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Kader, M. A., Lindberg, S., Seidel, T., Golldack, D., and Yemelyanov, V. (2007). Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars. &lt;em&gt;PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM&lt;/em&gt; 130, 99-111.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kader, Mohammed A., Lindberg, Sylvia, Seidel, Thorsten, Golldack, Dortje, and Yemelyanov, Vladislav. 2007. “Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars”. &lt;em&gt;PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM&lt;/em&gt; 130 (1): 99-111.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee>M.A. Kader, et al., “Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars”, &lt;em&gt;PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 130, 2007,  pp. 99-111.</ieee>
<lncs>Kader, M.A., Lindberg, S., Seidel, T., Golldack, D., Yemelyanov, V.: Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars. PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM. 130, 99-111 (2007).</lncs>
<mla>Kader, Mohammed A., Lindberg, Sylvia, Seidel, Thorsten, Golldack, Dortje, and Yemelyanov, Vladislav. “Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars”. &lt;em&gt;PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM&lt;/em&gt; 130.1 (2007): 99-111.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kader, M. A., Lindberg, S., Seidel, T., Golldack, D., &amp;amp; Yemelyanov, V. (2007). Sodium sensing induces different changes in free cytosolic calcium concentration and pH in salt-tolerant and -sensitive rice (Oryza sativa) cultivars. &lt;em&gt;PHYSIOLOGIA PLANTARUM&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;130&lt;/em&gt;(1), 99-111.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1594514</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:16:21Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-02-19T14:25:55Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1594514</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1594514</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
