<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">V</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kovacik</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hirsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">S</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zoric</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Friedrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Grützmacher</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">41603</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Chemie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10018</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Intense cluster ions corresponding to proton-bound hetero-dimers of an amide molecule and an oligosaccharide molecule are observed in the liquid secondary ion mass spectra of methyl glycosides of oligoxylans if a solution of an aliphatic carboxamide in glycerol is used as the liquid matrix. These cluster ions are particularly abundant and persist for a long period if urea (U) or thiourea (TU) is used as the matrix additive. In these cases, cluster ions containing more than one molecule of U or TU and two oligosaccharide molecules are also observed. The intense signal due to the proton-bound hetero-dimer between U or TU and the oligosaccharide can be used with advantage for a molecular weight determination. The bonding interactions between a protonated saccharide molecule and a molecule U or TU in the proton-bound hetero-dimers are so strong that the urea molecules remain attached to the fragment ions during the decay of metastable cluster ions and even during collision-induced dissociation. Thus, the mass-analysed ion kinetic energy spectra of these proton-bound hetero-dimers are dominated by abundant cluster ions [B-n + U] and [Y-m+ U] arising from cleavage of the glycosidic bonds within the oligosaccharides. The collisionally-activated mass spectra of the proton-bound hetero-dimers additionally contain peaks of the free ions B-n and Y-m. Therefore, these spectra clearly reflect the arrangement of the monosaccharide residues in the oligosaccharide and can be used conveniently for structural analysis.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1996</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0951-4198</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1097-0231</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">8914338</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1996VN92200016</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1097-0231(199610)10:13&lt;1661::AID-RCM680&gt;3.0.CO;2-6</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>13</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1661-1667</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kovacik, V., Hirsch, J., Zoric, S. &amp;amp; Grützmacher, H.-F. (1996). Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(13), 1661-1667. JOHN WILEY &amp;amp; SONS LTD. doi:10.1002/(SICI)1097-0231(199610)10:13&amp;lt;1661::AID-RCM680&amp;gt;3.0.CO;2-6.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Kovacik, V., et al., 1996. Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;, 10(13), p 1661-1667.</harvard1>
<ama>Kovacik V, Hirsch J, Zoric S, Grützmacher H-F. Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;. 1996;10(13):1661-1667.</ama>
<bio1>Kovacik V, Hirsch J, Zoric S, Grützmacher H-F (1996) &lt;br /&gt;Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides.&lt;br /&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY 10(13): 1661-1667.</bio1>
<aps>V.  Kovacik, et al., Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides, RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;, 1661-1667 (1996).</aps>
<wels>Kovacik, V.; Hirsch, J.; Zoric, S.; Grützmacher, H. - F. (1996): Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;,10:(13): 1661-1667.</wels>
<default>Kovacik V, Hirsch J, Zoric S, Grützmacher H-F (1996) &lt;br /&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY 10(13): 1661-1667.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kovacik, V., Hirsch, J., Zoric, S., &amp;amp; Grützmacher, H. - F. (1996). Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(13), 1661-1667.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>V. Kovacik, et al., “Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides”, &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 1996,  pp. 1661-1667.</ieee>
<mla>Kovacik, V, Hirsch, J, Zoric, S, and Grützmacher, Hans-Friedrich. “Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides”. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt; 10.13 (1996): 1661-1667.</mla>
<lncs>Kovacik, V., Hirsch, J., Zoric, S., Grützmacher, H.-F.: Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides. RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY. 10, 1661-1667 (1996).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kovacik, V, Hirsch, J, Zoric, S, and Grützmacher, Hans-Friedrich. 1996. “Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides”. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt; 10 (13): 1661-1667.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Kovacik, V., Hirsch, J., Zoric, S., &amp;amp; Grützmacher, H. - F. (1996). Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(13), 1661-1667.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>V.  Kovacik, J.  Hirsch, S.  Zoric, and H. - F.  Grützmacher, “Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides”, &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1996&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, 1661-1667.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Kovacik, V., Hirsch, J., Zoric, S., and Grützmacher, H. - F. (1996). Liquid secondary ion mass spectrometry of methyl glycosides of oligosaccharides using matrices containing carboxamides. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt; 10, 1661-1667.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1638269</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:14:41Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-08-23T19:05:45Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1638269</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1638269</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
