<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexandros A.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Karamanlidis</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Vangelis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Paravas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Fritz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Trillmich</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21949</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Panagiotis</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dendrinos</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Verhaltensforschung</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Understanding reproductive behavior, especially the circumstances surrounding parturition and the events following the first days postpartum, is essential in developing effective conservation strategies for endangered pinnipeds. In the case of the critically endangered Mediterranean monk seal (Monachus monachus), difficulties in documenting events such as parturition are compounded by the very low population numbers and the inaccessibility of the habitat occupied by the species. In this study, the authors report the first observations of parturition for the species from the central Aegean Sea, Greece, in the eastern Mediterranean Sea. Using a state-of-the-art infrared remote-monitoring system, two births were documented, and important information on the total duration of the events; the total duration of attempted suckling; as well as information on the presentation of the pups, their sex, and habitat were recorded. This new information on the reproductive biology of the species in this part of its range outline the importance of suitable reproductive caves for the conservation of the species and the urgency of protecting them. In addition, considering the high cost and logistics of the study, monitoring the species on a large scale to effectively protect it will require the development of new, low-cost, and time-efficient methodologies.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>Aquatic Mammals Journal</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Mediterranean monk seal</topic><topic>conservation</topic><topic>endangered</topic><topic>species</topic><topic>Greece</topic><topic>parturition</topic><topic>non-invasive monitoring</topic><topic>Monachus monachus</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>AQUATIC MAMMALS</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0167-5427</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000283447900004</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1578/AM.36.1.2010.27</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>36</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">27-32</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Karamanlidis, A. A., Paravas, V., Trillmich, F., and Dendrinos, P. (2010). First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean. &lt;em&gt;AQUATIC MAMMALS&lt;/em&gt; 36, 27-32.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>A. A.  Karamanlidis, V.  Paravas, F.  Trillmich, and P.  Dendrinos, “First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean”, &lt;em&gt;AQUATIC MAMMALS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;36&lt;/em&gt;, 27-32.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Karamanlidis, A. A., Paravas, V., Trillmich, F., &amp;amp; Dendrinos, P. (2010). First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean. &lt;em&gt;AQUATIC MAMMALS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;36&lt;/em&gt;(1), 27-32.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Karamanlidis, Alexandros A., Paravas, Vangelis, Trillmich, Fritz, and Dendrinos, Panagiotis. 2010. “First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean”. &lt;em&gt;AQUATIC MAMMALS&lt;/em&gt; 36 (1): 27-32.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs>Karamanlidis, A.A., Paravas, V., Trillmich, F., Dendrinos, P.: First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean. AQUATIC MAMMALS. 36, 27-32 (2010).</lncs>
<mla>Karamanlidis, Alexandros A., Paravas, Vangelis, Trillmich, Fritz, and Dendrinos, Panagiotis. “First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean”. &lt;em&gt;AQUATIC MAMMALS&lt;/em&gt; 36.1 (2010): 27-32.</mla>
<ieee>A.A. Karamanlidis, et al., “First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean”, &lt;em&gt;AQUATIC MAMMALS&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 36, 2010,  pp. 27-32.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Karamanlidis, A. A., Paravas, V., Trillmich, F., &amp;amp; Dendrinos, P. (2010). First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean. &lt;em&gt;AQUATIC MAMMALS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;36&lt;/em&gt;(1), 27-32.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Karamanlidis AA, Paravas V, Trillmich F, Dendrinos P (2010) &lt;br /&gt;AQUATIC MAMMALS 36(1): 27-32.</default>
<wels>Karamanlidis, A. A.; Paravas, V.; Trillmich, F.; Dendrinos, P. (2010): First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean &lt;em&gt;AQUATIC MAMMALS&lt;/em&gt;,36:(1): 27-32.</wels>
<bio1>Karamanlidis AA, Paravas V, Trillmich F, Dendrinos P (2010) &lt;br /&gt;First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean.&lt;br /&gt;AQUATIC MAMMALS 36(1): 27-32.</bio1>
<aps>A. A.  Karamanlidis, et al., First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean, AQUATIC MAMMALS &lt;strong&gt;36&lt;/strong&gt;, 27-32 (2010).</aps>
<ama>Karamanlidis AA, Paravas V, Trillmich F, Dendrinos P. First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean. &lt;em&gt;AQUATIC MAMMALS&lt;/em&gt;. 2010;36(1):27-32.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Karamanlidis, A.A., Paravas, V., Trillmich, F. &amp;amp; Dendrinos, P. (2010). First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean. &lt;em&gt;AQUATIC MAMMALS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;36&lt;/em&gt;(1), 27-32. Aquatic Mammals Journal. doi:10.1578/AM.36.1.2010.27.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Karamanlidis, A.A., et al., 2010. First Observations of Parturition and Postpartum Behavior in the Mediterranean Monk Seal (Monachus monachus) in the Eastern Mediterranean. &lt;em&gt;AQUATIC MAMMALS&lt;/em&gt;, 36(1), p 27-32.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1929347</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-12-07T10:47:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-11-22T10:53:04Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1929347</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1929347</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
