<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Muschiol</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Walter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Traunspurger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21944</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2685511</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The life cycle and somatic growth of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp. and Poikilolaimus sp., isolated from chemoautotrophic microbial mats in Movile Cave, Romania, were studied in monoxenic cultures at 20 degrees C with Escherichia coli as the food source. A method is described that allows simultaneous investigation of the somatic growth pattern, age-specific fecundity, and age-specific mortality of single individuals with high accuracy. Somatic growth curves of the species are presented. During juvenile development, both species showed a strict linear increase in body length, whereas body weight increased exponentially. Growth was continuous without lag phases. The relationships between fresh weight, W (mu g), and body length, L (mm), were W = 1.6439L(2.7672) for Poikilolaimus sp. and W = 0.2085L(4.0915) for Panagrolaimus sp. Life tables and fecundity schedules for the two species are presented. In addition, demographic parameters were calculated. For Panagrolaimus, the intrinsic rate of natural increase (rn,), calculated according to the Lotka equation, was 0.309, the net reproductive rate (RO) 64, the mean generation time (T) 13.8 days and the minimum generation time (T-min) 9.5 days. The corresponding values for Poikilolaimus were r(m) = 0. 165, R-0 = 108, T = 26.2 and T-min = 19.5. Panagrolaimus produced fewer progeny than Poikilolaimus during its life but exhibited faster population growth due to its faster maturation. It showed a distinct post-reproductive period, whereas Poikilolaimus remained fertile until death.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>BRILL ACADEMIC PUBLISHERS</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>age-specific fecundity</topic><topic>culture medium</topic><topic>generation time</topic><topic>life</topic><topic>tables</topic><topic>microbial mat</topic><topic>population growth</topic><topic>somatic growth</topic><topic>biofilm</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>NEMATOLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1388-5545</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1568-5411</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000248540200012</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1163/156854107780739117</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>9</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">271-284</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Muschiol, D. &amp;amp; Traunspurger, W. (2007). Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania. &lt;em&gt;NEMATOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(2), 271-284. BRILL ACADEMIC PUBLISHERS. doi:10.1163/156854107780739117.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Muschiol D, Traunspurger W. Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania. &lt;em&gt;NEMATOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. 2007;9(2):271-284.</ama>
<harvard1>Muschiol, D., &amp;amp; Traunspurger, W., 2007. Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania. &lt;em&gt;NEMATOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 9(2), p 271-284.</harvard1>
<bio1>Muschiol D, Traunspurger W (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania.&lt;br /&gt;NEMATOLOGY 9(2): 271-284.</bio1>
<aps> D.  Muschiol and W.  Traunspurger, Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania, NEMATOLOGY &lt;strong&gt;9&lt;/strong&gt;, 271-284 (2007).</aps>
<wels>Muschiol, D.; Traunspurger, W. (2007): Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania &lt;em&gt;NEMATOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,9:(2): 271-284.</wels>
<default>Muschiol D, Traunspurger W (2007) &lt;br /&gt;NEMATOLOGY 9(2): 271-284.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Muschiol, D., &amp;amp; Traunspurger, W. (2007). Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania. &lt;em&gt;NEMATOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(2), 271-284.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee> D. Muschiol and W. Traunspurger, “Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania”, &lt;em&gt;NEMATOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 9, 2007,  pp. 271-284.</ieee>
<mla>Muschiol, Daniel, and Traunspurger, Walter. “Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania”. &lt;em&gt;NEMATOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 9.2 (2007): 271-284.</mla>
<lncs> Muschiol, D., Traunspurger, W.: Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania. NEMATOLOGY. 9, 271-284 (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Muschiol, Daniel, and Traunspurger, Walter. 2007. “Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania”. &lt;em&gt;NEMATOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 9 (2): 271-284.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Muschiol, D., &amp;amp; Traunspurger, W. (2007). Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania. &lt;em&gt;NEMATOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;(2), 271-284.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Muschiol, and W.  Traunspurger, “Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania”, &lt;em&gt;NEMATOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt;, 271-284.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Muschiol, D., and Traunspurger, W. (2007). Life cycle and calculation of the intrinsic rate of natural increase of two bacterivorous nematodes, Panagrolaimus sp and Poikilolaimus sp from chemoautotrophic Movile Cave, Romania. &lt;em&gt;NEMATOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 9, 271-284.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1632467</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:06:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-10-21T07:24:47Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1632467</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1632467</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
