<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nils</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hansen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Terrill A.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cool</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Phillip R.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Westmoreland</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katharina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kohse-Höinghaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">20770</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17978</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry of premixed, laminar, low-pressure flat flames has been demonstrated to be an efficient tool to study combustion chemistry. In this technique, flame gases are sampled through a small opening in a quartz probe, and after formation of a molecular beam, all flame species are separated using mass spectrometry. The present review focuses on critical aspects of the experimental approach including probe sampling effects, different ionization processes, and mass separation procedures. The capability for isomer-resolved flame species measurements, achievable by employing tunable vacuum-ultraviolet radiation for single-photon ionization, has greatly benefited flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry. This review also offers an overview of recent combustion chemistry studies of flames fueled by hydrocarbons and oxygenates. The identity of a variety of intermediates in hydrocarbon flames, including resonantly stabilized radicals and closed-shell intermediates, is described, thus establishing a more detailed understanding of the fundamentals of molecular-weight growth processes. Finally, molecular-beam mass-spectrometric studies of reaction paths in flames of alcohols, ethers, and esters, which have been performed to support the development and validation of kinetic models for bio-derived alternative fuels, are reviewed. (C) 2008 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Oxygenated fuel</topic><topic>Low-pressure flame</topic><topic>Combustion chemistry</topic><topic>Mass spectrometry</topic><topic>ring formation</topic><topic>Aromatic</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0360-1285</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000264129400003</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/j.pecs.2008.10.001</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>35</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">168-191</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Hansen, Nils, Cool, Terrill A., Westmoreland, Phillip R., and Kohse-Höinghaus, Katharina. 2009. “Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry”. &lt;em&gt;PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt; 35 (2): 168-191.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Hansen, N., Cool, T. A., Westmoreland, P. R., and Kohse-Höinghaus, K. (2009). Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry. &lt;em&gt;PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt; 35, 168-191.</frontiers>
<apa>Hansen, N., Cool, T. A., Westmoreland, P. R., &amp;amp; Kohse-Höinghaus, K. (2009). Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry. &lt;em&gt;PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;35&lt;/em&gt;(2), 168-191.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Hansen, T. A.  Cool, P. R.  Westmoreland, and K.  Kohse-Höinghaus, “Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry”, &lt;em&gt;PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;35&lt;/em&gt;, 168-191.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Hansen, N., Cool, T. A., Westmoreland, P. R., &amp;amp; Kohse-Höinghaus, K. (2009). Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry. &lt;em&gt;PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;35&lt;/em&gt;(2), 168-191.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Hansen, Nils, Cool, Terrill A., Westmoreland, Phillip R., and Kohse-Höinghaus, Katharina. “Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry”. &lt;em&gt;PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt; 35.2 (2009): 168-191.</mla>
<lncs>Hansen, N., Cool, T.A., Westmoreland, P.R., Kohse-Höinghaus, K.: Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry. PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE. 35, 168-191 (2009).</lncs>
<ieee>N. Hansen, et al., “Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry”, &lt;em&gt;PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 35, 2009,  pp. 168-191.</ieee>
<default>Hansen N, Cool TA, Westmoreland PR, Kohse-Höinghaus K (2009) &lt;br /&gt;PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE 35(2): 168-191.</default>
<wels>Hansen, N.; Cool, T. A.; Westmoreland, P. R.; Kohse-Höinghaus, K. (2009): Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry &lt;em&gt;PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;,35:(2): 168-191.</wels>
<bio1>Hansen N, Cool TA, Westmoreland PR, Kohse-Höinghaus K (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry.&lt;br /&gt;PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE 35(2): 168-191.</bio1>
<aps>N.  Hansen, et al., Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry, PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE &lt;strong&gt;35&lt;/strong&gt;, 168-191 (2009).</aps>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Hansen, N., Cool, T.A., Westmoreland, P.R. &amp;amp; Kohse-Höinghaus, K. (2009). Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry. &lt;em&gt;PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;35&lt;/em&gt;(2), 168-191. Elsevier BV. doi:10.1016/j.pecs.2008.10.001.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Hansen N, Cool TA, Westmoreland PR, Kohse-Höinghaus K. Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry. &lt;em&gt;PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;. 2009;35(2):168-191.</ama>
<harvard1>Hansen, N., et al., 2009. Recent contributions of flame-sampling molecular-beam mass spectrometry to a fundamental understanding of combustion chemistry. &lt;em&gt;PROGRESS IN ENERGY AND COMBUSTION SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, 35(2), p 168-191.</harvard1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1634985</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:07:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-02-12T11:35:26Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1634985</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1634985</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
