<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Trümper</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">142462</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">S.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mäueler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vobejda</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">40034</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Elke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zimmermann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">40017</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Arbeitsbereich I - Sportmedizin - Gesundheit und Training</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">28977922</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Objective: To determine if a heart rate-based protocol for bronchial provocation testing ensures sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction. Participants: 100 clinically healthy non-asthmatic sports students. Design: Subjects underwent an exercise challenge test (ECT) on a treadmill ergometer for bronchial provocation according to the guidelines of the American Thoracic Society (ATS). Heart rate (HR), forced expiratory volume in 1 second (FEV1), pH (pH) and lactate concentration were measured before and after exercise. Results: After exercise in 56% of the examined subjects lactate concentrations were,6 mmol/l. A highly significant decrease in FEV1 (mean -4.41 (SD 1.5%)) was found at concentrations of &gt;6 mmol/l, whereas at concentrations &lt;6.48 mmol/l, no participant showed an impairment of lung function (FEV1 values &lt;= 90%). In five subjects, a bronchial obstruction was found, as shown by decreases in FEV1 of 210 to 247% after exercise. The lactate concentrations in these individuals were between 6.48 and 11.7 mmol/l, indicating a predominantly anaerobic metabolic response to exercise. Conclusion: These results show that the ATS standard protocol, using a heart rate formula for assessing the exercise intensity, is not sufficient to cause predominantly anaerobic lactate metabolism and hence exercise-induced hyperventilation. Therefore, a potential bronchial obstruction could not be induced in 56% of the subjects. For a sensitive study design, exercise intensities demanding anaerobic lactate metabolism should always be ensured. A more precise protocol is required.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>BMJ</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>British Journal of Sportsmedicine</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0306-3674</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">18308878</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000266731000008</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2007.041715</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>43</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>6</number></detail><extent unit="pages">429-431</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Trümper C, Mäueler S, Vobejda C, Zimmermann E. Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction. &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Sportsmedicine&lt;/em&gt;. 2009;43(6):429-431.</ama>
<harvard1>Trümper, C., et al., 2009. Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction. &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Sportsmedicine&lt;/em&gt;, 43(6), p 429-431.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Trümper, C., Mäueler, S., Vobejda, C. &amp;amp; Zimmermann, E. (2009). Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction. &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Sportsmedicine&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;43&lt;/em&gt;(6), 429-431. BMJ. doi:10.1136/bjsm.2007.041715.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Trümper C, Mäueler S, Vobejda C, Zimmermann E (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction.&lt;br /&gt;British Journal of Sportsmedicine 43(6): 429-431.</bio1>
<aps>C.  Trümper, et al., Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction, British Journal of Sportsmedicine &lt;strong&gt;43&lt;/strong&gt;, 429-431 (2009).</aps>
<wels>Trümper, C.; Mäueler, S.; Vobejda, C.; Zimmermann, E. (2009): Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Sportsmedicine&lt;/em&gt;,43:(6): 429-431.</wels>
<default>Trümper C, Mäueler S, Vobejda C, Zimmermann E (2009) &lt;br /&gt;British Journal of Sportsmedicine 43(6): 429-431.</default>
<ieee>C. Trümper, et al., “Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction”, &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Sportsmedicine&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 43, 2009,  pp. 429-431.</ieee>
<mla>Trümper, Christian, Mäueler, S., Vobejda, Christian, and Zimmermann, Elke. “Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction”. &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Sportsmedicine&lt;/em&gt; 43.6 (2009): 429-431.</mla>
<lncs>Trümper, C., Mäueler, S., Vobejda, C., Zimmermann, E.: Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction. British Journal of Sportsmedicine. 43, 429-431 (2009).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Trümper, C., Mäueler, S., Vobejda, C., &amp;amp; Zimmermann, E. (2009). Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction. &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Sportsmedicine&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;43&lt;/em&gt;(6), 429-431.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<apa>Trümper, C., Mäueler, S., Vobejda, C., &amp;amp; Zimmermann, E. (2009). Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction. &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Sportsmedicine&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;43&lt;/em&gt;(6), 429-431.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Trümper, S.  Mäueler, C.  Vobejda, and E.  Zimmermann, “Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction”, &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Sportsmedicine&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;43&lt;/em&gt;, 429-431.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Trümper, C., Mäueler, S., Vobejda, C., and Zimmermann, E. (2009). Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction. &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Sportsmedicine&lt;/em&gt; 43, 429-431.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Trümper, Christian, Mäueler, S., Vobejda, Christian, and Zimmermann, Elke. 2009. “Heart rate-based protocols for exercise challenge testing do not ensure sufficient exercise intensity for inducing exercise-induced bronchial obstruction”. &lt;em&gt;British Journal of Sportsmedicine&lt;/em&gt; 43 (6): 429-431.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1633696</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:06:58Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-12-07T15:32:52Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1633696</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1633696</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
