<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Li</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">DE</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bauzon</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">XY</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Xu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tschesche</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">19406</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cao</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">QXA</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sang</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Biochemie I</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17967</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Membrane type (MT) 1 matrix metalloproteinase (MMP) activates progelatinase A (pro-MMP-2), a type IV collagenase, on the cell surface of tumors; however, its function in breast cancer progression and metastasis is not fully understood. To examine the expression of MT1-MMP in breast cancer cells and fibroblasts, a specific rabbit antibody (Ab) directed against a unique synthetic peptide derived from the human MT1-MMP catalytic domain was produced, purified, and characterized. This Ab is not likely to cross-react with MT2-, MT3-, or MT4-MMP or any other MMPs. MT1-MMP expression and pro-M M P-2 activation were stimulated by concanavalin A in two human breast carcinoma cell lines (BT549 and MDA-MB-231) and in normal human fetal-lung fibroblasts (HFL-1) and were slightly upregulated by breast cancer cell-fibroblast interactions. Both pro-MT1-MMP in plasma membrane (63.4 kDa) and the soluble forms of the enzyme in culture medium (57.6 and 25-30 kDa) were detected by immunoblot analysis, suggesting that cell-surface MT1-MMP exhibits an active conformation without the removal of its propeptide domain and that the mature enzyme is shed into the medium. In breast cancer cells, MT1-MMP and a recombinant catalytic domain of MT1-MMP were unable to activate pro-matrilysin, indicating that MT1-MMP is not a universal activator of all MMPs. MT1-MMP may play an important role in the invasive growth and spread of breast cancer cells by specifically activating pro-MMP-2 to cleave the connective-tissue barrier. Furthermore, use of the specific Ab may aid in the investigation of the role of MT1-MMP in human tumors. Mel. Carcinog. 22:84-94, 1998. (C) 1998 Wiley-Liss, Inc.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>WILEY-LISS</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1998</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>antibody production</topic><topic>matrilysin</topic><topic>proteinase processing</topic><topic>invasion and metastasis</topic><topic>gelatinase A</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0899-1987</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1098-2744</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">9655252</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000074465400003</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1098-2744(199806)22:2&lt;84::AID-MC3&gt;3.0.CO;2-K</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>22</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">84-94</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Li, H.; Bauzon, D. E.; Xu, X. Y.; Tschesche, H.; Cao, J.; Sang, Q. X. A. (1998): Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS&lt;/em&gt;,22:(2): 84-94.</wels>
<default>Li H, Bauzon DE, Xu XY, Tschesche H, Cao J, Sang QXA (1998) &lt;br /&gt;MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS 22(2): 84-94.</default>
<ama>Li H, Bauzon DE, Xu XY, Tschesche H, Cao J, Sang QXA. Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS&lt;/em&gt;. 1998;22(2):84-94.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Li, H., Bauzon, D.E., Xu, X.Y., Tschesche, H., Cao, J. &amp;amp; Sang, Q.X.A. (1998). Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;22&lt;/em&gt;(2), 84-94. WILEY-LISS. doi:10.1002/(SICI)1098-2744(199806)22:2&amp;lt;84::AID-MC3&amp;gt;3.0.CO;2-K.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Li, H., et al., 1998. Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS&lt;/em&gt;, 22(2), p 84-94.</harvard1>
<bio1>Li H, Bauzon DE, Xu XY, Tschesche H, Cao J, Sang QXA (1998) &lt;br /&gt;Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts.&lt;br /&gt;MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS 22(2): 84-94.</bio1>
<aps>H.  Li, et al., Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts, MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS &lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt;, 84-94 (1998).</aps>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Li, D. E.  Bauzon, X. Y.  Xu, H.  Tschesche, J.  Cao, and Q. X. A.  Sang, “Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts”, &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1998&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;22&lt;/em&gt;, 84-94.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Li, H., Bauzon, D. E., Xu, X. Y., Tschesche, H., Cao, J., &amp;amp; Sang, Q. X. A. (1998). Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;22&lt;/em&gt;(2), 84-94.</apa>
<frontiers>Li, H., Bauzon, D. E., Xu, X. Y., Tschesche, H., Cao, J., and Sang, Q. X. A. (1998). Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS&lt;/em&gt; 22, 84-94.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Li, H, Bauzon, DE, Xu, XY, Tschesche, Harald, Cao, J, and Sang, QXA. 1998. “Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts”. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS&lt;/em&gt; 22 (2): 84-94.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee>H. Li, et al., “Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts”, &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 22, 1998,  pp. 84-94.</ieee>
<mla>Li, H, Bauzon, DE, Xu, XY, Tschesche, Harald, Cao, J, and Sang, QXA. “Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts”. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS&lt;/em&gt; 22.2 (1998): 84-94.</mla>
<lncs>Li, H., Bauzon, D.E., Xu, X.Y., Tschesche, H., Cao, J., Sang, Q.X.A.: Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts. MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS. 22, 84-94 (1998).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Li, H., Bauzon, D. E., Xu, X. Y., Tschesche, H., Cao, J., &amp;amp; Sang, Q. X. A. (1998). Immunological characterization of cell-surface and soluble forms of membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase in human breast cancer cells and in fibroblasts. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR CARCINOGENESIS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;22&lt;/em&gt;(2), 84-94.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1625271</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:20:38Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-08T11:57:05Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1625271</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1625271</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
