<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tschesche</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">19406</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">BLASER</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">KLEINE</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">S</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">SCHNIERER</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">P</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">REINEMER</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">W</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">BODE</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">U</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">MAASJOSHUSMANN</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">C</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">FRICKE</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Biochemie I</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17967</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>NEW YORK ACAD SCIENCES</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1994</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0077-8923</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">7978819</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1994BD10L00048</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1111/j.1749-6632.1994.tb24766.x</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>732</number></detail><extent unit="pages">400-402</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Tschesche, H., BLASER, J., KLEINE, T., SCHNIERER, S., REINEMER, P., BODE, W., MAASJOSHUSMANN, U., and FRICKE, C. (1994). “INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR” in &lt;em&gt;INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 732, (NEW YORK ACAD SCIENCES), 400-402.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Tschesche, J.  BLASER, T.  KLEINE, S.  SCHNIERER, P.  REINEMER, W.  BODE, U.  MAASJOSHUSMANN, and C.  FRICKE, in &lt;em&gt;INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL&lt;/em&gt;, New York Acad Sciences, &lt;strong&gt;1994&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 400-402.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Tschesche, H., BLASER, J., KLEINE, T., SCHNIERER, S., REINEMER, P., BODE, W., MAASJOSHUSMANN, U., et al. (1994). INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR. &lt;em&gt;INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;732&lt;/em&gt;, 400-402.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tschesche, Harald, BLASER, J, KLEINE, T, SCHNIERER, S, REINEMER, P, BODE, W, MAASJOSHUSMANN, U, and FRICKE, C. 1994. “INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR”. In &lt;em&gt;INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL&lt;/em&gt;, 732:400-402. NEW YORK ACAD SCIENCES.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs>Tschesche, H., BLASER, J., KLEINE, T., SCHNIERER, S., REINEMER, P., BODE, W., MAASJOSHUSMANN, U., FRICKE, C.: INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR. INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL. 732, p. 400-402. NEW YORK ACAD SCIENCES (1994).</lncs>
<mla>Tschesche, Harald, BLASER, J, KLEINE, T, SCHNIERER, S, REINEMER, P, BODE, W, MAASJOSHUSMANN, U, and FRICKE, C. “INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR”. &lt;em&gt;INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL&lt;/em&gt;. NEW YORK ACAD SCIENCES, 1994.Vol. 732. 400-402.</mla>
<ieee>H. Tschesche, et al., “INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR”, &lt;em&gt;INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 732, NEW YORK ACAD SCIENCES, 1994,  pp.400-402.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tschesche, H., BLASER, J., KLEINE, T., SCHNIERER, S., REINEMER, P., BODE, W., MAASJOSHUSMANN, U., et al. (1994). INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR. &lt;em&gt;INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;732&lt;/em&gt;, 400-402.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Tschesche H, BLASER J, KLEINE T, SCHNIERER S, REINEMER P, BODE W, MAASJOSHUSMANN U, FRICKE C (1994)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL. 732. NEW YORK ACAD SCIENCES:  400-402.</default>
<wels>Tschesche, H.; BLASER, J.; KLEINE, T.; SCHNIERER, S.; REINEMER, P.; BODE, W.; MAASJOSHUSMANN, U.; FRICKE, C. (1994): INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR. In: INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL. NEW YORK ACAD SCIENCES. (732).  S. 400-402.</wels>
<bio1>Tschesche H, BLASER J, KLEINE T, SCHNIERER S, REINEMER P, BODE W, MAASJOSHUSMANN U, FRICKE C (1994) &lt;br /&gt;INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR. &lt;br /&gt;In:  INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL. 732. NEW YORK ACAD SCIENCES:  400-402.</bio1>
<aps>H.  Tschesche, et al., INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR, in &lt;em&gt;INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;732&lt;/strong&gt; (NEW YORK ACAD SCIENCES, 1994), p. 400-402.</aps>
<harvard1>Tschesche, H., et al., 1994. INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR. In &lt;em&gt;INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL&lt;/em&gt;. no.732  NEW YORK ACAD SCIENCES, pp. 400-402.</harvard1>
<ama>Tschesche H, BLASER J, KLEINE T, et al. INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR. In:  &lt;em&gt;INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 732. NEW YORK ACAD SCIENCES;  1994: 400-402.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tschesche, H., BLASER, J., KLEINE, T., SCHNIERER, S., REINEMER, P., BODE, W., MAASJOSHUSMANN, U. &amp;amp; FRICKE, C. (1994). INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES IN RHEUMATOID-ARTHRITIS AND THE CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC BINDING MODE OF A PEPTIDE INHIBITOR. &lt;em&gt;INHIBITION OF MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES: THERAPEUTIC POTENTIAL&lt;/em&gt; (S. 400-402). NEW YORK ACAD SCIENCES. doi:10.1111/j.1749-6632.1994.tb24766.x.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1640736</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:15:58Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-08T12:07:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1640736</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1640736</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
