<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tschesche</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">19406</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">C</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">KOPP</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">WH</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">HORL</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">U</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">HEMPELMANN</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Biochemie I</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17967</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">A degranulation inhibiting protein was purified to apparent homogeneity from plasma ultrafiltrates of patients with uremia using gel-permeation chromatography, ion-exchange chromatography, affinity chromatography on blue Sepharose, and ion-exchange chromatography on a Mono S HR 5/5 fast protein liquid chromatography column. The identity of the isolated degranulation inhibiting protein with angogenin was demonstrated by amino acid sequence determination, immunoblotting, and identical inhibitory activity effects on leukocyte degranulation. At concentrations in the nanomolar range, the protein inhibited spontaneous degranulation of polymorphonuclear leukocytes (PMNL) to 40%. The protein discharge of cells, which were preincubated with nanomolar concentrations of angiogenin and then stimulated with the chemotactic peptide formyl-norleucyl-leucyl-phenylalanyl-norleucyl-tyrosyl-leucine (FNLPNTL), was inhibited by 70%. Cellular functions such as chemotaxis, phagocytosis, and the oxidative respiratory burst were not obviously affected by angiogenin. A polyclonal antibody to human recombinant angiogenin abolished the inhibitory effect of the isolated protein upon PMNL. The same but reduced effect was induced by the disulfide C-39-C-92 containing tryptic angiogenin fragment L-H-G-G-S-P-W P-P-C-92-Q-Y-R G-L-T-S-P-C-39-K, indicating a new, so far unknown biologically active site of angiogenin which is different from the sites responsible for angiogenic or ribonucleolytic activity. Two synthetic peptides containing residues 83-95, one with S-92 instead of C-92, revealed the same inhibitory effect on the protein degranulation of PMNL as the entire tryptic fragment.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>AMER SOC BIOCHEMISTRY MOLECULAR BIOLOGY INC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1994</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0021-9258</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">7982938</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1994PU52500038</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>269</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>48</number></detail><extent unit="pages">30274-30280</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tschesche, H., KOPP, C., HORL, W.H. &amp;amp; HEMPELMANN, U. (1994). INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;269&lt;/em&gt;(48), 30274-30280. AMER SOC BIOCHEMISTRY MOLECULAR BIOLOGY INC.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Tschesche H, KOPP C, HORL WH, HEMPELMANN U. INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;. 1994;269(48):30274-30280.</ama>
<harvard1>Tschesche, H., et al., 1994. INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, 269(48), p 30274-30280.</harvard1>
<bio1>Tschesche H, KOPP C, HORL WH, HEMPELMANN U (1994) &lt;br /&gt;INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT.&lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY 269(48): 30274-30280.</bio1>
<aps>H.  Tschesche, et al., INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT, JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY &lt;strong&gt;269&lt;/strong&gt;, 30274-30280 (1994).</aps>
<wels>Tschesche, H.; KOPP, C.; HORL, W. H.; HEMPELMANN, U. (1994): INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;,269:(48): 30274-30280.</wels>
<default>Tschesche H, KOPP C, HORL WH, HEMPELMANN U (1994) &lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY 269(48): 30274-30280.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tschesche, H., KOPP, C., HORL, W. H., &amp;amp; HEMPELMANN, U. (1994). INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;269&lt;/em&gt;(48), 30274-30280.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>H. Tschesche, et al., “INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 269, 1994,  pp. 30274-30280.</ieee>
<lncs>Tschesche, H., KOPP, C., HORL, W.H., HEMPELMANN, U.: INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT. JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY. 269, 30274-30280 (1994).</lncs>
<mla>Tschesche, Harald, KOPP, C, HORL, WH, and HEMPELMANN, U. “INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 269.48 (1994): 30274-30280.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tschesche, Harald, KOPP, C, HORL, WH, and HEMPELMANN, U. 1994. “INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 269 (48): 30274-30280.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Tschesche, C.  KOPP, W. H.  HORL, and U.  HEMPELMANN, “INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1994&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;269&lt;/em&gt;, 30274-30280.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Tschesche, H., KOPP, C., HORL, W. H., &amp;amp; HEMPELMANN, U. (1994). INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;269&lt;/em&gt;(48), 30274-30280.</apa>
<frontiers>Tschesche, H., KOPP, C., HORL, W. H., and HEMPELMANN, U. (1994). INHIBITION OF DEGRANULATION OF POLYMORPHONUCLEAR LEUKOCYTES BY ANGIOGENIN AND ITS TRYPTIC FRAGMENT. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 269, 30274-30280.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1642061</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:27:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-08T12:07:20Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1642061</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1642061</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
