<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Friedhelm</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Waldhausen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">10607</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">James Cecil</namePart><namePart type="family">Cantrell</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">C. Henry</namePart><namePart type="family">Edwards</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Mathematik</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10020</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Waldhausen_017.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1782175/2313705</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription><accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Markham Publ. Co.</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1971</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-8410-1018-8</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-30085</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">205-211</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Waldhausen, F. (1971). On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. In J. C.   Cantrell &amp;amp; C. H.  Edwards (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Markham mathematics series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt; (2. print., pp. 205-211). Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs>Waldhausen, F.: On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. In: Cantrell, J.C. and Edwards , C.H. (eds.) Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969. Markham mathematics series. 2. print. p. 205-211. Markham Publ. Co., Chicago (1971).</lncs>
<mla>Waldhausen, Friedhelm. “On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings”. &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. James Cecil  Cantrell and C. Henry Edwards. 2. print. Chicago: Markham Publ. Co., 1971. Markham mathematics series. 205-211.</mla>
<ieee>F. Waldhausen, “On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings”, &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt;, J.C.  Cantrell and C.H. Edwards, eds., Markham mathematics series, 2. print.,  Chicago: Markham Publ. Co., 1971,  pp.205-211.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Waldhausen, Friedhelm. 1971. “On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings”. In &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt;, ed. James Cecil  Cantrell and C. Henry Edwards, 2. print., 205-211. Markham mathematics series. Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Waldhausen, F. (1971). “On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings” in &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt;, ed. J. C.   Cantrell and C. H.  Edwards Markham mathematics series 2. print. (Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.), 205-211.</frontiers>
<apa>Waldhausen, F. (1971). On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. In J. C.   Cantrell &amp;amp; C. H.  Edwards (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Markham mathematics series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt; (2. print., pp. 205-211). Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Waldhausen, in &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J.C.  Cantrell, C.H. Edwards), Markham Publ. Co., Chicago, &lt;strong&gt;1971&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 205-211.</angewandte-chemie>
<aps>F.  Waldhausen, On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings, in &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt;, edited by J. C.   Cantrell and C. H.  Edwards, Markham mathematics series, 2. print. (Markham Publ. Co., Chicago, 1971), p. 205-211.</aps>
<bio1>Waldhausen F (1971) &lt;br /&gt;On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969. Cantrell JC, Edwards  CH (Eds); Markham mathematics series,  2. print. Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.:  205-211.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Waldhausen, F. (1971). On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings (Markham mathematics series). &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt; (2. print., S. 205-211). Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Waldhausen, F., 1971. On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. In J. C.   Cantrell &amp;amp; C. H.  Edwards, eds. &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt;. Markham mathematics series. 2. print.  Chicago: Markham Publ. Co., pp. 205-211.</harvard1>
<ama>Waldhausen F. On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. In: Cantrell JC, Edwards  CH, eds. &lt;em&gt;Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969&lt;/em&gt;. Markham mathematics series. 2. print. Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.;  1971: 205-211.</ama>
<default>Waldhausen F (1971)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969. Cantrell JC, Edwards  CH (Eds); Markham mathematics series,  2. print. Chicago: Markham Publ. Co.:  205-211.</default>
<wels>Waldhausen, F. (1971): On mappings of handlebodies and Heegaard splittings. In: James Cecil  Cantrell; C. Henry Edwards (Hrsg.):  Topology of manifolds: proceedings of the University of Georgia Topology of Manifolds Institute 1969. 2. print. Chicago: Markham Publ. Co. (Markham mathematics series, ).  S. 205-211.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1782175</recordIdentifier><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-06-27T12:53:54Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1782175</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1782175</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
