<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andrea</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kirschner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Malthaner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">9195505</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Wilhelm</namePart><namePart type="family">Heitmeyer</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Heinz-Gerhard</namePart><namePart type="family">Haupt</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Andrea</namePart><namePart type="family">Kirschner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Stefan</namePart><namePart type="family">Malthaner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Institut für interdisziplinäre Konflikt- und Gewaltforschung</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10058</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>Springer</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies</title></titleInfo>
<part><extent unit="pages">3-45</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Kirschner, A., and Malthaner, S. (2010). “Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework” in &lt;em&gt;Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies&lt;/em&gt;, ed. W.  Heitmeyer, H. - G.  Haupt, A.  Kirschner, and S.  Malthaner (New York: Springer), 3-45.</frontiers>
<apa>Kirschner, A., &amp;amp; Malthaner, S. (2010). Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework. In W.  Heitmeyer, H. - G.  Haupt, A.  Kirschner, &amp;amp; S.  Malthaner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 3-45). New York: Springer.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Kirschner, and S.  Malthaner, in &lt;em&gt;Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: W. Heitmeyer, H.-G. Haupt, A. Kirschner, S. Malthaner), Springer, New York, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 3-45.</angewandte-chemie>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kirschner, Andrea, and Malthaner, Stefan. 2010. “Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework”. In &lt;em&gt;Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Wilhelm Heitmeyer, Heinz-Gerhard Haupt, Andrea Kirschner, and Stefan Malthaner, 3-45. New York: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Kirschner, Andrea, and Malthaner, Stefan. “Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework”. &lt;em&gt;Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Wilhelm Heitmeyer, Heinz-Gerhard Haupt, Andrea Kirschner, and Stefan Malthaner. New York: Springer, 2010. 3-45.</mla>
<lncs>Kirschner, A., Malthaner, S.: Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework. In: Heitmeyer, W., Haupt, H.-G., Kirschner, A., and Malthaner, S. (eds.) Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies. p. 3-45. Springer, New York (2010).</lncs>
<ieee>A. Kirschner and S. Malthaner, “Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework”, &lt;em&gt;Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies&lt;/em&gt;, W. Heitmeyer, et al., eds.,  New York: Springer, 2010,  pp.3-45.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kirschner, A., &amp;amp; Malthaner, S. (2010). Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework. In W.  Heitmeyer, H. - G.  Haupt, A.  Kirschner, &amp;amp; S.  Malthaner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 3-45). New York: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Kirschner A, Malthaner S (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies. Heitmeyer W, Haupt H-G, Kirschner A, Malthaner S (Eds);New York: Springer:  3-45.</default>
<wels>Kirschner, A.; Malthaner, S. (2010): Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework. In: Wilhelm Heitmeyer; Heinz-Gerhard Haupt; Andrea Kirschner; Stefan Malthaner (Hrsg.):  Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies. New York: Springer.  S. 3-45.</wels>
<aps>A.  Kirschner and S.  Malthaner, Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework, in &lt;em&gt;Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies&lt;/em&gt;, edited by W.  Heitmeyer, et al. (Springer, New York, 2010), p. 3-45.</aps>
<bio1>Kirschner A, Malthaner S (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies. Heitmeyer W, Haupt H-G, Kirschner A, Malthaner S (Eds); New York: Springer:  3-45.</bio1>
<harvard1>Kirschner, A., &amp;amp; Malthaner, S., 2010. Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework. In W.  Heitmeyer, et al., eds. &lt;em&gt;Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies&lt;/em&gt;.  New York: Springer, pp. 3-45.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kirschner, A. &amp;amp; Malthaner, S. (2010). Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework. &lt;em&gt;Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies&lt;/em&gt; (S. 3-45). New York: Springer.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Kirschner A, Malthaner S. Control of Violence: an Analytical Framework. In: Heitmeyer W, Haupt H-G, Kirschner A, Malthaner S, eds. &lt;em&gt;Control of Violence: Historical and International Perspectives on Violence in Modern Societies&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Springer;  2010: 3-45.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1919689</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-24T15:09:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-01-28T09:29:50Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1919689</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1919689</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
