<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">73476</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Sigrid</namePart><namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Technische Fakultät</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Center of Excellence - Cognitive Interaction Technology CITEC</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>AG Wissensbasierte Systeme</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Wachsmuth_69.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1779326/2312660</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription><accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Univ. of Georgia</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1982</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-18358</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">43-49</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee>I. Wachsmuth, “Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, S. Wagner, ed.,  Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia, 1982,  pp.43-49.</ieee>
<lncs>Wachsmuth, I.: Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction. In: Wagner, S. (ed.) Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. p. 43-49. Univ. of Georgia, Athens, Ga. (1982).</lncs>
<mla>Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Sigrid Wagner. Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia, 1982. 43-49.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (1982). Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction. In S.  Wagner (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 43-49). Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: S. Wagner), Univ. Of Georgia, Athens, Ga., &lt;strong&gt;1982&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 43-49.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Wachsmuth, I. (1982). Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction. In S.  Wagner (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 43-49). Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia.</apa>
<frontiers>Wachsmuth, I. (1982). “Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, ed. S.  Wagner (Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia), 43-49.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1982. “Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Sigrid Wagner, 43-49. Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<harvard1>Wachsmuth, I., 1982. Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction. In S.  Wagner, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;.  Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia, pp. 43-49.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Wachsmuth, I. (1982). Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (S. 43-49). Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Wachsmuth I. Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction. In: Wagner S, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;. Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia;  1982: 43-49.</ama>
<aps>I.  Wachsmuth, Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, edited by S.  Wagner (Univ. of Georgia, Athens, Ga., 1982), p. 43-49.</aps>
<bio1>Wachsmuth I (1982) &lt;br /&gt;Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Wagner S (Ed); Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia:  43-49.</bio1>
<wels>Wachsmuth, I. (1982): Questions on some issues in the psychology of mathematics instruction. In: Sigrid Wagner (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia.  S. 43-49.</wels>
<default>Wachsmuth I (1982)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Wagner S (Ed);Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia:  43-49.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1779326</recordIdentifier><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-01-26T08:38:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1779326</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1779326</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
