<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">S</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Niemann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">C</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Keel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pühler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21937</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Werner</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Selbitschka</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22010</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Biologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The impact of biocontrol strain Pseudomonas fluorescens CHA0 and of its genetically modified, antibiotic-overproducing derivative CHA0/pME3424 on a reconstructed population of the plant-beneficial Sinorhizobium meliloti bacteria was assessed in gnotobiotic systems. In sterile soil, the final density of the reconstructed S. meliloti population decreased by more than one order of magnitude in the presence of either of the Pseudomonas strains when compared to a control without addition of P. fluorescens. Moreover there was a change in the proportion of each individual S. meliloti strain within the population. Plant tests also revealed changes in the nodulating S. meliloti population in the presence of strains CHA0 or CHA0/ pME3424. In both treatments one S. meliloti strain, f43, was significantly reduced in its root nodule occupancy. Analysis of alfalfa yields showed a slight but statistically significant increase in shoot dry weight when strain CHA0 was added to the reconstructed S. meliloti population whereas no such effect was observed with CHA0/pME3424.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>SPRINGER VERLAG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1997</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>microcosm studies</topic><topic>Sinorhizobium</topic><topic>symbiotic nitrogen fixation</topic><topic>genetically modified organisms</topic><topic>ecological impact</topic><topic>plant-beneficial bacteria</topic><topic>meliloti</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0178-2762</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1432-0789</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1997XY71000004</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/s003740050309</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>25</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>3</number></detail><extent unit="pages">240-244</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Niemann, S.; Keel, C.; Pühler, A.; Selbitschka, W. (1997): Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems &lt;em&gt;BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS&lt;/em&gt;,25:(3): 240-244.</wels>
<default>Niemann S, Keel C, Pühler A, Selbitschka W (1997) &lt;br /&gt;BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS 25(3): 240-244.</default>
<harvard1>Niemann, S., et al., 1997. Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems. &lt;em&gt;BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS&lt;/em&gt;, 25(3), p 240-244.</harvard1>
<ama>Niemann S, Keel C, Pühler A, Selbitschka W. Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems. &lt;em&gt;BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS&lt;/em&gt;. 1997;25(3):240-244.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Niemann, S., Keel, C., Pühler, A. &amp;amp; Selbitschka, W. (1997). Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems. &lt;em&gt;BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;25&lt;/em&gt;(3), 240-244. SPRINGER VERLAG. doi:10.1007/s003740050309.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Niemann S, Keel C, Pühler A, Selbitschka W (1997) &lt;br /&gt;Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems.&lt;br /&gt;BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS 25(3): 240-244.</bio1>
<aps>S.  Niemann, et al., Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems, BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS &lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt;, 240-244 (1997).</aps>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Niemann, C.  Keel, A.  Pühler, and W.  Selbitschka, “Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems”, &lt;em&gt;BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1997&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;25&lt;/em&gt;, 240-244.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Niemann, S., Keel, C., Pühler, A., &amp;amp; Selbitschka, W. (1997). Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems. &lt;em&gt;BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;25&lt;/em&gt;(3), 240-244.</apa>
<frontiers>Niemann, S., Keel, C., Pühler, A., and Selbitschka, W. (1997). Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems. &lt;em&gt;BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS&lt;/em&gt; 25, 240-244.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Niemann, S, Keel, C, Pühler, Alfred, and Selbitschka, Werner. 1997. “Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems”. &lt;em&gt;BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS&lt;/em&gt; 25 (3): 240-244.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee>S. Niemann, et al., “Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems”, &lt;em&gt;BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 25, 1997,  pp. 240-244.</ieee>
<mla>Niemann, S, Keel, C, Pühler, Alfred, and Selbitschka, Werner. “Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems”. &lt;em&gt;BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS&lt;/em&gt; 25.3 (1997): 240-244.</mla>
<lncs>Niemann, S., Keel, C., Pühler, A., Selbitschka, W.: Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems. BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS. 25, 240-244 (1997).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Niemann, S., Keel, C., Pühler, A., &amp;amp; Selbitschka, W. (1997). Biocontrol strain Pseudomonas flourescens CHAO and its genetically modified derivative with enhanced biocontrol capability exert comparable effects on the structure of a Sinorhizobium meliloti population in gnotobiotic systems. &lt;em&gt;BIOLOGY AND FERTILITY OF SOILS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;25&lt;/em&gt;(3), 240-244.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1627429</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:22:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-09T08:49:32Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1627429</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1627429</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
