<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rafael T.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Mikolajczyk</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Annette E.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Maxwell</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Vihra</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Naydenova</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sabine</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Meier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Walid</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">El Ansari</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Gesundheitswissenschaften</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10046</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Despite a high prevalence of depressive symptoms among university students, few studies have examined how this mental health problem is associated with perceived stress and perceived burdens related to being a student. Methods:  We conducted a cross-sectional study of 2,103 first year students from one western (Germany), one central (Poland), and one south-eastern European country (Bulgaria). The self-administered questionnaires included the modified Beck Depression Inventory and Cohen&apos;s Perceived Stress Scale. A 13 item scale measured perceived burdens related to being a student with four subscales: &apos;&apos;Course work&apos;&apos;, &apos;&apos;Relationships&apos;&apos;, &apos;&apos;Isolation&apos;&apos;, and &apos;&apos;Future&apos;&apos;. Results: Depressive symptoms were highly prevalent in all three countries (M-BDI &amp;#8805;35: 34% in Poland, 39% in Bulgaria, and 23% in Germany). Students felt more burdened by course work and bad job prospects (&apos;&apos;Future&apos;&apos;) than by relationship problems or by feelings of isolation. The perceived burdens subscales &apos;&apos;Future&apos;&apos;, &apos;&apos;Relationship&apos;&apos; and &apos;&apos;Isolation&apos;&apos; remained associated with depressive symptoms after adjusting for perceived stress, which displayed a strong association with depressive symptoms. The association between perceived stress and depressive symptoms differed by gender. These findings were similar in all three countries. Conclusion: Perceived burdens related to studying are positively associated with higher depression scores among students, not only by mediation through perceived stress but also directly. While the strong association between perceived stress and depressive symptoms suggests the need for interventions that improve stress management, perceived burdens should also be addressed.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="30.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1783705/2314250</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription><accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1745-0179</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">18598340</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-pub-17837052</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1745-0179-4-19</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>4</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">19</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Mikolajczyk RT, Maxwell AE, Naydenova V, Meier S, El Ansari W (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health 4(1).</default>
<wels>Mikolajczyk, R. T.; Maxwell, A. E.; Naydenova, V.; Meier, S.; El Ansari, W. (2008): Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries &lt;em&gt;Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health&lt;/em&gt;,4:(1)</wels>
<aps>R. T.  Mikolajczyk, et al., Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries, Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;, (2008).</aps>
<bio1>Mikolajczyk RT, Maxwell AE, Naydenova V, Meier S, El Ansari W (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries.&lt;br /&gt;Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health 4(1).</bio1>
<harvard1>Mikolajczyk, R.T., et al., 2008. Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries. &lt;em&gt;Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health&lt;/em&gt;, 4(1).</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Mikolajczyk, R.T., Maxwell, A.E., Naydenova, V., Meier, S. &amp;amp; El Ansari, W. (2008). Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries. &lt;em&gt;Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;(1). doi:10.1186/1745-0179-4-19.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Mikolajczyk RT, Maxwell AE, Naydenova V, Meier S, El Ansari W. Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries. &lt;em&gt;Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health&lt;/em&gt;. 2008;4(1).</ama>
<frontiers>Mikolajczyk, R. T., Maxwell, A. E., Naydenova, V., Meier, S., and El Ansari, W. (2008). Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries. &lt;em&gt;Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health&lt;/em&gt; 4.</frontiers>
<apa>Mikolajczyk, R. T., Maxwell, A. E., Naydenova, V., Meier, S., &amp;amp; El Ansari, W. (2008). Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries. &lt;em&gt;Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;(1).</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>R. T.  Mikolajczyk, A. E.  Maxwell, V.  Naydenova, S.  Meier, and W.  El Ansari, “Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries”, &lt;em&gt;Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Mikolajczyk, Rafael T., Maxwell, Annette E., Naydenova, Vihra, Meier, Sabine, and El Ansari, Walid. 2008. “Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries”. &lt;em&gt;Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health&lt;/em&gt; 4 (1).&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Mikolajczyk, Rafael T., Maxwell, Annette E., Naydenova, Vihra, Meier, Sabine, and El Ansari, Walid. “Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries”. &lt;em&gt;Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health&lt;/em&gt; 4.1 (2008).</mla>
<lncs>Mikolajczyk, R.T., Maxwell, A.E., Naydenova, V., Meier, S., El Ansari, W.: Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries. Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health. 4, (2008).</lncs>
<ieee>R.T. Mikolajczyk, et al., “Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries”, &lt;em&gt;Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 4, 2008.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Mikolajczyk, R. T., Maxwell, A. E., Naydenova, V., Meier, S., &amp;amp; El Ansari, W. (2008). Depressive symptoms and perceived burdens related to being a student: survey in three European countries. &lt;em&gt;Clinical Practice and Epidemiology in Mental Health&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;(1).&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1783705</recordIdentifier><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-01-26T08:38:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1783705</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1783705</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
