<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hamelmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">40261</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heinzmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">40276</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Szekeres</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">N</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kirov</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nikolova</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">33079537</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">29133467</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Silicon oxide thin films deposited on Si substrates in a RF-plasma CVD reactor, using Si(OC2H5)(4) (TEOS) as the precursor and oxygen as the gas ambient, were studied by IR spectrophotometry. All depositions were performed at a substrate temperature of 200 degrees C, a plasma power of 20 or 80 W and with a DC-bias of -120 V applied to the Si substrate. The observed IR peaks were assigned to corresponding vibrational modes. Peaks related to Si-H, C-H and OH bond vibrations were also detected. Some degree of porosity exists, resulting in a lower refractive index of the films than that typical for SiO2 material.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>NATL INST OPTOELECTRONICS</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>thin films</topic><topic>silicon oxides</topic><topic>optical properties</topic><topic>IR spectroscopy</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1454-4164</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000228522700068</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>7</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">389-392</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Hamelmann F, Heinzmann U, Szekeres A, Kirov N, Nikolova T. Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis. In:  &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 7. NATL INST OPTOELECTRONICS;  2005: 389-392.</ama>
<harvard1>Hamelmann, F., et al., 2005. Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis. In &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS&lt;/em&gt;. no.7  NATL INST OPTOELECTRONICS, pp. 389-392.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Hamelmann, F., Heinzmann, U., Szekeres, A., Kirov, N. &amp;amp; Nikolova, T. (2005). Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS&lt;/em&gt; (S. 389-392). NATL INST OPTOELECTRONICS.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Hamelmann F, Heinzmann U, Szekeres A, Kirov N, Nikolova T (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis. &lt;br /&gt;In:  JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS. 7. NATL INST OPTOELECTRONICS:  389-392.</bio1>
<aps> F.  Hamelmann, et al., Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis, in &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;7&lt;/strong&gt; (NATL INST OPTOELECTRONICS, 2005), p. 389-392.</aps>
<wels>Hamelmann, F.; Heinzmann, U.; Szekeres, A.; Kirov, N.; Nikolova, T. (2005): Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis. In: JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS. NATL INST OPTOELECTRONICS. (7).  S. 389-392.</wels>
<default>Hamelmann F, Heinzmann U, Szekeres A, Kirov N, Nikolova T (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS. 7. NATL INST OPTOELECTRONICS:  389-392.</default>
<ieee> F. Hamelmann, et al., “Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 7, NATL INST OPTOELECTRONICS, 2005,  pp.389-392.</ieee>
<lncs> Hamelmann, F., Heinzmann, U., Szekeres, A., Kirov, N., Nikolova, T.: Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis. JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS. 7, p. 389-392. NATL INST OPTOELECTRONICS (2005).</lncs>
<mla>Hamelmann, Frank, Heinzmann, Ulrich, Szekeres, A, Kirov, N, and Nikolova, T. “Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS&lt;/em&gt;. NATL INST OPTOELECTRONICS, 2005.Vol. 7. 389-392.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Hamelmann, F., Heinzmann, U., Szekeres, A., Kirov, N., &amp;amp; Nikolova, T. (2005). Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;(1), 389-392.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Hamelmann, U.  Heinzmann, A.  Szekeres, N.  Kirov, and T.  Nikolova, in &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS&lt;/em&gt;, Natl Inst Optoelectronics, &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 389-392.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Hamelmann, F., Heinzmann, U., Szekeres, A., Kirov, N., &amp;amp; Nikolova, T. (2005). Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;(1), 389-392.</apa>
<frontiers>Hamelmann, F., Heinzmann, U., Szekeres, A., Kirov, N., and Nikolova, T. (2005). “Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis” in &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 7, (NATL INST OPTOELECTRONICS), 389-392.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Hamelmann, Frank, Heinzmann, Ulrich, Szekeres, A, Kirov, N, and Nikolova, T. 2005. “Deposition of silicon oxide thin films in TEOS with addition of oxygen to the plasma ambient: IR spectra analysis”. In &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF OPTOELECTRONICS AND ADVANCED MATERIALS&lt;/em&gt;, 7:389-392. NATL INST OPTOELECTRONICS.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1604354</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:40:17Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-09-29T08:49:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1604354</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1604354</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
