<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stephan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Unger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">37001512</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Cristina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Máguas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">João Santos</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pereira</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Luís Miguel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Aires</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Teresa Soares</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">David</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christiane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Werner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22053</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7676-9057</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Biologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Experimentelle Ökologie und Ökosystembiologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2685201</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Net carbon flux partitioning was used to disentangle abiotic and biotic drivers of all
important component fluxes influencing the overall sink strength of a Mediterranean
ecosystem during a rapid spring to summer transition. Between May and June 2006 we
analyzed how seasonal drought affected ecosystem assimilation and respiration fluxes in
an evergreen oak woodland and attributed variations in the component fluxes (trees,
understory, soil microorganisms and roots) to observations at the ecosystem scale. We
observed a two thirds decrease in both ecosystem carbon assimilation and respiration (Reco)
within only 15 days time. The impact of decreasing Reco on the ecosystem carbon balance
was smaller than the impact of decreasing primary productivity. Flux partitioning of GPP
and Reco into their component fluxes from trees, understory, soil microorganisms and roots
showed that declining ecosystem sink strength was due to a large drought and temperatureinduced
decrease in understory carbon uptake (from 56% to 21%). Hence, the shallow-rooted
annuals mainly composing the understory have a surprisingly large impact on the source/
sink behavior of this open evergreen oak woodland during spring to summer transition and
the timing of the onset of drought might have a large effect on the annual carbon budget. In
response to seasonal drought Reco was increasingly dominated by respiration of heterotrophic
soil microorganisms, while the root flux was found to be of minor importance. Soil
respiration flux decreased with drought but its contribution to total daily CO2-exchange
increased by 11.5%. This partitioning approach disentangled changes in respiratory and
photosynthetic ecosystem fluxes that were not apparent from the eddy-covariance or the
soil respiration data alone. By the novel combination of understory vs. overstory carbon flux
partitioning with soil respiration data fromtrenched and control plots, we gained a detailed
understanding of factors controlling net carbon exchange of Mediterranean ecosystems.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Carbon fluxes
Mediterranean woodland
Ecosystem respiration
Net ecosystem exchange
Partitioning
Drought</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Agricultural and Forest Meteorology</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0168-1923</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000265363900005</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/j.agrformet.2008.11.013</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>149</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>6-7</number></detail><extent unit="pages">949-961</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Unger, S., Máguas, C., Pereira, J.S., Aires, L.M., David, T.S. &amp;amp; Werner, C. (2009). Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought. &lt;em&gt;Agricultural and Forest Meteorology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;149&lt;/em&gt;(6-7), 949-961. Elsevier BV. doi:10.1016/j.agrformet.2008.11.013.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Unger, S., et al., 2009. Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought. &lt;em&gt;Agricultural and Forest Meteorology&lt;/em&gt;, 149(6-7), p 949-961.</harvard1>
<ama>Unger S, Máguas C, Pereira JS, Aires LM, David TS, Werner C. Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought. &lt;em&gt;Agricultural and Forest Meteorology&lt;/em&gt;. 2009;149(6-7):949-961.</ama>
<bio1>Unger S, Máguas C, Pereira JS, Aires LM, David TS, Werner C (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought.&lt;br /&gt;Agricultural and Forest Meteorology 149(6-7): 949-961.</bio1>
<aps>S.  Unger, et al., Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought, Agricultural and Forest Meteorology &lt;strong&gt;149&lt;/strong&gt;, 949-961 (2009).</aps>
<wels>Unger, S.; Máguas, C.; Pereira, J. S.; Aires, L. M.; David, T. S.; Werner, C. (2009): Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought &lt;em&gt;Agricultural and Forest Meteorology&lt;/em&gt;,149:(6-7): 949-961.</wels>
<default>Unger S, Máguas C, Pereira JS, Aires LM, David TS, Werner C (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Agricultural and Forest Meteorology 149(6-7): 949-961.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Unger, S., Máguas, C., Pereira, J. S., Aires, L. M., David, T. S., &amp;amp; Werner, C. (2009). Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought. &lt;em&gt;Agricultural and Forest Meteorology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;149&lt;/em&gt;(6-7), 949-961.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>S. Unger, et al., “Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought”, &lt;em&gt;Agricultural and Forest Meteorology&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 149, 2009,  pp. 949-961.</ieee>
<lncs>Unger, S., Máguas, C., Pereira, J.S., Aires, L.M., David, T.S., Werner, C.: Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought. Agricultural and Forest Meteorology. 149, 949-961 (2009).</lncs>
<mla>Unger, Stephan, Máguas, Cristina, Pereira, João Santos, Aires, Luís Miguel, David, Teresa Soares, and Werner, Christiane. “Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought”. &lt;em&gt;Agricultural and Forest Meteorology&lt;/em&gt; 149.6-7 (2009): 949-961.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Unger, Stephan, Máguas, Cristina, Pereira, João Santos, Aires, Luís Miguel, David, Teresa Soares, and Werner, Christiane. 2009. “Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought”. &lt;em&gt;Agricultural and Forest Meteorology&lt;/em&gt; 149 (6-7): 949-961.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Unger, C.  Máguas, J. S.  Pereira, L. M.  Aires, T. S.  David, and C.  Werner, “Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought”, &lt;em&gt;Agricultural and Forest Meteorology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;149&lt;/em&gt;, 949-961.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Unger, S., Máguas, C., Pereira, J. S., Aires, L. M., David, T. S., &amp;amp; Werner, C. (2009). Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought. &lt;em&gt;Agricultural and Forest Meteorology&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;149&lt;/em&gt;(6-7), 949-961.</apa>
<frontiers>Unger, S., Máguas, C., Pereira, J. S., Aires, L. M., David, T. S., and Werner, C. (2009). Partitioning carbon fluxes in a Mediterranean oak forest to disentangle changes in ecosystem sink strength during drought. &lt;em&gt;Agricultural and Forest Meteorology&lt;/em&gt; 149, 949-961.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1925787</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-12-03T12:47:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-12-17T15:30:12Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1925787</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1925787</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
