<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">O</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">DIEKMANN</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tschesche</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">19406</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Biochemie I</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17967</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">1. The kinetics of the degradation of the kinins bradykinin and Met-Lys-bradykinin, angiotensins I and II and the tachykinin substance P by PMNL-collagenase (MMP 8), PMNL-gelatinase (MMP 9) and by the recombinant catalytic domain of MMP 8 (rcd-PMNL-c) was examined by RP-HPLC. The resulting fragments were identified by automated Edman degradation or by amino acid analysis. 2. The initial degradation rates of substance P at a substrate concentration of 25 mu M were 5 min(-1) for MMP 9 and 150 min(-1) for MMP 8. The kinetic constants K-M and k(cat) were determined by concentration-dependent measurements. For MMP 8/substance P the constants were K-M = 78 +/- 14 mu M and k(cat) = 412 +/- 67 min(-1). For MMP 9/substance P the constants were K-M = 91 +/- 15 mu M and k(cat) = 25 +/- 4 min(-1). Both enzymes cleaved substance P between Gln(6) and Phe(7) and between Gly(9) and Leu(10). 3. Under the same conditions, MMP 8 degraded angiotensin I at an initial rate of 20 h(-1) resulting mainly in the vasoactive fragments angiotensin II and angiotensin(1-7). At a substrate concentration of 25 mu M and an enzyme/substrate ratio of 1:100, angiotensin II was degraded very slowly (19% in 24 h) by MMP 8. Under these conditions, MMP 9 degraded angiotensin I to a lesser extent than MMP 8 (25% in 24 h) and was unable to cleave angiotensin II. 4. Under the same conditions, bradykinin and Met-Lys-bradykinin were cleaved by PMNL-collagenase at a rate of 20% in 24 h, producing BK(1-7) and BK(1-8). PMNL-gelatinase was unable to cleave the kinins under these conditions. 5. In all cases, rcd-PMNL-c produced the same fragments as wild type PMNL-collagenase, but at a significantly lower rate.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>ASSOC BRAS DIVULG CIENTIFICA</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1994</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES</topic><topic>GELATINASE</topic><topic>KININS</topic><topic>TACHYKININS</topic><topic>ANGIOTENSINS</topic><topic>COLLAGENASE</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0100-879X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">7538373</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1994PC60600016</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>27</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>8</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1865-1876</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs>DIEKMANN, O., Tschesche, H.: DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9. BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH. 27, p. 1865-1876. ASSOC BRAS DIVULG CIENTIFICA (1994).</lncs>
<mla>DIEKMANN, O, and Tschesche, Harald. “DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9”. &lt;em&gt;BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;. ASSOC BRAS DIVULG CIENTIFICA, 1994.Vol. 27. 1865-1876.</mla>
<ieee>O. DIEKMANN and H. Tschesche, “DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9”, &lt;em&gt;BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 27, ASSOC BRAS DIVULG CIENTIFICA, 1994,  pp.1865-1876.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;DIEKMANN, O., &amp;amp; Tschesche, H. (1994). DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9. &lt;em&gt;BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;27&lt;/em&gt;(8), 1865-1876.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>DIEKMANN, O., and Tschesche, H. (1994). “DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9” in &lt;em&gt;BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 27, (ASSOC BRAS DIVULG CIENTIFICA), 1865-1876.</frontiers>
<apa>DIEKMANN, O., &amp;amp; Tschesche, H. (1994). DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9. &lt;em&gt;BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;27&lt;/em&gt;(8), 1865-1876.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>O.  DIEKMANN, and H.  Tschesche, in &lt;em&gt;BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, Assoc Bras Divulg Cientifica, &lt;strong&gt;1994&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1865-1876.</angewandte-chemie>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;DIEKMANN, O, and Tschesche, Harald. 1994. “DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9”. In &lt;em&gt;BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, 27:1865-1876. ASSOC BRAS DIVULG CIENTIFICA.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<bio1>DIEKMANN O, Tschesche H (1994) &lt;br /&gt;DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9. &lt;br /&gt;In:  BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH. 27. ASSOC BRAS DIVULG CIENTIFICA:  1865-1876.</bio1>
<aps>O.  DIEKMANN and H.  Tschesche, DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9, in &lt;em&gt;BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;27&lt;/strong&gt; (ASSOC BRAS DIVULG CIENTIFICA, 1994), p. 1865-1876.</aps>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;DIEKMANN, O. &amp;amp; Tschesche, H. (1994). DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9. &lt;em&gt;BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1865-1876). ASSOC BRAS DIVULG CIENTIFICA.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>DIEKMANN O, Tschesche H. DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9. In:  &lt;em&gt;BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 27. ASSOC BRAS DIVULG CIENTIFICA;  1994: 1865-1876.</ama>
<harvard1>DIEKMANN, O., &amp;amp; Tschesche, H., 1994. DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9. In &lt;em&gt;BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;. no.27  ASSOC BRAS DIVULG CIENTIFICA, pp. 1865-1876.</harvard1>
<default>DIEKMANN O, Tschesche H (1994)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH. 27. ASSOC BRAS DIVULG CIENTIFICA:  1865-1876.</default>
<wels>DIEKMANN, O.; Tschesche, H. (1994): DEGRADATION OF KININS, ANGIOTENSINS AND SUBSTANCE-P BY POLYMORPHONUCLEAR MATRIX METALLOPROTEINASES MMP-8 AND MMP-9. In: BRAZILIAN JOURNAL OF MEDICAL AND BIOLOGICAL RESEARCH. ASSOC BRAS DIVULG CIENTIFICA. (27).  S. 1865-1876.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1642954</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:27:50Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-08T10:52:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1642954</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1642954</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
