<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulrich</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schulte</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Daniel</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kuesters</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sebastian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Steinfartz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">164260</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We studied patterns of annual movement of individual adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) during the years 2001 and 2002 in Western Germany in a typical middle European habitat for this species. We tested whether salamanders inhabit small home ranges and move little during the activity period as predicted for a species that shows strong site fidelity to a limited area. Initially, 98 individuals were collected in their natural habitat and marked with passive integrated transponder (PIT) tags. Of those individuals 88 were released at the collection site for recapture during the activity periods of the years 2001 and 2002. Ten marked individuals were kept in captivity to test for the tolerance of PIT tags. We did not find any negative impact of PIT tags on marked individuals of S. salamandra, neither under captive nor natural conditions. Forty-seven of the marked individuals (corresponding to 53% of the 88 released ones) were recaptured at least once and 28 individuals (corresponding to 32%) were recaptured multiple times. The return rate of males (78%) was higher than for females (43%). Mean home range size (and standard deviation) was estimated to 494 +/- 282 m(2) for 4 individuals as the minimum convex polygon based on 5 to 6 recapture events for each individual per year and to 1295 +/- 853 m(2) for 3 individuals with 8 records over two years. Minimum distances moved inferred from individual recaptures increased during the activity period of both years with time, indicating that individuals have more of a tendency to disperse than to stay within a limited area. Our data suggest therefore that S. salamandra adults display site fidelity, but use a much larger area than hitherto documented for this and other terrestrial salamander species.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>BRILL ACADEMIC PUBLISHERS</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Salamandra salamandra</topic><topic>home range size</topic><topic>amphibians</topic><topic>site fidelity</topic><topic>recapture</topic><topic>movement pattern</topic><topic>PIT tags</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Amphibia-Reptilia</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0173-5373</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1568-5381</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000250868800009</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1163/156853807782152543</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>28</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>4</number></detail><extent unit="pages">531-536</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Schulte U, Kuesters D, Steinfartz S (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Amphibia-Reptilia 28(4): 531-536.</default>
<wels>Schulte, U.; Kuesters, D.; Steinfartz, S. (2007): A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat &lt;em&gt;Amphibia-Reptilia&lt;/em&gt;,28:(4): 531-536.</wels>
<aps> U.  Schulte, D.  Kuesters, and S.  Steinfartz, A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat, Amphibia-Reptilia &lt;strong&gt;28&lt;/strong&gt;, 531-536 (2007).</aps>
<bio1>Schulte U, Kuesters D, Steinfartz S (2007) &lt;br /&gt;A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat.&lt;br /&gt;Amphibia-Reptilia 28(4): 531-536.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Schulte, U., Kuesters, D. &amp;amp; Steinfartz, S. (2007). A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat. &lt;em&gt;Amphibia-Reptilia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;28&lt;/em&gt;(4), 531-536. BRILL ACADEMIC PUBLISHERS. doi:10.1163/156853807782152543.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Schulte U, Kuesters D, Steinfartz S. A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat. &lt;em&gt;Amphibia-Reptilia&lt;/em&gt;. 2007;28(4):531-536.</ama>
<harvard1>Schulte, U., Kuesters, D., &amp;amp; Steinfartz, S., 2007. A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat. &lt;em&gt;Amphibia-Reptilia&lt;/em&gt;, 28(4), p 531-536.</harvard1>
<frontiers>Schulte, U., Kuesters, D., and Steinfartz, S. (2007). A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat. &lt;em&gt;Amphibia-Reptilia&lt;/em&gt; 28, 531-536.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>U.  Schulte, D.  Kuesters, and S.  Steinfartz, “A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat”, &lt;em&gt;Amphibia-Reptilia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;28&lt;/em&gt;, 531-536.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Schulte, U., Kuesters, D., &amp;amp; Steinfartz, S. (2007). A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat. &lt;em&gt;Amphibia-Reptilia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;28&lt;/em&gt;(4), 531-536.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Schulte, Ulrich, Kuesters, Daniel, and Steinfartz, Sebastian. 2007. “A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat”. &lt;em&gt;Amphibia-Reptilia&lt;/em&gt; 28 (4): 531-536.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Schulte, U., Kuesters, D., Steinfartz, S.: A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat. Amphibia-Reptilia. 28, 531-536 (2007).</lncs>
<mla>Schulte, Ulrich, Kuesters, Daniel, and Steinfartz, Sebastian. “A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat”. &lt;em&gt;Amphibia-Reptilia&lt;/em&gt; 28.4 (2007): 531-536.</mla>
<ieee> U. Schulte, D. Kuesters, and S. Steinfartz, “A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat”, &lt;em&gt;Amphibia-Reptilia&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 28, 2007,  pp. 531-536.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Schulte, U., Kuesters, D., &amp;amp; Steinfartz, S. (2007). A PIT tag based analysis of annual movement patterns of adult fire salamanders (Salamandra salamandra) in a Middle European habitat. &lt;em&gt;Amphibia-Reptilia&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;28&lt;/em&gt;(4), 531-536.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1631507</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:05:46Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-10-24T12:20:44Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1631507</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1631507</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
