<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Olaf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kruse</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22124</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">G. H.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schmid</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Centrum für Biotechnologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">89815</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Algenbiotechnologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">4833667</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">For the qualitative characterization of D1 as a lipid-binding peptide, the effect of the lipids phosphatidylglycerol (PG), monogalactosyldiacylglyceridc (MGDG) and phosphatidylcholine (PC) on PSII-oxygen evolution was analysed in reconstitution experiments. In these experiments purified photosystem II (PSII)-particle preparations were treated with the enzyme phospholipase A(2) and supplemented with lipid emulsions. We were able to show that the inhibition of electron transport, as the consequence of this lipase treatment, was only relieved, if phosphatidylglycerol was added to the preparation. A model was proposed. in which phosphatidylglycerol is a functional effector for the optimal conformation of D1 in the PSII core complex. Phosphatidylglycerol molecules are unusually tightly hound to the D1 peptide by hydrophobic interactions. A covalent binding seems not probable. The localisation of phosphatidylglycerol binding sites was found by trypsin treatment of D1 and analysis of the obtained oligopeptides with HPLC and immunoblotting. The binding sites could be confined to the hydrophobic amino acid section between arginine 27 and arginine 225, which is known to be the membrane anchor of D1. This has led us to the conclusion that the phospholipid phosphatidylglycerol plays an important role for anchoring the D1-peptide and for its orientation in the thylakoid membrane. Phosphatidylglycerol with its high amount of palmitic acid has in prokaryotic cyanobacteria apparently a role in stabilization and orientation. The high turn-over of D1 and the spatial separation of the synthesis- and incorporation-site in the membrane, developed during evolution in eukaryotic organisms, might have changed the requirement on the mobility and the orientation of D1 in photosynthetic membranes.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>VERLAG Z NATURFORSCH</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1995</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL</topic><topic>D1-PEPTIDE</topic><topic>LIPID-PROTEIN BINDING</topic><topic>CYANOBACTERIUM</topic><topic>PSII-COMPLEX</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0939-5075</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">7546031</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1995RF99300008</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>50</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>5-6</number></detail><extent unit="pages">380-390</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Kruse O, Schmid GH (1995) &lt;br /&gt;Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences 50(5-6): 380-390.</default>
<wels>Kruse, O.; Schmid, G. H. (1995): The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences&lt;/em&gt;,50:(5-6): 380-390.</wels>
<bio1>Kruse O, Schmid GH (1995) &lt;br /&gt;The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea.&lt;br /&gt;Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences 50(5-6): 380-390.</bio1>
<aps>O.  Kruse and G. H.  Schmid, The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea, Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences &lt;strong&gt;50&lt;/strong&gt;, 380-390 (1995).</aps>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kruse, O. &amp;amp; Schmid, G.H. (1995). The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;50&lt;/em&gt;(5-6), 380-390. VERLAG Z NATURFORSCH.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Kruse, O., &amp;amp; Schmid, G.H., 1995. The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences&lt;/em&gt;, 50(5-6), p 380-390.</harvard1>
<ama>Kruse O, Schmid GH. The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences&lt;/em&gt;. 1995;50(5-6):380-390.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kruse, Olaf, and Schmid, G. H. 1995. “The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea”. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences&lt;/em&gt; 50 (5-6): 380-390.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Kruse, O., and Schmid, G. H. (1995). The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences&lt;/em&gt; 50, 380-390.</frontiers>
<apa>Kruse, O., &amp;amp; Schmid, G. H. (1995). The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;50&lt;/em&gt;(5-6), 380-390.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>O.  Kruse, and G. H.  Schmid, “The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea”, &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1995&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;50&lt;/em&gt;, 380-390.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kruse, O., &amp;amp; Schmid, G. H. (1995). The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;50&lt;/em&gt;(5-6), 380-390.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs>Kruse, O., Schmid, G.H.: The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea. Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences. 50, 380-390 (1995).</lncs>
<mla>Kruse, Olaf, and Schmid, G. H. “The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea”. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences&lt;/em&gt; 50.5-6 (1995): 380-390.</mla>
<ieee>O. Kruse and G.H. Schmid, “The Role of Phosphatidylglycerol as a Functional Effector and Membrane Anchor of the D1-Core Peptide from Photosystem II-Particles of the Cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea”, &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Naturforschung. C, a Journal of Biosciences&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 50, 1995,  pp. 380-390.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1640654</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:15:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-12-08T18:26:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1640654</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1640654</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
