<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katharina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kohse-Höinghaus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">20770</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">J.</namePart><namePart type="family">Jarosinski</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">B.</namePart><namePart type="family">Veyssiere</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17978</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>CRC Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-0-8493-8408-0</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1201/9780849384097.ch2</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">3-13</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kohse-Höinghaus, K. (2009). Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry. In J.  Jarosinski &amp;amp; B.  Veyssiere (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 3-13). Boca Raton: CRC Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs>Kohse-Höinghaus, K.: Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry. In: Jarosinski, J. and Veyssiere, B. (eds.) Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction. p. 3-13. CRC Press, Boca Raton (2009).</lncs>
<mla>Kohse-Höinghaus, Katharina. “Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry”. &lt;em&gt;Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. J. Jarosinski and B. Veyssiere. Boca Raton: CRC Press, 2009. 3-13.</mla>
<ieee>K. Kohse-Höinghaus, “Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry”, &lt;em&gt;Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction&lt;/em&gt;, J. Jarosinski and B. Veyssiere, eds.,  Boca Raton: CRC Press, 2009,  pp.3-13.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kohse-Höinghaus, Katharina. 2009. “Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry”. In &lt;em&gt;Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction&lt;/em&gt;, ed. J. Jarosinski and B. Veyssiere, 3-13. Boca Raton: CRC Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Kohse-Höinghaus, K. (2009). “Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry” in &lt;em&gt;Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction&lt;/em&gt;, ed. J.  Jarosinski and B.  Veyssiere (Boca Raton: CRC Press), 3-13.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Kohse-Höinghaus, in &lt;em&gt;Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J. Jarosinski, B. Veyssiere), Crc Press, Boca Raton, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 3-13.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Kohse-Höinghaus, K. (2009). Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry. In J.  Jarosinski &amp;amp; B.  Veyssiere (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 3-13). Boca Raton: CRC Press.</apa>
<bio1>Kohse-Höinghaus K (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction. Jarosinski J, Veyssiere B (Eds); Boca Raton: CRC Press:  3-13.</bio1>
<aps>K.  Kohse-Höinghaus, Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry, in &lt;em&gt;Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction&lt;/em&gt;, edited by J.  Jarosinski and B.  Veyssiere (CRC Press, Boca Raton, 2009), p. 3-13.</aps>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kohse-Höinghaus, K. (2009). Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry. &lt;em&gt;Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction&lt;/em&gt; (S. 3-13). Boca Raton: CRC Press. doi:10.1201/9780849384097.ch2.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Kohse-Höinghaus K. Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry. In: Jarosinski J, Veyssiere B, eds. &lt;em&gt;Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction&lt;/em&gt;. Boca Raton: CRC Press;  2009: 3-13.</ama>
<harvard1>Kohse-Höinghaus, K., 2009. Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry. In J.  Jarosinski &amp;amp; B.  Veyssiere, eds. &lt;em&gt;Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction&lt;/em&gt;.  Boca Raton: CRC Press, pp. 3-13.</harvard1>
<default>Kohse-Höinghaus K (2009)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction. Jarosinski J, Veyssiere B (Eds);Boca Raton: CRC Press:  3-13.</default>
<wels>Kohse-Höinghaus, K. (2009): Diagnostics in combustion: Measurements to unravel combustion chemistry. In: J. Jarosinski; B. Veyssiere (Hrsg.):  Combustion Phenomena: Selected Mechanisms of Flame Formation, Propagation and Extinction. Boca Raton: CRC Press.  S. 3-13.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1861133</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-02-12T11:35:58Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-02-12T11:35:58Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1861133</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1861133</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
