<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">unpublished</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harry</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kullmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">19240284</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>AG 4 - Schulentwicklung und Schulforschung</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">7978212</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Wissenschaftliche Einrichtung Laborschule</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10051</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>University of California</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kullmann, H. (Unpublished).  &lt;em&gt;Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little&lt;/em&gt;. Berkeley, USA: University of California.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>H. Kullmann, &lt;em&gt;Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little&lt;/em&gt;,  Berkeley, USA: University of California, Unpublished.</ieee>
<mla>Kullmann, Harry. &lt;em&gt;Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little&lt;/em&gt;. Berkeley, USA: University of California, Unpublished.</mla>
<lncs>Kullmann, H.: Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little. University of California, Berkeley, USA (Unpublished).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kullmann, Harry. Unpublished. &lt;em&gt;Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little&lt;/em&gt;. Berkeley, USA: University of California.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Kullmann, &lt;em&gt;Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little&lt;/em&gt;, University Of California, Berkeley, USA, &lt;strong&gt;Unpublished&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Kullmann, H. (Unpublished).  &lt;em&gt;Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little&lt;/em&gt;. Berkeley, USA: University of California.</apa>
<frontiers>Kullmann, H. (Unpublished). Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little. Berkeley, USA: University of California.</frontiers>
<ama>Kullmann H. &lt;em&gt;Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little&lt;/em&gt;. Berkeley, USA: University of California; Unpublished.</ama>
<harvard1>Kullmann, H., Unpublished. &lt;em&gt;Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little&lt;/em&gt;, Berkeley, USA: University of California.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kullmann, H. (Unpublished). &lt;em&gt;Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little&lt;/em&gt;. Berkeley, USA: University of California.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<aps>H.  Kullmann, Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little, (University of California, Berkeley, Usa, Unpublished).</aps>
<bio1>Kullmann H (Unpublished) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Berkeley, USA: University of California.</bio1>
<wels>Kullmann, H. (Unpublished): Culture of science teaching, workplace conditions, and instruction-focused science teacher cooperation in high schools. Some observations from the US and selected comparisons with the situation in Germany. Unveröffentlichter Forschungsbericht für die Arbeitsgruppe von Judith W. Little. Berkeley, USA: University of California.</wels>
<default>Kullmann H (Unpublished) &lt;br /&gt;Berkeley, USA: University of California.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1932751</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-12-08T13:54:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2015-06-24T07:55:10Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1932751</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1932751</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
