<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ursula</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Müller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">13182</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ilse</namePart><namePart type="family">Lenz</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Charlotte</namePart><namePart type="family">Ullrich</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Barbara</namePart><namePart type="family">Fersch</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10068</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>Barbara Budrich</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>


<relatedItem type="host"><location><url>http://www.budrich-verlag.de/pages/frameset/reload.php?ID=175&amp;_requested_page=%2Fpages%2Fdetails.php</url></location></relatedItem>

<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-86649-091-8</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">327-343</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Müller U (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity. Lenz I, Ullrich C, Fersch B (Eds);Opladen, Farmington Hills: Barbara Budrich:  327-343.</default>
<wels>Müller, U. (2007): Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police. In: Ilse Lenz; Charlotte Ullrich; Barbara Fersch (Hrsg.):  Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity. Opladen, Farmington Hills: Barbara Budrich.  S. 327-343.</wels>
<aps>U.  Müller, Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police, in &lt;em&gt;Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity&lt;/em&gt;, edited by I.  Lenz, et al. (Barbara Budrich, Opladen, Farmington Hills, 2007), p. 327-343.</aps>
<bio1>Müller U (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity. Lenz I, Ullrich C, Fersch B (Eds); Opladen, Farmington Hills: Barbara Budrich:  327-343.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Müller, U. (2007). Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police. &lt;em&gt;Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity&lt;/em&gt; (S. 327-343). Opladen, Farmington Hills: Barbara Budrich.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Müller U. Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police. In: Lenz I, Ullrich C, Fersch B, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity&lt;/em&gt;. Opladen, Farmington Hills: Barbara Budrich;  2007: 327-343.</ama>
<harvard1>Müller, U., 2007. Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police. In I.  Lenz, C.  Ullrich, &amp;amp; B.  Fersch, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity&lt;/em&gt;.  Opladen, Farmington Hills: Barbara Budrich, pp. 327-343.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Müller, Ursula. 2007. “Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police”. In &lt;em&gt;Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Ilse Lenz, Charlotte Ullrich, and Barbara Fersch, 327-343. Opladen, Farmington Hills: Barbara Budrich.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Müller, U. (2007). “Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police” in &lt;em&gt;Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity&lt;/em&gt;, ed. I.  Lenz, C.  Ullrich, and B.  Fersch (Opladen, Farmington Hills: Barbara Budrich), 327-343.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>U.  Müller, in &lt;em&gt;Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: I. Lenz, C. Ullrich, B. Fersch), Barbara Budrich, Opladen, Farmington Hills, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 327-343.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Müller, U. (2007). Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police. In I.  Lenz, C.  Ullrich, &amp;amp; B.  Fersch (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 327-343). Opladen, Farmington Hills: Barbara Budrich.</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Müller, U. (2007). Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police. In I.  Lenz, C.  Ullrich, &amp;amp; B.  Fersch (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 327-343). Opladen, Farmington Hills: Barbara Budrich.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Müller, Ursula. “Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police”. &lt;em&gt;Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Ilse Lenz, Charlotte Ullrich, and Barbara Fersch. Opladen, Farmington Hills: Barbara Budrich, 2007. 327-343.</mla>
<lncs>Müller, U.: Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police. In: Lenz, I., Ullrich, C., and Fersch, B. (eds.) Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity. p. 327-343. Barbara Budrich, Opladen, Farmington Hills (2007).</lncs>
<ieee>U. Müller, “Gender Boundaries in Organizational Development: Body and Culture in German Police”, &lt;em&gt;Gender Orders Unbound? Globalisation, Restructing and Reciprocity&lt;/em&gt;, I. Lenz, C. Ullrich, and B. Fersch, eds.,  Opladen, Farmington Hills: Barbara Budrich, 2007,  pp.327-343.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1859791</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-01-15T11:06:30Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-01-15T11:06:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1859791</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1859791</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
