<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">D</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">BOCK</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Horst</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hinssen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21849</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">DHAESE</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Biochemische Zellbiologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2685621</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">A Ca2+-dependent actin-severing protein was purified from the tail muscle of the crayfish Astacus leptodactylus. The isolation procedure involved extraction at low ionic strength in the presence of EGTA, followed by ammonium sulfate fractionation, ion-exchange chromatography and gel filtration. The purified crayfish actin modulator appeared as a single band with a molecular mass of 105 kDa on SDS/PAGE. The crustacean actin modulator revealed basic functional properties in common with vertebrate gelsolin, like the Ca2+-activated severing of F-actin and the nucleation of actin polymerization. However, both proteins differed in major aspects: Ca2+ activation of crayfish actin modulator started at lower threshold concentrations (0.1 mu M). The effect of the modulator on shortening the nucleation phase of actin polymerization was significantly weaker at lower modulator/actin ratios. The modulator formed three distinct stoichiometric complexes with G-actin, identified as binary, ternary and quaternary. Binding of G-actin occurred in a low cooperative manner and was completely reversible by EGTA. Despite some properties being similar to those of villin, crayfish actin modulator did not cross-link actin filaments. It is regarded in principle as a gelsolin-type protein, but with characteristic functional deviations from vertebrate gelsolin.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>SPRINGER VERLAG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1994</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0014-2956</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1432-1033</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">7957188</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1994PN68900026</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1111/j.1432-1033.1994.00727.x</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>225</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">727-735</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>BOCK D, Hinssen H, DHAESE J (1994) &lt;br /&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY 225(2): 727-735.</default>
<wels>BOCK, D.; Hinssen, H.; DHAESE, J. (1994): A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;,225:(2): 727-735.</wels>
<bio1>BOCK D, Hinssen H, DHAESE J (1994) &lt;br /&gt;A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS.&lt;br /&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY 225(2): 727-735.</bio1>
<aps>D.  BOCK, H.  Hinssen, and J.  DHAESE, A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS, EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY &lt;strong&gt;225&lt;/strong&gt;, 727-735 (1994).</aps>
<ama>BOCK D, Hinssen H, DHAESE J. A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;. 1994;225(2):727-735.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;BOCK, D., Hinssen, H. &amp;amp; DHAESE, J. (1994). A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;225&lt;/em&gt;(2), 727-735. SPRINGER VERLAG. doi:10.1111/j.1432-1033.1994.00727.x.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>BOCK, D., Hinssen, H., &amp;amp; DHAESE, J., 1994. A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, 225(2), p 727-735.</harvard1>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;BOCK, D, Hinssen, Horst, and DHAESE, J. 1994. “A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS”. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 225 (2): 727-735.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>BOCK, D., Hinssen, H., and DHAESE, J. (1994). A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 225, 727-735.</frontiers>
<apa>BOCK, D., Hinssen, H., &amp;amp; DHAESE, J. (1994). A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;225&lt;/em&gt;(2), 727-735.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  BOCK, H.  Hinssen, and J.  DHAESE, “A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS”, &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1994&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;225&lt;/em&gt;, 727-735.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;BOCK, D., Hinssen, H., &amp;amp; DHAESE, J. (1994). A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;225&lt;/em&gt;(2), 727-735.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs>BOCK, D., Hinssen, H., DHAESE, J.: A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS. EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY. 225, 727-735 (1994).</lncs>
<mla>BOCK, D, Hinssen, Horst, and DHAESE, J. “A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS”. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 225.2 (1994): 727-735.</mla>
<ieee>D. BOCK, H. Hinssen, and J. DHAESE, “A GELSOLIN-RELATED ACTIN-SEVERING PROTEIN WITH FULLY REVERSIBLE ACTIN-BINDING PROPERTIES FROM THE TAIL MUSCLE OF CRAYFISH, ASTACUS-LEPTODACTYLUS”, &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 225, 1994,  pp. 727-735.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1642294</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:27:37Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-01-06T14:04:39Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1642294</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1642294</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
