<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Olaf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kruse</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22124</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">RADUNZ</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">GH</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">SCHMID</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">4833667</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">89815</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Photosystem II-particles from the cyanobacterium Oscillatoria chalybea were isolated by fractionating centrifugation. Purification of these particles was achieved by a 22 hours centrifugation over a linear sucrose density gradient at 217.500 X g. The obtained particle fraction exhibited an oxygen evolution activity which corresponded to three times the rate of intact cells and to five times the rate of intact thylakoids. The chlorophyll protein ratio was 1:10 and the ratio manganese/chlorophyll 1:34. SDS-polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis showed that the photosystem II-fraction is composed of the core peptides D 1 and D 2, the chlorophyll-binding peptides CP 43 and CP 47, the extrinsic 33 kDa peptide (manganese stabilizing peptide, MSP) and phycobiliproteins with molecular masses between 16 to 20 kDa. Cyt b(559) was not detected in our gel electrophoresis assay. Part of the peptides of the 30 kDa-region (D 1, D 2, MSP) occurred as aggregates with a molecular mass of 60 to 66 kDa. The D 1-peptide was isolated from the PS II-preparation by SDS-gel electrophoresis. The intrinisic peptide reacts in the Western blot procedure with the antiserum to phosphatidylglycerol and with the antiserum to beta-carotene. Incubation of the peptide with the antisera to monogalactosyldiglyceride, sulfoquinovosyldiglyceride and zeaxanthine resulted negatively. The binding of phosphatidylglycerol onto the D 1-peptide was confirmed by lipid analysis in HPLC and fatty acid analysis by gas chromatography. Only this Lipid, respectively the typical fatty acid mixture of this lipid was detected. The lipid is characterized by the fact that the hexadecenoic acid does not exhibit trans-configuration, as is true for phosphatidylglycerol of higher plants and algae, but occurs in cis-configuration. With the antibody being directed towards the glycerol-phosphate residue and not towards the fatty acids, it can be concluded from the reaction of the antibodies with the bound lipid that the Lipid is bound to the peptide via the fatty acid. The negatively charged phosphatidylglycerol increases the hydrophobicity of the peptide and leads to a negatively charged surface favouring binding of cations like calcium and magnesium. The fact that incubation of this PS II-fraction with phospholipase inhibits photosynthetic activity by 25% which can be fully restored by addition of phosphatidylglycerol, shows that bound phosphatidylglycerol has a functional role.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>VERLAG Z NATURFORSCH</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1994</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>BETA-CAROTENE</topic><topic>ANTIBODY</topic><topic>LIPID-PROTEIN BINDING</topic><topic>MANGANESE STABILIZING PEPTIDE</topic><topic>CYANOBACTERIUM</topic><topic>D1-PEPTIDE</topic><topic>PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0939-5075</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1994MY47800017</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>49</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1-2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">115-124</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<lncs> Kruse, O., RADUNZ, A., SCHMID, G.H.: PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA. ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES. 49, 115-124 (1994).</lncs>
<mla>Kruse, Olaf, RADUNZ, A, and SCHMID, GH. “PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA”. &lt;em&gt;ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt; 49.1-2 (1994): 115-124.</mla>
<ieee> O. Kruse, A. RADUNZ, and G.H. SCHMID, “PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA”, &lt;em&gt;ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 49, 1994,  pp. 115-124.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kruse, O., RADUNZ, A., &amp;amp; SCHMID, G. H. (1994). PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA. &lt;em&gt;ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;49&lt;/em&gt;(1-2), 115-124.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Kruse, O., RADUNZ, A., and SCHMID, G. H. (1994). PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA. &lt;em&gt;ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt; 49, 115-124.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>O.  Kruse, A.  RADUNZ, and G. H.  SCHMID, “PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA”, &lt;em&gt;ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1994&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;49&lt;/em&gt;, 115-124.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Kruse, O., RADUNZ, A., &amp;amp; SCHMID, G. H. (1994). PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA. &lt;em&gt;ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;49&lt;/em&gt;(1-2), 115-124.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kruse, Olaf, RADUNZ, A, and SCHMID, GH. 1994. “PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA”. &lt;em&gt;ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt; 49 (1-2): 115-124.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<aps> O.  Kruse, A.  RADUNZ, and G. H.  SCHMID, PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA, ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES &lt;strong&gt;49&lt;/strong&gt;, 115-124 (1994).</aps>
<bio1>Kruse O, RADUNZ A, SCHMID GH (1994) &lt;br /&gt;PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA.&lt;br /&gt;ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES 49(1-2): 115-124.</bio1>
<ama>Kruse O, RADUNZ A, SCHMID GH. PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA. &lt;em&gt;ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;. 1994;49(1-2):115-124.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kruse, O., RADUNZ, A. &amp;amp; SCHMID, G.H. (1994). PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA. &lt;em&gt;ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;49&lt;/em&gt;(1-2), 115-124. VERLAG Z NATURFORSCH.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Kruse, O., RADUNZ, A., &amp;amp; SCHMID, G.H., 1994. PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA. &lt;em&gt;ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;, 49(1-2), p 115-124.</harvard1>
<default>Kruse O, RADUNZ A, SCHMID GH (1994) &lt;br /&gt;ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES 49(1-2): 115-124.</default>
<wels>Kruse, O.; RADUNZ, A.; SCHMID, G. H. (1994): PHOSPHATIDYLGLYCEROL AND BETA-CAROTENE BOUND ONTO THE D1-CORE PEPTIDE OF PHOTOSYSTEM-II IN THE FILAMENTOUS CYANOBACTERIUM OSCILLATORIA-CHALYBEA &lt;em&gt;ZEITSCHRIFT FUR NATURFORSCHUNG C-A JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES&lt;/em&gt;,49:(1-2): 115-124.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1629503</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:28:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-11-23T13:00:05Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1629503</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1629503</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
