<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">S</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bensiek</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bangel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">B</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Georg</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stammler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">20167</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Peter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jutzi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">20144</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Anorganische Chemie und Strukturchemie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17966</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The (N,N-dialkylaminoethyl)cyclopentadienyl group 13 element dichlorides 3 and 4 of the type [(R2NCH2CH2)C5H4]MCl2 {M = Al, R = Me (3); M = Ga, R = i-Pr (4)} were prepared via salt elimination reactions of [(R2NCH2CH2)C5H4]K {R = Me (1), i-Pr (2)} with the respective group 13 element trichlorides. The reaction of 3 with LiAlH4 afforded the cyclopentadienylaluminum dihydride [(Me2NCH2CH2)C5H4]AlH2 (5) in nearly quantitative yield. Treatment of the organogallium dichlorides [(R2NCH2CH2)C5H4]GaCl2 {R = i-Pr (4), Me (6)} with LiAlH4 led via transmetalation to the organoaluminum dihydrides [(R2NCH2-CH2)C5H4]AlH2 {R =Me (5), i-Pr (7)} in good yields. The reaction of 6 with LiGaH4 resulted in the formation of the organogallium dihydride [(Me2NCH2CH2)C5H4]GaH2 (8). The novel compounds 3-5, 7, and 8 were characterized by elemental analysis, NMR spectroscopy, mass spectrometry, and X-ray crystallography. In the solid state and also in solution, all compounds feature a monomeric structure with an intramolecularly coordinated dialkylamino group. The coordinative and electronic saturation of the metal center in these compounds leads to a drastically decreased reactivity toward moisture and air in comparison to nondonor-stabilized Cp-group 13 element compounds. The dynamic behavior observed in solution is based on fast haptotropic shifts in a &quot;windshield-wiper&quot; type process. Sufficient volatility makes the organodihydrido compounds 5 and 8 suitable precursors for the deposition of aluminum and gallium, respectively, in the MOCVD process. Ex-situ characterization with sputter auger electron spectroscopy (SAES) provides information about the chemical composition of the aluminum and gallium layers. Irradiation of 5 and 8 in solution is followed by decomposition into the respective metal and into the hydrogen-functionalized ligand [C5H5(CH2CH2NMe2)].</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2000</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>ORGANOMETALLICS</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0276-7333</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1520-6041</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000086226600015</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1021/om990562v</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>19</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>7</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1292-1298</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Bensiek, S, Bangel, M, Neumann, B, Stammler, Hans-Georg, and Jutzi, Peter. 2000. “Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides”. &lt;em&gt;ORGANOMETALLICS&lt;/em&gt; 19 (7): 1292-1298.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Bensiek, M.  Bangel, B.  Neumann, H. - G.  Stammler, and P.  Jutzi, “Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides”, &lt;em&gt;ORGANOMETALLICS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2000&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;, 1292-1298.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Bensiek, S., Bangel, M., Neumann, B., Stammler, H. - G., &amp;amp; Jutzi, P. (2000). Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides. &lt;em&gt;ORGANOMETALLICS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;(7), 1292-1298.</apa>
<frontiers>Bensiek, S., Bangel, M., Neumann, B., Stammler, H. - G., and Jutzi, P. (2000). Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides. &lt;em&gt;ORGANOMETALLICS&lt;/em&gt; 19, 1292-1298.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Bensiek, S., Bangel, M., Neumann, B., Stammler, H. - G., &amp;amp; Jutzi, P. (2000). Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides. &lt;em&gt;ORGANOMETALLICS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;(7), 1292-1298.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>S. Bensiek, et al., “Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides”, &lt;em&gt;ORGANOMETALLICS&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 19, 2000,  pp. 1292-1298.</ieee>
<mla>Bensiek, S, Bangel, M, Neumann, B, Stammler, Hans-Georg, and Jutzi, Peter. “Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides”. &lt;em&gt;ORGANOMETALLICS&lt;/em&gt; 19.7 (2000): 1292-1298.</mla>
<lncs>Bensiek, S., Bangel, M., Neumann, B., Stammler, H.-G., Jutzi, P.: Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides. ORGANOMETALLICS. 19, 1292-1298 (2000).</lncs>
<wels>Bensiek, S.; Bangel, M.; Neumann, B.; Stammler, H. - G.; Jutzi, P. (2000): Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides &lt;em&gt;ORGANOMETALLICS&lt;/em&gt;,19:(7): 1292-1298.</wels>
<default>Bensiek S, Bangel M, Neumann B, Stammler H-G, Jutzi P (2000) &lt;br /&gt;ORGANOMETALLICS 19(7): 1292-1298.</default>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Bensiek, S., Bangel, M., Neumann, B., Stammler, H.-G. &amp;amp; Jutzi, P. (2000). Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides. &lt;em&gt;ORGANOMETALLICS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;(7), 1292-1298. AMER CHEMICAL SOC. doi:10.1021/om990562v.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Bensiek S, Bangel M, Neumann B, Stammler H-G, Jutzi P. Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides. &lt;em&gt;ORGANOMETALLICS&lt;/em&gt;. 2000;19(7):1292-1298.</ama>
<harvard1>Bensiek, S., et al., 2000. Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides. &lt;em&gt;ORGANOMETALLICS&lt;/em&gt;, 19(7), p 1292-1298.</harvard1>
<aps>S.  Bensiek, et al., Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides, ORGANOMETALLICS &lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt;, 1292-1298 (2000).</aps>
<bio1>Bensiek S, Bangel M, Neumann B, Stammler H-G, Jutzi P (2000) &lt;br /&gt;Synthesis, structure, and significance for MOCVD of intramolecularly base-stabilized monomeric cyclopentadienylaluminum and -gallium dihydrides.&lt;br /&gt;ORGANOMETALLICS 19(7): 1292-1298.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1620167</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:04:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-01-18T15:13:23Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1620167</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1620167</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
