<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">B</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Price</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">C</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dennison</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tschesche</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">19406</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">E</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Elliott</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Biochemie I</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17967</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The human neutrophil granule location of precursors of matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs), MMP-8 and -9, has been established, but that of the tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 (TIMP-1) has not. In this study, labeling for TIMP-1, pro-MMP-8, pro-MMP-9, and established granule marker proteins reveals that TIMP-1 is mainly located in distinct oval, electron translucent organelles, a little larger than azurophil granules. A lack of labeling for the fluid phase endocytic marker, bovine serum albumin-gold, the lysosome-associated membrane protein markers, and for glycosylphosphatidylinositol-linked proteins, which are enriched in secretory vesicles, indicates the nonendosomal, non-lysosomal, and non-secretory nature of this organelle. Density gradient cofractionation with the least dense, secretory population and some pleomorphism of the organelle suggest it is a &quot;vesicle&quot; rather than a &quot;granule&quot; population. Colocalization with pro-MMP-9 or pro-MMP-8, in minor subpopulations, suggests that TIMP-1 vesicle biogenesis occurs between metamyelocytic and terminal differentiation and before secretory vesicle synthesis. Pulse-chased IgG-coated latex beads and immunolabeling show that specific and azurophil granules fuse with the phagosome whereas TIMP-1 and pro-MMP-9-containing organelles do not. This suggests that these play no role in phagosomal destruction of IgG-opsonized bacteria. Separate localization and colocalization of these proteins may, however, facilitate fine regulation of extracellular proteolysis.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>AMER SOC BIOCHEMISTRY MOLECULAR BIOLOGY INC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2000</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0021-9258</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">10869345</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000089197100103</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>275</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>36</number></detail><extent unit="pages">28308-28315</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Price, B., Dennison, C., Tschesche, H., &amp;amp; Elliott, E. (2000). Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;275&lt;/em&gt;(36), 28308-28315.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>B. Price, et al., “Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 275, 2000,  pp. 28308-28315.</ieee>
<lncs>Price, B., Dennison, C., Tschesche, H., Elliott, E.: Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome. JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY. 275, 28308-28315 (2000).</lncs>
<mla>Price, B, Dennison, C, Tschesche, Harald, and Elliott, E. “Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 275.36 (2000): 28308-28315.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Price, B, Dennison, C, Tschesche, Harald, and Elliott, E. 2000. “Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 275 (36): 28308-28315.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<angewandte-chemie>B.  Price, C.  Dennison, H.  Tschesche, and E.  Elliott, “Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2000&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;275&lt;/em&gt;, 28308-28315.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Price, B., Dennison, C., Tschesche, H., &amp;amp; Elliott, E. (2000). Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;275&lt;/em&gt;(36), 28308-28315.</apa>
<frontiers>Price, B., Dennison, C., Tschesche, H., and Elliott, E. (2000). Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 275, 28308-28315.</frontiers>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Price, B., Dennison, C., Tschesche, H. &amp;amp; Elliott, E. (2000). Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;275&lt;/em&gt;(36), 28308-28315. AMER SOC BIOCHEMISTRY MOLECULAR BIOLOGY INC.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Price, B., et al., 2000. Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, 275(36), p 28308-28315.</harvard1>
<ama>Price B, Dennison C, Tschesche H, Elliott E. Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;. 2000;275(36):28308-28315.</ama>
<aps>B.  Price, et al., Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome, JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY &lt;strong&gt;275&lt;/strong&gt;, 28308-28315 (2000).</aps>
<bio1>Price B, Dennison C, Tschesche H, Elliott E (2000) &lt;br /&gt;Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome.&lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY 275(36): 28308-28315.</bio1>
<wels>Price, B.; Dennison, C.; Tschesche, H.; Elliott, E. (2000): Neutrophil tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinases-1 occurs in novel vesicles that do not fuse with the phagosome &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;,275:(36): 28308-28315.</wels>
<default>Price B, Dennison C, Tschesche H, Elliott E (2000) &lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY 275(36): 28308-28315.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1619122</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:04:15Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-08T12:23:57Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1619122</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1619122</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
