<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tauch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22082</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">F</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kassing</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörn</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kalinowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">147567</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pühler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21937</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The clinical isolate Corynebacterium xerosis M82B carries the 50-kb R-plasmid pTP10 that confers resistance to the antibiotics chloramphenicol, kanamycin, erythromycin, and tetracycline. A detailed restriction map of pTP10 was constructed by cloning and analyzing restriction fragments of pTP10 in Escherichia coli. The resistance determinants of pTP10 were located by studying the phenotype of the recombinant plasmids in E. coli and Corynebacterium glutamicum. Restriction patterns of fragments encoding the kanamycin and erythromycin resistances revealed striking similarity to the kanamycin resistance of transposon Tn903 and the erythromycin resistance on plasmid pNG2 from Corynebacterium diphtheriae, respectively. Expression of the resistance determinants in E. coli and C. glutamicum ATCC 13032 led to high resistance levels in both strains, with the exception of the tetracycline resistance gene, which could be expressed only in C. glutamicum. Furthermore, the erythromycin resistance gene was found to be located on a transposable element which is functional in C. glutamicum strains. (C) 1995 Academic Press, Inc.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS INC JNL-COMP SUBSCRIPTIONS</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1995</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PLASMID</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0147-619X</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">7568464</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1995RE68300002</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1006/plas.1995.1018</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>33</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>3</number></detail><extent unit="pages">168-179</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tauch, Andreas, Kassing, F, Kalinowski, Jörn, and Pühler, Alfred. 1995. “The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum”. &lt;em&gt;PLASMID&lt;/em&gt; 33 (3): 168-179.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Tauch, A., Kassing, F., Kalinowski, J., and Pühler, A. (1995). The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum. &lt;em&gt;PLASMID&lt;/em&gt; 33, 168-179.</frontiers>
<apa>Tauch, A., Kassing, F., Kalinowski, J., &amp;amp; Pühler, A. (1995). The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum. &lt;em&gt;PLASMID&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;33&lt;/em&gt;(3), 168-179.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Tauch, F.  Kassing, J.  Kalinowski, and A.  Pühler, “The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum”, &lt;em&gt;PLASMID&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1995&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;33&lt;/em&gt;, 168-179.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tauch, A., Kassing, F., Kalinowski, J., &amp;amp; Pühler, A. (1995). The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum. &lt;em&gt;PLASMID&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;33&lt;/em&gt;(3), 168-179.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs> Tauch, A., Kassing, F., Kalinowski, J., Pühler, A.: The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum. PLASMID. 33, 168-179 (1995).</lncs>
<mla>Tauch, Andreas, Kassing, F, Kalinowski, Jörn, and Pühler, Alfred. “The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum”. &lt;em&gt;PLASMID&lt;/em&gt; 33.3 (1995): 168-179.</mla>
<ieee> A. Tauch, et al., “The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum”, &lt;em&gt;PLASMID&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 33, 1995,  pp. 168-179.</ieee>
<default>Tauch A, Kassing F, Kalinowski J, Pühler A (1995) &lt;br /&gt;PLASMID 33(3): 168-179.</default>
<wels>Tauch, A.; Kassing, F.; Kalinowski, J.; Pühler, A. (1995): The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum &lt;em&gt;PLASMID&lt;/em&gt;,33:(3): 168-179.</wels>
<aps> A.  Tauch, et al., The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum, PLASMID &lt;strong&gt;33&lt;/strong&gt;, 168-179 (1995).</aps>
<bio1>Tauch A, Kassing F, Kalinowski J, Pühler A (1995) &lt;br /&gt;The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum.&lt;br /&gt;PLASMID 33(3): 168-179.</bio1>
<harvard1>Tauch, A., et al., 1995. The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum. &lt;em&gt;PLASMID&lt;/em&gt;, 33(3), p 168-179.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tauch, A., Kassing, F., Kalinowski, J. &amp;amp; Pühler, A. (1995). The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum. &lt;em&gt;PLASMID&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;33&lt;/em&gt;(3), 168-179. ACADEMIC PRESS INC JNL-COMP SUBSCRIPTIONS. doi:10.1006/plas.1995.1018.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Tauch A, Kassing F, Kalinowski J, Pühler A. The erythromycin resistance gene of the Corynebacterium xerosis R-plasmid pTP10 also carrying chloramphenicol, kanamycin, and tetracycline resistances is capable of transposition in Corynebacterium glutamicum. &lt;em&gt;PLASMID&lt;/em&gt;. 1995;33(3):168-179.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1640693</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:15:55Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-09-14T06:40:37Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1640693</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1640693</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
