<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christiane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Werner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22053</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7676-9057</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stephan</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Unger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">37001512</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">João Santos</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pereira</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jaleh</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ghashghaie</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Cristina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Máguas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Todd E.</namePart><namePart type="family">Dawson</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Rolf T.W.</namePart><namePart type="family">Siegwolf</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2685201</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>Elsevier Academic Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-0-12-373627-7</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/S1936-7961(07)01013-5</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">193-210</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Werner, C.; Unger, S.; Pereira, J. S.; Ghashghaie, J.; Máguas, C. (2007): Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes. In: Todd E. Dawson; Rolf T.W. Siegwolf (Hrsg.):  Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change . San Diego: Elsevier Academic Press. (Terrestrial ecology series, ).  S. 193-210.</wels>
<default>Werner C, Unger S, Pereira JS, Ghashghaie J, Máguas C (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change . Dawson TE, Siegwolf RTW (Eds); Terrestrial ecology series, . San Diego: Elsevier Academic Press:  193-210.</default>
<harvard1>Werner, C., et al., 2007. Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes. In T. E.  Dawson &amp;amp; R. T. W.  Siegwolf, eds. &lt;em&gt;Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change &lt;/em&gt;. Terrestrial ecology series.  San Diego: Elsevier Academic Press, pp. 193-210.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Werner, C., Unger, S., Pereira, J.S., Ghashghaie, J. &amp;amp; Máguas, C. (2007). Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes (Terrestrial ecology series). &lt;em&gt;Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change &lt;/em&gt; (S. 193-210). San Diego: Elsevier Academic Press. doi:10.1016/S1936-7961(07)01013-5.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Werner C, Unger S, Pereira JS, Ghashghaie J, Máguas C. Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes. In: Dawson TE, Siegwolf RTW, eds. &lt;em&gt;Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change &lt;/em&gt;. Terrestrial ecology series. San Diego: Elsevier Academic Press;  2007: 193-210.</ama>
<aps>C.  Werner, et al., Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes, in &lt;em&gt;Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change &lt;/em&gt;, edited by T. E.  Dawson and R. T. W.  Siegwolf, Terrestrial ecology series (Elsevier Academic Press, San Diego, 2007), p. 193-210.</aps>
<bio1>Werner C, Unger S, Pereira JS, Ghashghaie J, Máguas C (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change . Dawson TE, Siegwolf RTW (Eds); Terrestrial ecology series,  San Diego: Elsevier Academic Press:  193-210.</bio1>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Werner, Christiane, Unger, Stephan, Pereira, João Santos, Ghashghaie, Jaleh, and Máguas, Cristina. 2007. “Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes”. In &lt;em&gt;Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change &lt;/em&gt;, ed. Todd E. Dawson and Rolf T.W. Siegwolf, 193-210. Terrestrial ecology series. San Diego: Elsevier Academic Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Werner, C., Unger, S., Pereira, J. S., Ghashghaie, J., &amp;amp; Máguas, C. (2007). Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes. In T. E.  Dawson &amp;amp; R. T. W.  Siegwolf (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Terrestrial ecology series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change &lt;/em&gt; (pp. 193-210). San Diego: Elsevier Academic Press.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Werner, S.  Unger, J. S.  Pereira, J.  Ghashghaie, and C.  Máguas, in &lt;em&gt;Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change &lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: T.E. Dawson, R.T.W. Siegwolf), Elsevier Academic Press, San Diego, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 193-210.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Werner, C., Unger, S., Pereira, J. S., Ghashghaie, J., and Máguas, C. (2007). “Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes” in &lt;em&gt;Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change &lt;/em&gt;, ed. T. E.  Dawson and R. T. W.  Siegwolf Terrestrial ecology series (San Diego: Elsevier Academic Press), 193-210.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Werner, C., Unger, S., Pereira, J. S., Ghashghaie, J., &amp;amp; Máguas, C. (2007). Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes. In T. E.  Dawson &amp;amp; R. T. W.  Siegwolf (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Terrestrial ecology series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;. Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change &lt;/em&gt; (pp. 193-210). San Diego: Elsevier Academic Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>C. Werner, et al., “Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes”, &lt;em&gt;Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change &lt;/em&gt;, T.E. Dawson and R.T.W. Siegwolf, eds., Terrestrial ecology series,  San Diego: Elsevier Academic Press, 2007,  pp.193-210.</ieee>
<mla>Werner, Christiane, Unger, Stephan, Pereira, João Santos, Ghashghaie, Jaleh, and Máguas, Cristina. “Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes”. &lt;em&gt;Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change &lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Todd E. Dawson and Rolf T.W. Siegwolf. San Diego: Elsevier Academic Press, 2007. Terrestrial ecology series. 193-210.</mla>
<lncs>Werner, C., Unger, S., Pereira, J.S., Ghashghaie, J., Máguas, C.: Temporal dynamics in δ13C of ecosystem respiration in response to environmental changes. In: Dawson, T.E. and Siegwolf, R.T.W. (eds.) Stable isotopes as indicators of ecological change . Terrestrial ecology series. p. 193-210. Elsevier Academic Press, San Diego (2007).</lncs>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1925922</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-12-03T14:05:22Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-01-18T13:52:04Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1925922</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1925922</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
