<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kanak</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stobiecki</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">O</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schebaum</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Günter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Reiss</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">40207</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0918-5940</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bruckl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Research Group  G. Reiss</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">33079602</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>AG Dünne Schichten &amp; Physik der Nanostrukturen</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">28536538</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">In this study, we report the relationship between interface roughness, texture and the exchange bias and the interlayer-Neel coupling fields of the spin-valve magnetic tunnel junction (SV-MTJ). SV-MTJs with the structure: Si(100)/SiO2/buffer/IrMn/CoFeB/AlOx/NiFe/Ta were deposited on two buffers: Cu and Ta/Cu/Ta/Cu, and next the samples were annealed in vacuum and in a magnetic field. XRD analysis reveals that the texture degree of MTJ with Cu buffer is significantly lower than that of the sample with Ta/Cu/Ta/Cu buffer. The enhancement of IrMn and CoFeB texture leads to a higher amplitude of roughness and an increase of exchange bias and Neel coupling fields. The comparison of junctions with CoFe and CoFeB bottom electrodes shows that addition of 5% B in a CoFe layer makes the surface of the pinned layer smoother. This leads to a lower Neel coupling field, which is desirable for application of MTJ in MRAM technology. (c) 2006 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0370-1972</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000234925800037</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/pssb.200562456</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>243</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">197-201</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Kanak, T.  Stobiecki, O.  Schebaum, G.  Reiss, and H.  Bruckl, in &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, Wiley-V C H Verlag Gmbh, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 197-201.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Kanak, J., Stobiecki, T., Schebaum, O., Reiss, G., &amp;amp; Bruckl, H. (2006). Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode. &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;243&lt;/em&gt;(1), 197-201.</apa>
<frontiers>Kanak, J., Stobiecki, T., Schebaum, O., Reiss, G., and Bruckl, H. (2006). “Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode” in &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 243, (WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH), 197-201.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kanak, J, Stobiecki, T, Schebaum, O, Reiss, Günter, and Bruckl, H. 2006. “Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode”. In &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, 243:197-201. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee>J. Kanak, et al., “Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode”, &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 243, WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH, 2006,  pp.197-201.</ieee>
<mla>Kanak, J, Stobiecki, T, Schebaum, O, Reiss, Günter, and Bruckl, H. “Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode”. &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH, 2006.Vol. 243. 197-201.</mla>
<lncs>Kanak, J., Stobiecki, T., Schebaum, O., Reiss, G., Bruckl, H.: Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode. PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS. 243, p. 197-201. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH (2006).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kanak, J., Stobiecki, T., Schebaum, O., Reiss, G., &amp;amp; Bruckl, H. (2006). Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode. &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;243&lt;/em&gt;(1), 197-201.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Kanak, J.; Stobiecki, T.; Schebaum, O.; Reiss, G.; Bruckl, H. (2006): Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode. In: PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH. (243).  S. 197-201.</wels>
<default>Kanak J, Stobiecki T, Schebaum O, Reiss G, Bruckl H (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS. 243. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH:  197-201.</default>
<harvard1>Kanak, J., et al., 2006. Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode. In &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;. no.243  WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH, pp. 197-201.</harvard1>
<ama>Kanak J, Stobiecki T, Schebaum O, Reiss G, Bruckl H. Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode. In:  &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 243. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH;  2006: 197-201.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kanak, J., Stobiecki, T., Schebaum, O., Reiss, G. &amp;amp; Bruckl, H. (2006). Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode. &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt; (S. 197-201). WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH. doi:10.1002/pssb.200562456.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<aps>J.  Kanak, et al., Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode, in &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;243&lt;/strong&gt; (WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH, 2006), p. 197-201.</aps>
<bio1>Kanak J, Stobiecki T, Schebaum O, Reiss G, Bruckl H (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Microstructure and exchange coupling parameters of MTJ with CoFeB bottom electrode. &lt;br /&gt;In:  PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS. 243. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH:  197-201.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1600804</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:31:26Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-12-16T09:52:02Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1600804</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1600804</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
