<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">R</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sepper</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">YT</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Konttinen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">L</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Buo</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">KK</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eklund</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lauhio</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sorsa</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tschesche</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">19406</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">AO</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Aasen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sillastu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Biochemie I</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17967</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We attempted to study the possible relationships between neutrophiltype procollagenase/pro-matrix metalloproteinase (MMP-8) and the serine proteinases plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis. The presence of the plasmin/piasminogen system and plasmin-, cathepsin G-and tryptase-like activities were compared to the activity of endogenously activated MMP-8 in bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL) fluid in 38 bronchiectasis patients and in 14 healthy controls by means of immunohistochemistry, Western-blot and substratebased functional assays, In contrast to cathepsin G-and tryptase-like activities, the plasmin/plasminogen activator system in BAL fluid was observed to have a relatively weak activation stage and no correlation with disease severity, Neither plasmin-like activities nor concentrations of plasminogen activators from the bronchiectatic patients differed significantly from the values of health. controls, Immunolocation of plasminogen activator inhibitor-1 showed a marked, but not significant, increase in bronchiectatic lung as compared to controls, In contrast to cathepsin G-and tryptase-like activities,,vith their strong and significant correlation with endogenously activated collagenase (r=0.9; p=0.0001; and r=0.6; p=0.03, respectively), no correlations were observed between plasmin-like and endogenously activated collagenase(r=0.3; p=0.2) in bronchiectasis. These findings suggest that cathepsin G-and tryptase-like activities may act as potent pro-matrix metalloproteinase-8 activators in patients with bronrhiectasis, whereas the plasminogen activator/plasmin cascade was shown to be down-regulated.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>MUNKSGAARD INT PUBL LTD</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1997</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>bronchiectasis</topic><topic>mast cell tryptase</topic><topic>plasminogen system</topic><topic>procollagenase/proMMP-8</topic><topic>cathepsin G</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0903-1936</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">0000-0000</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">9493662</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000071854700020</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1183/09031936.97.10122788</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>10</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>12</number></detail><extent unit="pages">2788-2793</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<aps>R.  Sepper, et al., Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo, EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL &lt;strong&gt;10&lt;/strong&gt;, 2788-2793 (1997).</aps>
<bio1>Sepper R, Konttinen YT, Buo L, Eklund KK, Lauhio A, Sorsa T, Tschesche H, Aasen AO, Sillastu H (1997) &lt;br /&gt;Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo.&lt;br /&gt;EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL 10(12): 2788-2793.</bio1>
<ama>Sepper R, Konttinen YT, Buo L, et al. Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;. 1997;10(12):2788-2793.</ama>
<harvard1>Sepper, R., et al., 1997. Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 10(12), p 2788-2793.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Sepper, R., Konttinen, Y.T., Buo, L., Eklund, K.K., Lauhio, A., Sorsa, T., Tschesche, H., Aasen, A.O. &amp;amp; Sillastu, H. (1997). Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(12), 2788-2793. MUNKSGAARD INT PUBL LTD. doi:10.1183/09031936.97.10122788.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Sepper R, Konttinen YT, Buo L, Eklund KK, Lauhio A, Sorsa T, Tschesche H, Aasen AO, Sillastu H (1997) &lt;br /&gt;EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL 10(12): 2788-2793.</default>
<wels>Sepper, R.; Konttinen, Y. T.; Buo, L.; Eklund, K. K.; Lauhio, A.; Sorsa, T.; Tschesche, H.; Aasen, A. O.; Sillastu, H. (1997): Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;,10:(12): 2788-2793.</wels>
<lncs>Sepper, R., Konttinen, Y.T., Buo, L., Eklund, K.K., Lauhio, A., Sorsa, T., Tschesche, H., Aasen, A.O., Sillastu, H.: Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo. EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL. 10, 2788-2793 (1997).</lncs>
<mla>Sepper, R, Konttinen, YT, Buo, L, Eklund, KK, Lauhio, A, Sorsa, T, Tschesche, Harald, Aasen, AO, and Sillastu, H. “Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo”. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt; 10.12 (1997): 2788-2793.</mla>
<ieee>R. Sepper, et al., “Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo”, &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 10, 1997,  pp. 2788-2793.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Sepper, R., Konttinen, Y. T., Buo, L., Eklund, K. K., Lauhio, A., Sorsa, T., Tschesche, H., et al. (1997). Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(12), 2788-2793.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Sepper, R., Konttinen, Y. T., Buo, L., Eklund, K. K., Lauhio, A., Sorsa, T., Tschesche, H., Aasen, A. O., and Sillastu, H. (1997). Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt; 10, 2788-2793.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Sepper, Y. T.  Konttinen, L.  Buo, K. K.  Eklund, A.  Lauhio, T.  Sorsa, H.  Tschesche, A. O.  Aasen, and H.  Sillastu, “Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo”, &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1997&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;, 2788-2793.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Sepper, R., Konttinen, Y. T., Buo, L., Eklund, K. K., Lauhio, A., Sorsa, T., Tschesche, H., et al. (1997). Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;10&lt;/em&gt;(12), 2788-2793.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Sepper, R, Konttinen, YT, Buo, L, Eklund, KK, Lauhio, A, Sorsa, T, Tschesche, Harald, Aasen, AO, and Sillastu, H. 1997. “Potentiative effects of neutral proteinases in an inflamed lung: Relationship of neutrophil procollagenase (proMMP-8) to plasmin, cathepsin G and tryptase in bronchiectasis in vivo”. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN RESPIRATORY JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt; 10 (12): 2788-2793.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1626404</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:21:59Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-08T12:26:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1626404</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1626404</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
