<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Katrin</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Golsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">16281346</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">H.-P.</namePart><namePart type="family">Blossfeld</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">M.</namePart><namePart type="family">Mills</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">F.</namePart><namePart type="family">Bernardi</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Soziologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10030</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Arbeitsbereich 5 - Sozialstruktur und soziale Ungleichheit</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">5656055</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>Edward Elgar</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison</title></titleInfo>
<part><extent unit="pages">299-327</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Golsch, Katrin. 2006. “Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity”. In &lt;em&gt;Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison&lt;/em&gt;, ed. H.-P. Blossfeld, M. Mills, and F. Bernardi, 299-327. Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Golsch, K. (2006). “Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity” in &lt;em&gt;Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison&lt;/em&gt;, ed. H. - P.  Blossfeld, M.  Mills, and F.  Bernardi (Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar), 299-327.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>K.  Golsch, in &lt;em&gt;Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: H.-P. Blossfeld, M. Mills, F. Bernardi), Edward Elgar, Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 299-327.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Golsch, K. (2006). Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity. In H. - P.  Blossfeld, M.  Mills, &amp;amp; F.  Bernardi (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 299-327). Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar.</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Golsch, K. (2006). Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity. In H. - P.  Blossfeld, M.  Mills, &amp;amp; F.  Bernardi (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 299-327). Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Golsch, Katrin. “Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity”. &lt;em&gt;Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. H.-P. Blossfeld, M. Mills, and F. Bernardi. Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar, 2006. 299-327.</mla>
<lncs>Golsch, K.: Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity. In: Blossfeld, H.-P., Mills, M., and Bernardi, F. (eds.) Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison. p. 299-327. Edward Elgar, Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA (2006).</lncs>
<ieee>K. Golsch, “Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity”, &lt;em&gt;Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison&lt;/em&gt;, H.-P. Blossfeld, M. Mills, and F. Bernardi, eds.,  Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar, 2006,  pp.299-327.</ieee>
<default>Golsch K (2006)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison. Blossfeld H-P, Mills M, Bernardi F (Eds);Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar:  299-327.</default>
<wels>Golsch, K. (2006): Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity. In: H.-P. Blossfeld; M. Mills; F. Bernardi (Hrsg.):  Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison. Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar.  S. 299-327.</wels>
<aps>K.  Golsch, Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity, in &lt;em&gt;Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison&lt;/em&gt;, edited by H. - P.  Blossfeld, et al. (Edward Elgar, Cheltenham, Uk Und Northampton, Ma, Usa, 2006), p. 299-327.</aps>
<bio1>Golsch K (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison. Blossfeld H-P, Mills M, Bernardi F (Eds); Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar:  299-327.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Golsch, K. (2006). Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity. &lt;em&gt;Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison&lt;/em&gt; (S. 299-327). Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Golsch, K., 2006. Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity. In H. - P.  Blossfeld, M.  Mills, &amp;amp; F.  Bernardi, eds. &lt;em&gt;Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison&lt;/em&gt;.  Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar, pp. 299-327.</harvard1>
<ama>Golsch K. Men’s labor market mobility in Britain. Globalization, labor market flexibility, and job insecurity. In: Blossfeld H-P, Mills M, Bernardi F, eds. &lt;em&gt;Globalization, Uncertainty and Men’s Careers: An International Comparison&lt;/em&gt;. Cheltenham, UK und Northampton, MA, USA: Edward Elgar;  2006: 299-327.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1857423</recordIdentifier><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-11-21T09:28:38Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1857423</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1857423</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
