<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Coles</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Diercks</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">B</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Muehlenweg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">S</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bartsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">V</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Zolzer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tschesche</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">19406</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kessler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Biochemie I</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17967</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin (HNGAL) is a member of the lipocalin family of extracellular proteins that function as transporters of small, hydrophobic molecules. HNGAL, a component of human blood granulocytes, binds bacterially derived formyl peptides that act as chemotactic agents and induce leukocyte granule discharge. HNGAL also forms a complex with the proenzyme form of matrix metalloproteinase-9 (pro-MMP-9, or progelatinase B) via an intermolecular disulphide bridge. This association allows the subsequent formation of ternary and quaternary metalloproteinase/inhibitor complexes that vary greatly in their metalloproteinase activities. The structure and dynamics of apo-HNGAL have been determined by NMR spectroscopy. Simulated annealing calculations yielded a set of 20 convergent structures with an average backbone RMSD from mean coordinate positions of 0.79(+/-0.13) Angstrom over secondary structure elements. The overall rotational correlation time (13.3 ns) derived from N-15 relaxation data is consistent with a monomeric protein of the size of HNGAL (179 residues) under the experimental conditions (1.4 mM protein, pH 6.0, 24.5 degrees C). The structure features an eight stranded antiparallel beta-barrel, typical of the lipocalin family. One end of the barrel is open, providing access to the binding site within the barrel cavity, while the other is closed by a short 3(10)-helix. The free cysteine residue required for association with pro-MMP-9 lies in an inter-strand loop at the closed end of the barrel. The structure provides a detailed model of the ligand-binding site and has led to the proposal of a site for pro-MMP-9 association. Dynamic data correlate well with structural features, which has allowed us to investigate a mechanism by which a cell-surface receptor might distinguish between apo and holo-HNGAL through conformational changes at the open end of the barrel. (C) 1999 Academic Press.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS LTD</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1999</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>protein structure</topic><topic>NMR</topic><topic>human neutrophil</topic><topic>gelatinase-associated lipocalin</topic><topic>protein-protein interactions</topic><topic>protein dynamics</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0022-2836</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">10339412</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000080818700013</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1006/jmbi.1999.2755</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>289</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">139-157</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ama>Coles M, Diercks T, Muehlenweg B, et al. The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. 1999;289(1):139-157.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Coles, M., Diercks, T., Muehlenweg, B., Bartsch, S., Zolzer, V., Tschesche, H. &amp;amp; Kessler, H. (1999). The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;289&lt;/em&gt;(1), 139-157. ACADEMIC PRESS LTD. doi:10.1006/jmbi.1999.2755.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Coles, M., et al., 1999. The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 289(1), p 139-157.</harvard1>
<aps>M.  Coles, et al., The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin, JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY &lt;strong&gt;289&lt;/strong&gt;, 139-157 (1999).</aps>
<bio1>Coles M, Diercks T, Muehlenweg B, Bartsch S, Zolzer V, Tschesche H, Kessler H (1999) &lt;br /&gt;The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin.&lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY 289(1): 139-157.</bio1>
<wels>Coles, M.; Diercks, T.; Muehlenweg, B.; Bartsch, S.; Zolzer, V.; Tschesche, H.; Kessler, H. (1999): The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,289:(1): 139-157.</wels>
<default>Coles M, Diercks T, Muehlenweg B, Bartsch S, Zolzer V, Tschesche H, Kessler H (1999) &lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY 289(1): 139-157.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Coles, M., Diercks, T., Muehlenweg, B., Bartsch, S., Zolzer, V., Tschesche, H., &amp;amp; Kessler, H. (1999). The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;289&lt;/em&gt;(1), 139-157.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>M. Coles, et al., “The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 289, 1999,  pp. 139-157.</ieee>
<lncs>Coles, M., Diercks, T., Muehlenweg, B., Bartsch, S., Zolzer, V., Tschesche, H., Kessler, H.: The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin. JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY. 289, 139-157 (1999).</lncs>
<mla>Coles, M, Diercks, T, Muehlenweg, B, Bartsch, S, Zolzer, V, Tschesche, Harald, and Kessler, H. “The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 289.1 (1999): 139-157.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Coles, M, Diercks, T, Muehlenweg, B, Bartsch, S, Zolzer, V, Tschesche, Harald, and Kessler, H. 1999. “The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 289 (1): 139-157.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Coles, T.  Diercks, B.  Muehlenweg, S.  Bartsch, V.  Zolzer, H.  Tschesche, and H.  Kessler, “The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1999&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;289&lt;/em&gt;, 139-157.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Coles, M., Diercks, T., Muehlenweg, B., Bartsch, S., Zolzer, V., Tschesche, H., &amp;amp; Kessler, H. (1999). The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;289&lt;/em&gt;(1), 139-157.</apa>
<frontiers>Coles, M., Diercks, T., Muehlenweg, B., Bartsch, S., Zolzer, V., Tschesche, H., and Kessler, H. (1999). The solution structure and dynamics of human neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 289, 139-157.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1622839</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:05:51Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-08T12:47:03Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1622839</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1622839</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
