<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Matthias</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Weigelt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">177202</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Abteilung Sportwissenschaft</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10027</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Structural constraints affect the coordination of bimanual movements in ways that have been taken to suggest that the specification of different movement amplitudes is subject to strong intermanual interference effects. Most experiments taken to support this notion, however, confounded variations of movement amplitudes with symmetry in starting locations and variations in target location. The present experiment was designed to further investigate the relative influence of the parameters starting location, movement amplitude, and target location on bimanual movement coordination. Participants performed simultaneous reaching movements with the left and right hand from same and different starting locations to same and different target locations. On each trial, two movements could match on none, one, or all of the parameters. We assessed the influence of each parameter by comparing conditions in which only a single parameter matched between the two hands with conditions in which all parameters differed. The reaction-time data revealed some challenging results for previous studies: (1) same starting locations significantly delayed movement initiation; (2) specifying movement amplitudes had virtually no effect on movement initiation, whereas (3) selecting same target locations significantly benefited the bimanual responses. These findings cannot be taken to support the notion that amplitude specification affects the initiation of bimanual movements. Rather, they support the notion that the initial starting locations of the two hands and the selection of target locations decide about the ease with which we perform bimanual reaching movements. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>motor control</topic><topic>reaching movements</topic><topic>intermanual</topic><topic>bimanual coordination</topic><topic>interference</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Human Movement Science</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0167-9457</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">17343946</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000245957100004</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/j.humov.2007.01.010</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>26</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">212-225</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Weigelt M (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Human Movement Science 26(2): 212-225.</default>
<wels>Weigelt, M. (2007): Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations &lt;em&gt;Human Movement Science&lt;/em&gt;,26:(2): 212-225.</wels>
<aps>M.  Weigelt, Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations, Human Movement Science &lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt;, 212-225 (2007).</aps>
<bio1>Weigelt M (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations.&lt;br /&gt;Human Movement Science 26(2): 212-225.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Weigelt, M. (2007). Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations. &lt;em&gt;Human Movement Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;26&lt;/em&gt;(2), 212-225. ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV. doi:10.1016/j.humov.2007.01.010.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Weigelt, M., 2007. Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations. &lt;em&gt;Human Movement Science&lt;/em&gt;, 26(2), p 212-225.</harvard1>
<ama>Weigelt M. Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations. &lt;em&gt;Human Movement Science&lt;/em&gt;. 2007;26(2):212-225.</ama>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Weigelt, Matthias. 2007. “Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations”. &lt;em&gt;Human Movement Science&lt;/em&gt; 26 (2): 212-225.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Weigelt, M. (2007). Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations. &lt;em&gt;Human Movement Science&lt;/em&gt; 26, 212-225.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Weigelt, “Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations”, &lt;em&gt;Human Movement Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;26&lt;/em&gt;, 212-225.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Weigelt, M. (2007). Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations. &lt;em&gt;Human Movement Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;26&lt;/em&gt;(2), 212-225.</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Weigelt, M. (2007). Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations. &lt;em&gt;Human Movement Science&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;26&lt;/em&gt;(2), 212-225.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs>Weigelt, M.: Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations. Human Movement Science. 26, 212-225 (2007).</lncs>
<mla>Weigelt, Matthias. “Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations”. &lt;em&gt;Human Movement Science&lt;/em&gt; 26.2 (2007): 212-225.</mla>
<ieee>M. Weigelt, “Re-examining structural constraints on the initiation of bimanual movements: The role of starting locations, movement amplitudes, and target locations”, &lt;em&gt;Human Movement Science&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 26, 2007,  pp. 212-225.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1594112</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:16:12Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-05-31T09:11:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1594112</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1594112</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
