<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs</title></titleInfo>

  
  
<titleInfo type="alternative">
  
  <title>Representations of collective identities and political Islam - Observed in the mass gatherings of the Turkish Islamist group Milli Gorus</title>
</titleInfo>

<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Levent</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tezcan</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">93388</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10058</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The article deals with expressions of collective identities as illustrated by Milli Gorus, a Turkish Islamist group active in Europe. The political mission is a central part of Islamism&apos;s idea of salvation, with mass gatherings gaining a status close to genuinely religious rituals. The analysis focuses, on the one hand, on the expressions of political mass piety. On the other hand, it examines the discoursive links established between various elements derived from the fund of national und religious narratives, which provide the arena in which collective identities can emerge. However, the events of September 11 have considerably hampered the previous strategies of representation. Finally, the article discusses the strategies used by Milli Gorus to establish itself as a political voice in German political discourse. It demonstrates that there remains an unbridgeable gap between two contradictory self-images: between, on the one hand, the organisation&apos;s self-description oriented towards Turkish society and based on the concept of salvation, which cannot be communicated to the Western public, and, on the other hand, its public self-presentation as a kind of charity organisation.</abstract>

<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2002</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">ger</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Soziale Welt</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0038-6073</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000180277700003</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>53</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>3</number></detail><extent unit="pages">303-324</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Tezcan, L. (2002). Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs. &lt;em&gt;Soziale Welt&lt;/em&gt; 53, 303-324.</frontiers>
<apa>Tezcan, L. (2002). Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs. &lt;em&gt;Soziale Welt&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;53&lt;/em&gt;(3), 303-324.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>L.  Tezcan, “Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs”, &lt;em&gt;Soziale Welt&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;53&lt;/em&gt;, 303-324.</angewandte-chemie>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tezcan, Levent. 2002. “Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs”. &lt;em&gt;Soziale Welt&lt;/em&gt; 53 (3): 303-324.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs> Tezcan, L.: Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs. Soziale Welt. 53, 303-324 (2002).</lncs>
<mla>Tezcan, Levent. “Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs”. &lt;em&gt;Soziale Welt&lt;/em&gt; 53.3 (2002): 303-324.</mla>
<ieee> L. Tezcan, “Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs”, &lt;em&gt;Soziale Welt&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 53, 2002,  pp. 303-324.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tezcan, L. (2002). Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs. &lt;em&gt;Soziale Welt&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;53&lt;/em&gt;(3), 303-324.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Tezcan L (2002) &lt;br /&gt;Soziale Welt 53(3): 303-324.</default>
<wels>Tezcan, L. (2002): Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs &lt;em&gt;Soziale Welt&lt;/em&gt;,53:(3): 303-324.</wels>
<bio1>Tezcan L (2002) &lt;br /&gt;Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs.&lt;br /&gt;Soziale Welt 53(3): 303-324.</bio1>
<aps> L.  Tezcan, Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs, Soziale Welt &lt;strong&gt;53&lt;/strong&gt;, 303-324 (2002).</aps>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tezcan, L. (2002). Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs. &lt;em&gt;Soziale Welt&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;53&lt;/em&gt;(3), 303-324.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Tezcan, L., 2002. Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs. &lt;em&gt;Soziale Welt&lt;/em&gt;, 53(3), p 303-324.</harvard1>
<ama>Tezcan L. Inszenierungen kollektiver Identität, Artikulationen des politischen Islam – beobachtet auf den Massenversammlungen der türkisch-islamistischen Gruppe Milli Görüs. &lt;em&gt;Soziale Welt&lt;/em&gt;. 2002;53(3):303-324.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1861190</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-09-21T13:18:00Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-09-21T13:18:00Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1861190</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1861190</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
