<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Johannes</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Müthing</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">94612</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">R</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Spanbroek</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">PeterKatalinic</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">FG</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hanisch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">C</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hanski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hasegawa</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">F</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Unland</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lehmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tschesche</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">19406</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Egge</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Biochemie I</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17967</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Technische Fakultät</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated neolacto-series gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from normal human granulocytes is described. Gangliosides were purified by consecutive use of anion exchange HPLC on Fractogel TMAE-650(S), adsorption and reversed phase HPLC on Nucleosil 50-7 and Nucleosil 7C(18) columns, respectively, TLC immunostaining with carbohydrate specific monoclonal antibodies, fast atom bombardment-mass spectrometry (FAB-MS) of the permethylated derivatives and gas chromatography-electron impact mass spectrometry (GC-EIMS) of partially methylated alditol acetates were used for structure elucidations, One ganglioside was identified as sialyl Lewis(x) antigen with nLcOse(6)Cer core, Neu5-Ac alpha 2-3Gal beta 1-4(Fuc alpha 1-3)GlcNAc beta 1-3Gal beta 1-4Glc NAc beta 1-3Gal beta 1-4Glc beta 1-1Cer. Furthermore, monosialylated ceramide: deca-, undeca-, dodeca- and tridecasaccharides with three (nLcOse(8)Cer) and four (nLcOse(10)Cer) linear lactosaminyl repeats were identified, carrying one to three fucoses. The ceramide portions were found to contain C-18 sphingosine and predominantly C-16:0 fatty acids, All monosialogangliosides were homogenous concerning their terminal alpha 2-3Neu5Ac-sialylation, but different in their fucosylation status, Beside VI(3)Neu5Ac, V(3)Fuc-nLcOse(6)Cer, in two of the fucosylated polylactosaminyl ganglioside fractions the sialyl Lewis(x) epitope was found, whereas five species expressed the terminal VIM-2 motif. The role of protein linked sialyl Lewis(x) epitope of human granulocytes as a ligand for endothelial leukocyte adhesion molecule-1 (ELAM-1; E-selectin) and platelet activation-dependent granule external membrane protein (PADGEM; P-selectin) is well documented, However, the involvement of endothelial cells E- and/or P-selectin mediated cell-cell adhesion via lipid bound sialyl Lewis(x) and/or VIM-2 epitopes on human granulocytes has to be proved in further investigations.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>OXFORD UNIV PRESS UNITED KINGDOM</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1996</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>sialyl Le(x)</topic><topic>leukocytes</topic><topic>glycosphingolipids</topic><topic>cell adhesion</topic><topic>antibodies</topic><topic>monoclonal</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>GLYCOBIOLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0959-6658</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1460-2423</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">8727787</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1996UF68400005</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1093/glycob/6.2.147</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>6</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">147-156</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<wels>Müthing, J.; Spanbroek, R.; PeterKatalinic, J.; Hanisch, F. G.; Hanski, C.; Hasegawa, A.; Unland, F.; Lehmann, J.; Tschesche, H.; Egge, H. (1996): Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes &lt;em&gt;GLYCOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,6:(2): 147-156.</wels>
<default>Müthing J, Spanbroek R, PeterKatalinic J, Hanisch FG, Hanski C, Hasegawa A, Unland F, Lehmann J, Tschesche H, Egge H (1996) &lt;br /&gt;GLYCOBIOLOGY 6(2): 147-156.</default>
<ama>Müthing J, Spanbroek R, PeterKatalinic J, et al. Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes. &lt;em&gt;GLYCOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. 1996;6(2):147-156.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Müthing, J., Spanbroek, R., PeterKatalinic, J., Hanisch, F.G., Hanski, C., Hasegawa, A., Unland, F., Lehmann, J., Tschesche, H. &amp;amp; Egge, H. (1996). Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes. &lt;em&gt;GLYCOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(2), 147-156. OXFORD UNIV PRESS UNITED KINGDOM. doi:10.1093/glycob/6.2.147.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Müthing, J., et al., 1996. Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes. &lt;em&gt;GLYCOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 6(2), p 147-156.</harvard1>
<bio1>Müthing J, Spanbroek R, PeterKatalinic J, Hanisch FG, Hanski C, Hasegawa A, Unland F, Lehmann J, Tschesche H, Egge H (1996) &lt;br /&gt;Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes.&lt;br /&gt;GLYCOBIOLOGY 6(2): 147-156.</bio1>
<aps>J.  Müthing, et al., Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes, GLYCOBIOLOGY &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt;, 147-156 (1996).</aps>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Müthing, R.  Spanbroek, J.  PeterKatalinic, F. G.  Hanisch, C.  Hanski, A.  Hasegawa, F.  Unland, J.  Lehmann, H.  Tschesche, and H.  Egge, “Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes”, &lt;em&gt;GLYCOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1996&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;, 147-156.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Müthing, J., Spanbroek, R., PeterKatalinic, J., Hanisch, F. G., Hanski, C., Hasegawa, A., Unland, F., et al. (1996). Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes. &lt;em&gt;GLYCOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(2), 147-156.</apa>
<frontiers>Müthing, J., Spanbroek, R., PeterKatalinic, J., Hanisch, F. G., Hanski, C., Hasegawa, A., Unland, F., Lehmann, J., Tschesche, H., and Egge, H. (1996). Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes. &lt;em&gt;GLYCOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 6, 147-156.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Müthing, Johannes, Spanbroek, R, PeterKatalinic, J, Hanisch, FG, Hanski, C, Hasegawa, A, Unland, F, Lehmann, J, Tschesche, Harald, and Egge, H. 1996. “Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes”. &lt;em&gt;GLYCOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 6 (2): 147-156.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee>J. Müthing, et al., “Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes”, &lt;em&gt;GLYCOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 6, 1996,  pp. 147-156.</ieee>
<mla>Müthing, Johannes, Spanbroek, R, PeterKatalinic, J, Hanisch, FG, Hanski, C, Hasegawa, A, Unland, F, Lehmann, J, Tschesche, Harald, and Egge, H. “Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes”. &lt;em&gt;GLYCOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 6.2 (1996): 147-156.</mla>
<lncs>Müthing, J., Spanbroek, R., PeterKatalinic, J., Hanisch, F.G., Hanski, C., Hasegawa, A., Unland, F., Lehmann, J., Tschesche, H., Egge, H.: Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes. GLYCOBIOLOGY. 6, 147-156 (1996).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Müthing, J., Spanbroek, R., PeterKatalinic, J., Hanisch, F. G., Hanski, C., Hasegawa, A., Unland, F., et al. (1996). Isolation and structural characterization of fucosylated gangliosides with linear poly-N-acetyllactosaminyl chains from human granulocytes. &lt;em&gt;GLYCOBIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;6&lt;/em&gt;(2), 147-156.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1639527</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:15:15Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-08T12:08:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1639527</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1639527</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
