<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">R</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hanemaaijer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sorsa</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">YT</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Konttinen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">YL</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ding</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sutinen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Visser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">VWM</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">vanHinsbergh</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Helaakoski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kainulainen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ronka</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tschesche</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">19406</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Salo</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Biochemie I</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17967</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Neutrophil collagenase (matrix metalloproteinase-8 or MMP-8) is regarded as being synthesized exclusively by polymorphonuclear neutrophils (PMN). However, in vivo MMP-8 expression was observed in mononuclear fibroblast-like cells in the rheumatoid synovial membrane. In addition, we detected MMP-8 mRNA expression in cultured rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and human endothelial cells. Up-regulation of MMP-8 was observed after treatment of the cells with either tumor necrosis factor-alpha (10 ng/ml) or phorbol 12-myristate 13-acetate (10 nM). Western analysis showed a similar regulation at the protein level. The size of secreted MMP-8 was 50 kDa, which is about 30 kDa smaller than MMP-8 from PMN. Conditioned media from rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts contained both type I and II collagen degrading activity. However, degradation of type II collagen, but not that of type I collagen, was completely inhibited by 50 mu M doxycycline, suggesting specific MMP-8 activity. In addition, doxycycline down-regulated MMP-8 induction, at both the mRNA and protein levels. Thus MMP-8 exerts markedly wider expression in human cells than had been thought previously, implying that PMN are not the only source of cartilage degrading activity at arthritic sites. The inhibition of both MMP-8 activity and synthesis by doxycycline provides an incentive for further studies on the clinical effects of doxycycline in the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>AMER SOC BIOCHEMISTRY MOLECULAR BIOLOGY INC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1997</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0021-9258</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">9395486</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1997YL41900045</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1074/jbc.272.50.31504</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>272</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>50</number></detail><extent unit="pages">31504-31509</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Hanemaaijer, R., Sorsa, T., Konttinen, Y. T., Ding, Y. L., Sutinen, M., Visser, H., vanHinsbergh, V. W. M., et al. (1997). Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;272&lt;/em&gt;(50), 31504-31509.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>R. Hanemaaijer, et al., “Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 272, 1997,  pp. 31504-31509.</ieee>
<mla>Hanemaaijer, R, Sorsa, T, Konttinen, YT, Ding, YL, Sutinen, M, Visser, H, vanHinsbergh, VWM, Helaakoski, T, Kainulainen, T, Ronka, H, Tschesche, Harald, and Salo, T. “Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 272.50 (1997): 31504-31509.</mla>
<lncs>Hanemaaijer, R., Sorsa, T., Konttinen, Y.T., Ding, Y.L., Sutinen, M., Visser, H., vanHinsbergh, V.W.M., Helaakoski, T., Kainulainen, T., Ronka, H., Tschesche, H., Salo, T.: Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline. JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY. 272, 31504-31509 (1997).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Hanemaaijer, R, Sorsa, T, Konttinen, YT, Ding, YL, Sutinen, M, Visser, H, vanHinsbergh, VWM, et al. 1997. “Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 272 (50): 31504-31509.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Hanemaaijer, R., Sorsa, T., Konttinen, Y. T., Ding, Y. L., Sutinen, M., Visser, H., vanHinsbergh, V. W. M., et al. (1997). Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;272&lt;/em&gt;(50), 31504-31509.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Hanemaaijer, T.  Sorsa, Y. T.  Konttinen, Y. L.  Ding, M.  Sutinen, H.  Visser, V. W. M.  vanHinsbergh, T.  Helaakoski, T.  Kainulainen, H.  Ronka, et al., “Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1997&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;272&lt;/em&gt;, 31504-31509.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Hanemaaijer, R., Sorsa, T., Konttinen, Y. T., Ding, Y. L., Sutinen, M., Visser, H., vanHinsbergh, V. W. M., Helaakoski, T., Kainulainen, T., Ronka, H., et al. (1997). Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 272, 31504-31509.</frontiers>
<harvard1>Hanemaaijer, R., et al., 1997. Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, 272(50), p 31504-31509.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Hanemaaijer, R., Sorsa, T., Konttinen, Y.T., Ding, Y.L., Sutinen, M., Visser, H., vanHinsbergh, V.W.M., Helaakoski, T., Kainulainen, T., Ronka, H., Tschesche, H. &amp;amp; Salo, T. (1997). Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;272&lt;/em&gt;(50), 31504-31509. AMER SOC BIOCHEMISTRY MOLECULAR BIOLOGY INC. doi:10.1074/jbc.272.50.31504.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Hanemaaijer R, Sorsa T, Konttinen YT, et al. Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;. 1997;272(50):31504-31509.</ama>
<aps>R.  Hanemaaijer, et al., Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline, JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY &lt;strong&gt;272&lt;/strong&gt;, 31504-31509 (1997).</aps>
<bio1>Hanemaaijer R, Sorsa T, Konttinen YT, Ding YL, Sutinen M, Visser H, vanHinsbergh VWM, Helaakoski T, Kainulainen T, Ronka H, Tschesche H, Salo T (1997) &lt;br /&gt;Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline.&lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY 272(50): 31504-31509.</bio1>
<wels>Hanemaaijer, R.; Sorsa, T.; Konttinen, Y. T.; Ding, Y. L.; Sutinen, M.; Visser, H.; vanHinsbergh, V. W. M.; Helaakoski, T.; Kainulainen, T.; Ronka, H.; Tschesche, H.; Salo, T. (1997): Matrix metalloproteinase-8 is expressed in rheumatoid synovial fibroblasts and endothelial cells - Regulation by tumor necrosis factor-alpha and doxycycline &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;,272:(50): 31504-31509.</wels>
<default>Hanemaaijer R, Sorsa T, Konttinen YT, Ding YL, Sutinen M, Visser H, vanHinsbergh VWM, Helaakoski T, Kainulainen T, Ronka H, Tschesche H, et al. (1997) &lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY 272(50): 31504-31509.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1626654</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:22:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-08T12:13:43Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1626654</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1626654</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
