<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Child poverty and environmental justice</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Claudia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hornberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">3752077</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andrea</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pauli</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Gesundheitswissenschaften</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10046</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Child poverty and social inequality in Western countries are growing both in scope and in complexity. The clustering of income poverty in urban settings reflects the complex process of residential segregation. Living in segregated neighbourhoods with much poverty and predominantly substandard housing is usually associated with poor physical, chemical and social environmental living conditions at the individual and community level which influence and shape children&apos;s health both directly and indirectly. Objective: This paper shows research data on the link between child poverty and income-related health inequalities according to the unequal exposure to environmental hazards as well as the unequal distribution of environmental resources in the domestic environment and within the local context as an increasing public health issue in Germany. The links between these factors are drawn from the conceptual framework of environmental justice. Examples are shown of integrated approaches to alleviate social and environmental disparities at the community level. Conclusion: The implications of environmental justice for public health include the need to uncover the link between socioeconomic factors and environmental health disparities related to the man-made environment. Developing relevant indicators for environmental inequalities in the context of housing and health is an important task for public health research. More emphasis should be placed on a comprehensive holistic approach to understand the mechanisms by which socioeconomic factors modify children&apos;s susceptibility and exposure to environmental hazards, particularly in low-income areas. (C) 2007 Elsevier GmbH. All rights reserved.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>ELSEVIER GMBH, URBAN &amp; FISCHER VERLAG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>child poverty</topic><topic>environmental exposure</topic><topic>environmental justice</topic><topic>health disparities</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1438-4639</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">17804293</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000251062600014</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/j.ijheh.2007.07.006</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>210</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>5</number></detail><extent unit="pages">571-580</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Hornberg, C., &amp;amp; Pauli, A. (2007). Child poverty and environmental justice. &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;210&lt;/em&gt;(5), 571-580.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs>Hornberg, C., Pauli, A.: Child poverty and environmental justice. INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH. 210, p. 571-580. ELSEVIER GMBH, URBAN &amp;amp; FISCHER VERLAG (2007).</lncs>
<mla>Hornberg, Claudia, and Pauli, Andrea. “Child poverty and environmental justice”. &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH&lt;/em&gt;. ELSEVIER GMBH, URBAN &amp;amp; FISCHER VERLAG, 2007.Vol. 210. 571-580.</mla>
<ieee>C. Hornberg and A. Pauli, “Child poverty and environmental justice”, &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 210, ELSEVIER GMBH, URBAN &amp;amp; FISCHER VERLAG, 2007,  pp.571-580.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Hornberg, Claudia, and Pauli, Andrea. 2007. “Child poverty and environmental justice”. In &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH&lt;/em&gt;, 210:571-580. ELSEVIER GMBH, URBAN &amp;amp; FISCHER VERLAG.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Hornberg, C., and Pauli, A. (2007). “Child poverty and environmental justice” in &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 210, (ELSEVIER GMBH, URBAN &amp;amp; FISCHER VERLAG), 571-580.</frontiers>
<apa>Hornberg, C., &amp;amp; Pauli, A. (2007). Child poverty and environmental justice. &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;210&lt;/em&gt;(5), 571-580.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Hornberg, and A.  Pauli, in &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH&lt;/em&gt;, Elsevier Gmbh, Urban &amp;amp; Fischer Verlag, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 571-580.</angewandte-chemie>
<bio1>Hornberg C, Pauli A (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Child poverty and environmental justice. &lt;br /&gt;In:  INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH. 210. ELSEVIER GMBH, URBAN &amp;amp; FISCHER VERLAG:  571-580.</bio1>
<aps>C.  Hornberg and A.  Pauli, Child poverty and environmental justice, in &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;210&lt;/strong&gt; (ELSEVIER GMBH, URBAN &amp;amp; FISCHER VERLAG, 2007), p. 571-580.</aps>
<harvard1>Hornberg, C., &amp;amp; Pauli, A., 2007. Child poverty and environmental justice. In &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH&lt;/em&gt;. no.210  ELSEVIER GMBH, URBAN &amp;amp; FISCHER VERLAG, pp. 571-580.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Hornberg, C. &amp;amp; Pauli, A. (2007). Child poverty and environmental justice. &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH&lt;/em&gt; (S. 571-580). ELSEVIER GMBH, URBAN &amp;amp; FISCHER VERLAG. doi:10.1016/j.ijheh.2007.07.006.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Hornberg C, Pauli A. Child poverty and environmental justice. In:  &lt;em&gt;INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 210. ELSEVIER GMBH, URBAN &amp;amp; FISCHER VERLAG;  2007: 571-580.</ama>
<default>Hornberg C, Pauli A (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH. 210. ELSEVIER GMBH, URBAN &amp;amp; FISCHER VERLAG:  571-580.</default>
<wels>Hornberg, C.; Pauli, A. (2007): Child poverty and environmental justice. In: INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYGIENE AND ENVIRONMENTAL HEALTH. ELSEVIER GMBH, URBAN &amp;amp; FISCHER VERLAG. (210).  S. 571-580.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1631398</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:05:42Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-01-04T17:29:22Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1631398</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1631398</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
