<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata)</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Monika</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sadananda</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Joachim</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bischof</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22137</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The lateral forebrain of zebra finches that comprises parts of the lateral nidopallium and parts of the lateral mesopallium is supposed to be involved in the storage and processing of visual information acquired by an early learning process called sexual imprinting. This information is later used to select an appropriate sexual partner for courtship behavior. Being involved in such a complicated behavioral task, the lateral nidopallium should be an integrative area receiving input from many other regions of the brain. our experiments indeed show that the lateral nidopallium receives input from a variety of telencephalic regions including the primary and secondary areas of both visual pathways, the globus pallidus, the caudolateral nidopallium functionally comparable to the prefrontal cortex, the caudomedial nidopallium involved in song perception and storage of song-related memories, and some parts of the arcopallium. There are also a number of thalamic, mesencephalic, and brainstem efferents including the catecholaminergic locus coeruleus and the unspecific activating reticular formation. The spatial distribution of afferents suggests a compartmentalization of the lateral nidopallium into several subdivisions. Based on its connections, the lateral nidopallium should be considered as an area of higher order processing of visual information coming from the tectofugal and the thalamofugal visual pathways. Other sensory modalities and also motivational factors from a variety of brain areas are also integrated here. These findings support the idea of an involvement of the lateral nidopallium in imprinting and the control of courtship behavior. (c) 2006 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>telencephalon</topic><topic>activity-dependent plasticity</topic><topic>pallium</topic><topic>tract tracing</topic><topic>visual pathway</topic><topic>bird</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BRAIN RESEARCH</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0006-8993</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">16843442</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000240510900013</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2006.04.009</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1106</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">111-122</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Sadananda M, Bischof H-J (2006) &lt;br /&gt;Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata).&lt;br /&gt;BRAIN RESEARCH 1106(1): 111-122.</bio1>
<aps> M.  Sadananda and H. - J.  Bischof, Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata), BRAIN RESEARCH &lt;strong&gt;1106&lt;/strong&gt;, 111-122 (2006).</aps>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Sadananda, M. &amp;amp; Bischof, H.-J. (2006). Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata). &lt;em&gt;BRAIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1106&lt;/em&gt;(1), 111-122. ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV. doi:10.1016/j.brainres.2006.04.009.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Sadananda, M., &amp;amp; Bischof, H.-J., 2006. Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata). &lt;em&gt;BRAIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, 1106(1), p 111-122.</harvard1>
<ama>Sadananda M, Bischof H-J. Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata). &lt;em&gt;BRAIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;. 2006;1106(1):111-122.</ama>
<default>Sadananda M, Bischof H-J (2006) &lt;br /&gt;BRAIN RESEARCH 1106(1): 111-122.</default>
<wels>Sadananda, M.; Bischof, H. - J. (2006): Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata) &lt;em&gt;BRAIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;,1106:(1): 111-122.</wels>
<lncs> Sadananda, M., Bischof, H.-J.: Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata). BRAIN RESEARCH. 1106, 111-122 (2006).</lncs>
<mla>Sadananda, Monika, and Bischof, Hans-Joachim. “Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata)”. &lt;em&gt;BRAIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt; 1106.1 (2006): 111-122.</mla>
<ieee> M. Sadananda and H.-J. Bischof, “Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata)”, &lt;em&gt;BRAIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 1106, 2006,  pp. 111-122.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Sadananda, M., &amp;amp; Bischof, H. - J. (2006). Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata). &lt;em&gt;BRAIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1106&lt;/em&gt;(1), 111-122.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Sadananda, M., and Bischof, H. - J. (2006). Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata). &lt;em&gt;BRAIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt; 1106, 111-122.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Sadananda, and H. - J.  Bischof, “Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata)”, &lt;em&gt;BRAIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1106&lt;/em&gt;, 111-122.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Sadananda, M., &amp;amp; Bischof, H. - J. (2006). Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata). &lt;em&gt;BRAIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1106&lt;/em&gt;(1), 111-122.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Sadananda, Monika, and Bischof, Hans-Joachim. 2006. “Afferentation of the lateral nidopallium: A tracing study of a brain area involved in sexual imprinting in the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata)”. &lt;em&gt;BRAIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt; 1106 (1): 111-122.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1597886</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:19:07Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-10-11T09:47:55Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1597886</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1597886</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
