<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae)</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">York</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Winter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Otto von</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Helversen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulla M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Norberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas H.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kunz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">John Fleng</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Steffensen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">W.</namePart><namePart type="family">Barthlott</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Biologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The cost of forward flight for a 11.7 g nectar-feeding bat Glossophaga soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae) was estimated to be 5.888 kJ h -1 (1.63 W). To obtain this estimate, we quantified the amount of time allocated to specific activities and the animal´s daily energy intake in captivity for 17 separate 24-hour-periods. These data were arrangedin a set of daily energy-balance equations with the energy coefficients for each activity as unknown parameters. These equations were solved for the unknown coefficients b ymultiple lonear regression analysis. Using our estimate of flight cost and values for daily energy expenditure from the literature, we estimated how a free-ranging nectar-feeding bat allocates time and energy among different activities.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Winter_01.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1780955/2313108</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription><accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1993</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>daily energy expenditure</topic><topic>Phyllostomidae</topic><topic>flight cost</topic><topic>time budget</topic><topic>Glossophaga soricina</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Animal plant interactions in tropical environments</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">3-925382-36-4</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-23008</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">167-174</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>Y.  Winter, O.  von Helversen, U. M.  Norberg, T. H.  Kunz, and J. F.  Steffensen, in &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: W. Barthlott), Bonn, &lt;strong&gt;1993&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 167-174.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Winter, Y., Helversen, O.  von, Norberg, U. M., Kunz, T. H., &amp;amp; Steffensen, J. F. (1993). Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae). In W.  Barthlott (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 167-174). Bonn.</apa>
<frontiers>Winter, Y., Helversen, O.  von, Norberg, U. M., Kunz, T. H., and Steffensen, J. F. (1993). “Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae)” in &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt;, ed. W.  Barthlott (Bonn), 167-174.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Winter, York, Helversen, Otto von, Norberg, Ulla M., Kunz, Thomas H., and Steffensen, John Fleng. 1993. “Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae)”. In &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt;, ed. W. Barthlott, 167-174. Bonn.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee>Y. Winter, et al., “Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae)”, &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt;, W. Barthlott, ed.,  Bonn: 1993,  pp.167-174.</ieee>
<mla>Winter, York, Helversen, Otto von, Norberg, Ulla M., Kunz, Thomas H., and Steffensen, John Fleng. “Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae)”. &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. W. Barthlott. Bonn, 1993. 167-174.</mla>
<lncs>Winter, Y., Helversen, O. von, Norberg, U.M., Kunz, T.H., Steffensen, J.F.: Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae). In: Barthlott, W. (ed.) Animal plant interactions in tropical environments. p. 167-174. Bonn (1993).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Winter, Y., Helversen, O.  von, Norberg, U. M., Kunz, T. H., &amp;amp; Steffensen, J. F. (1993). Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae). In W.  Barthlott (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 167-174). Bonn.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Winter, Y.; Helversen, O.  von; Norberg, U. M.; Kunz, T. H.; Steffensen, J. F. (1993): Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae). In: W. Barthlott (Hrsg.):  Animal plant interactions in tropical environments. Bonn.  S. 167-174.</wels>
<default>Winter Y, Helversen O von, Norberg UM, Kunz TH, Steffensen JF (1993)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Animal plant interactions in tropical environments. Barthlott W (Ed);Bonn:  167-174.</default>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Winter, Y., Helversen, O. von, Norberg, U.M., Kunz, T.H. &amp;amp; Steffensen, J.F. (1993). Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae). &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt; (S. 167-174). Bonn.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Winter, Y., et al., 1993. Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae). In W.  Barthlott, ed. &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt;.  Bonn, pp. 167-174.</harvard1>
<ama>Winter Y, Helversen O von, Norberg UM, Kunz TH, Steffensen JF. Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae). In: Barthlott W, ed. &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt;. Bonn;  1993: 167-174.</ama>
<aps>Y.  Winter, et al., Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae), in &lt;em&gt;Animal plant interactions in tropical environments&lt;/em&gt;, edited by W.  Barthlott (Bonn, 1993), p. 167-174.</aps>
<bio1>Winter Y, Helversen O von, Norberg UM, Kunz TH, Steffensen JF (1993) &lt;br /&gt;Flight cost and economy of nectar-feeding in the bat Glossophaga Soricina (Phyllostomidae; Glossophaginae). &lt;br /&gt;In:  Animal plant interactions in tropical environments. Barthlott W (Ed); Bonn:  167-174.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1780955</recordIdentifier><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-01-26T08:38:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1780955</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1780955</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
