<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schmidt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans-Joachim</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bischof</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22137</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2528935</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The electrophysiological and morphological features of visually driven neurons of the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch optic tectum were studied by extracellular recording and staining techniques. Stratum griseum centrale neuron responses are sustained in most cases. Receptive fields are big, up to 150degrees of the visual field. The excitatory center (hot spot) varies in size from 1degrees to 15degrees. It can be mapped by small static stimuli, adapts slower than the surround, and has a shape comparable to the excitatory fields of upper-layer neurons. In contrast, the big surround shows responses only to small moving objects which elicit a typical pattern of alternating bursts and silent periods. Alternatively, the same stimuli elicit long-lasting bursts followed by strong adaption. Anatomically, stratum griseum centrale neurons are characterized by far reaching dendrites which terminate with &quot;bottlebrush&quot;-like endings in the upper retinorecipient layers. In addition, they are connected with retinorecipient structures by an interneuron located between layers 10 and 11. The role of the structure of inputs for the organization of the receptive fields is discussed.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2001</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>hot spots</topic><topic>bird</topic><topic>visual system</topic><topic>biocytin</topic><topic>movement-sensitive surrounds</topic><topic>electrophysiology</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0340-7594</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1432-1351</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">11866189</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000173893900006</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/s00359-001-0264-8</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>187</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>11</number></detail><extent unit="pages">913-924</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Schmidt A, Bischof H-J (2001) &lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY 187(11): 913-924.</default>
<wels>Schmidt, A.; Bischof, H. - J. (2001): Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,187:(11): 913-924.</wels>
<aps> A.  Schmidt and H. - J.  Bischof, Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum, JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY &lt;strong&gt;187&lt;/strong&gt;, 913-924 (2001).</aps>
<bio1>Schmidt A, Bischof H-J (2001) &lt;br /&gt;Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum.&lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY 187(11): 913-924.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Schmidt, A. &amp;amp; Bischof, H.-J. (2001). Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;187&lt;/em&gt;(11), 913-924. SPRINGER-VERLAG. doi:10.1007/s00359-001-0264-8.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Schmidt A, Bischof H-J. Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. 2001;187(11):913-924.</ama>
<harvard1>Schmidt, A., &amp;amp; Bischof, H.-J., 2001. Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 187(11), p 913-924.</harvard1>
<frontiers>Schmidt, A., and Bischof, H. - J. (2001). Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 187, 913-924.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Schmidt, and H. - J.  Bischof, “Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2001&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;187&lt;/em&gt;, 913-924.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Schmidt, A., &amp;amp; Bischof, H. - J. (2001). Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;187&lt;/em&gt;(11), 913-924.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Schmidt, A, and Bischof, Hans-Joachim. 2001. “Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 187 (11): 913-924.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Schmidt, A, and Bischof, Hans-Joachim. “Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 187.11 (2001): 913-924.</mla>
<lncs> Schmidt, A., Bischof, H.-J.: Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum. JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY. 187, 913-924 (2001).</lncs>
<ieee> A. Schmidt and H.-J. Bischof, “Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 187, 2001,  pp. 913-924.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Schmidt, A., &amp;amp; Bischof, H. - J. (2001). Neurons with complex receptive fields in the stratum griseum centrale of the zebra finch (Taeniopygia guttata castanotis Gould) optic tectum. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF COMPARATIVE PHYSIOLOGY A-NEUROETHOLOGY SENSORY NEURAL AND BEHAVIORAL PHYSIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;187&lt;/em&gt;(11), 913-924.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1615346</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:01:51Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-09-20T06:10:54Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1615346</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1615346</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
