<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">D</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Niemeyer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Becker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Institut für Genomforschung und Systembiologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">It is thought that in the gram-negative soil bacterium Sinorhizobium meliloti the protein ExoP is involved in biosynthesis of the acidic exopolysaccharide succinoglycan (EPS I). The amounts and compositions of EPS I produced by mutants expressing ExoP proteins characterized by specific amino acid substitutions in the C-terminal cytoplasmic domain were analyzed. The cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein was shown to have ATPase activity. Mutations in the highly conserved Walker A ATP-binding motif prevented ATPase activity of the ExoP protein. Phenotypically, these mutations resulted in much lower levels of succinoglycan which consisted only of monomers of the octasaccharide repeating unit. The ExoP protein has similarities to proteins with autophosphorylating protein tyrosine kinase activity. We found that ExoP was phosphorylated on tyrosine and that site-directed mutagenesis of specific tyrosine residues in the cytoplasmic domain of ExoP resulted in an altered ratio of low-molecular-weight succinoglycan to high-molecular-weight succinoglycan.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>AMER SOC MICROBIOLOGY</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2001</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0021-9193</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">11489870</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000170349200027</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1128/JB.183.17.5163-5170.2001</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>183</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>17</number></detail><extent unit="pages">5163-5170</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Niemeyer, D., &amp;amp; Becker, A., 2001. The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 183(17), p 5163-5170.</harvard1>
<ama>Niemeyer D, Becker A. The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. 2001;183(17):5163-5170.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Niemeyer, D. &amp;amp; Becker, A. (2001). The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;183&lt;/em&gt;(17), 5163-5170. AMER SOC MICROBIOLOGY. doi:10.1128/JB.183.17.5163-5170.2001.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Niemeyer D, Becker A (2001) &lt;br /&gt;The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein.&lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY 183(17): 5163-5170.</bio1>
<aps>D.  Niemeyer and A.  Becker, The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein, JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY &lt;strong&gt;183&lt;/strong&gt;, 5163-5170 (2001).</aps>
<wels>Niemeyer, D.; Becker, A. (2001): The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,183:(17): 5163-5170.</wels>
<default>Niemeyer D, Becker A (2001) &lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY 183(17): 5163-5170.</default>
<ieee>D. Niemeyer and A. Becker, “The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 183, 2001,  pp. 5163-5170.</ieee>
<lncs>Niemeyer, D., Becker, A.: The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein. JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY. 183, 5163-5170 (2001).</lncs>
<mla>Niemeyer, D, and Becker, A. “The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 183.17 (2001): 5163-5170.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Niemeyer, D., &amp;amp; Becker, A. (2001). The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;183&lt;/em&gt;(17), 5163-5170.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>D.  Niemeyer, and A.  Becker, “The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2001&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;183&lt;/em&gt;, 5163-5170.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Niemeyer, D., &amp;amp; Becker, A. (2001). The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;183&lt;/em&gt;(17), 5163-5170.</apa>
<frontiers>Niemeyer, D., and Becker, A. (2001). The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 183, 5163-5170.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Niemeyer, D, and Becker, A. 2001. “The molecular weight distribution of succinoglycan produced by Sinorhizobium meliloti is influenced by specific tyrosine phosphorylation and ATPase activity of the cytoplasmic domain of the ExoP protein”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 183 (17): 5163-5170.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1616604</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:02:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-09-28T15:20:32Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1616604</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1616604</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
