<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nadina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Karaolis-Danckert</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anke L. B.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Guenther</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anja</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kroke</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Claudia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hornberg</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">3752077</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anette E.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Buyken</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Gesundheitswissenschaften</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10046</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: It is not clear whether the adverse effects of rapid weight gain in infancy are modified by nutrition during the first 2 y of life in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age (AGA). Objective: We examined the interaction between rapid weight gain and nutrition in infancy and early childhood and their effect on body fat percentage (BF%) trajectories between 2 and 5 y of age. Design: The study population comprised 249 (51.4% female) term AGA participants of the Dortmund Nutritional and Anthropometric Longitudinally Designed Study, for whom repeated anthropometric measurements until 5 y of age and information on breastfeeding status and on diet at 12 and 18-24 mo of age were available. Results: Multilevel model analyses showed that, among rapid growers, those who had been fully breastfed for &gt;= 4 mo had a lower BF% at 2 y of age than did those who had not been fully breastfed for 4 mo (0 SE: -1.53 +/- 0.59%; P = 0.009). This difference persisted until 5 y. Furthermore, those rapid growers who had a consistently high fat intake at both 12 and 18-24 mo did not show the expected physiologic decrease in BF% between 2 and 5 y seen in those rapid growers with an inconsistent or consistently low fat intake at these time points (0.73 +/- 0.26%/y; P = 0.006). Conclusions: Among rapid growers, full breastfeeding for &gt;= 4 mo is protective against a high BF% at 2 y of age, whereas a consistently high fat intake in the second year of life &quot;inhibits&quot; the physiologic decrease in BF% between 2 and 5 y.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>AMER SOC CLINICAL NUTRITION</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>rapid weight gain</topic><topic>nutrition</topic><topic>breastfeeding</topic><topic>body fat percentage</topic><topic>children</topic><topic>trajectories</topic><topic>appropriate for gestational age</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0002-9165</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">18065589</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000251575500019</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>86</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>6</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1700-1708</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<aps>N.  Karaolis-Danckert, et al., How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age, AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION &lt;strong&gt;86&lt;/strong&gt;, 1700-1708 (2007).</aps>
<bio1>Karaolis-Danckert N, Guenther ALB, Kroke A, Hornberg C, Buyken AE (2007) &lt;br /&gt;How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age.&lt;br /&gt;AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION 86(6): 1700-1708.</bio1>
<harvard1>Karaolis-Danckert, N., et al., 2007. How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age. &lt;em&gt;AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION&lt;/em&gt;, 86(6), p 1700-1708.</harvard1>
<ama>Karaolis-Danckert N, Guenther ALB, Kroke A, Hornberg C, Buyken AE. How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age. &lt;em&gt;AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION&lt;/em&gt;. 2007;86(6):1700-1708.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Karaolis-Danckert, N., Guenther, A.L.B., Kroke, A., Hornberg, C. &amp;amp; Buyken, A.E. (2007). How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age. &lt;em&gt;AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;86&lt;/em&gt;(6), 1700-1708. AMER SOC CLINICAL NUTRITION.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Karaolis-Danckert N, Guenther ALB, Kroke A, Hornberg C, Buyken AE (2007) &lt;br /&gt;AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION 86(6): 1700-1708.</default>
<wels>Karaolis-Danckert, N.; Guenther, A. L. B.; Kroke, A.; Hornberg, C.; Buyken, A. E. (2007): How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age &lt;em&gt;AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION&lt;/em&gt;,86:(6): 1700-1708.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Karaolis-Danckert, N., Guenther, A. L. B., Kroke, A., Hornberg, C., &amp;amp; Buyken, A. E. (2007). How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age. &lt;em&gt;AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;86&lt;/em&gt;(6), 1700-1708.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Karaolis-Danckert, Nadina, Guenther, Anke L. B., Kroke, Anja, Hornberg, Claudia, and Buyken, Anette E. “How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age”. &lt;em&gt;AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION&lt;/em&gt; 86.6 (2007): 1700-1708.</mla>
<lncs>Karaolis-Danckert, N., Guenther, A.L.B., Kroke, A., Hornberg, C., Buyken, A.E.: How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age. AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION. 86, 1700-1708 (2007).</lncs>
<ieee>N. Karaolis-Danckert, et al., “How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age”, &lt;em&gt;AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 86, 2007,  pp. 1700-1708.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Karaolis-Danckert, Nadina, Guenther, Anke L. B., Kroke, Anja, Hornberg, Claudia, and Buyken, Anette E. 2007. “How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age”. &lt;em&gt;AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION&lt;/em&gt; 86 (6): 1700-1708.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Karaolis-Danckert, N., Guenther, A. L. B., Kroke, A., Hornberg, C., and Buyken, A. E. (2007). How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age. &lt;em&gt;AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION&lt;/em&gt; 86, 1700-1708.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Karaolis-Danckert, A. L. B.  Guenther, A.  Kroke, C.  Hornberg, and A. E.  Buyken, “How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age”, &lt;em&gt;AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;86&lt;/em&gt;, 1700-1708.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Karaolis-Danckert, N., Guenther, A. L. B., Kroke, A., Hornberg, C., &amp;amp; Buyken, A. E. (2007). How early dietary factors modify the effect of rapid weight gain in infancy on subsequent body-composition development in term children whose birth weight was appropriate for gestational age. &lt;em&gt;AMERICAN JOURNAL OF CLINICAL NUTRITION&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;86&lt;/em&gt;(6), 1700-1708.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1631148</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:05:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-01-04T17:29:21Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1631148</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1631148</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
