<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Stefanie</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kuhn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stiens</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pühler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21937</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schlüter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">55545</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-4830-310X</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">33070639</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Plasmid pSmeSM11a, residing in the indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strain SM11 originating from a field in Strassmoos (Bavaria, Germany), was analysed previously at the genomic level. Thirty-seven indigenous S. meliloti strains, originating from two different locations in Germany, were screened for genes identified previously on pSmeSM11a. Seven of these strains harbour accessory plasmids that are very similar to pSmeSM11a. The identified pSmeSM11a-like plasmids are c. 130-150 kb in size and possess nearly identical restriction profiles. Up to 30 genes identified previously on pSmeSM11a could be detected on these plasmids by hybridisation experiments, e.g., the nodulation genes nodP and nodQ, the ethylene level modulation gene acdS and the taurine metabolism gene tauD. A few pSmeSM11a genes were also detected on other plasmids. The reference plasmid pSmeSM11a contains a region that is similar to a segment of S. meliloti strain Rm1021 pSymA. Regions with similarity to pSymA were also detected on the aforementioned seven pSmeSM11a-like plasmids. The specifications of these regions are nearly identical to the one on pSmeSM11a and differ from Rm1021 pSymA as determined by nucleotide sequence analysis. Two further plasmids similar to pSmeSM11a completely lack the pSymA-region. Those strains carrying accessory plasmids that contain the acdS gene encoding 1-aminocyclopropane-1-carboxylate deaminase are able to grow on 1-aminocyclopropane-1-carboxylate as the sole source of nitrogen, demonstrating functionality of the acdS gene product. About 36% of the analysed plasmids, including three pSmeSM11a-like plasmids, could be transferred to another S. meliloti recipient strain, allowing for their dissemination in S. meliloti populations.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>BLACKWELL PUBLISHING</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>nitrogen fixation</topic><topic>ethylene metabolism</topic><topic>1-aminocyclopropane-1-carboxylate deaminase</topic><topic>plasmid mobilisation</topic><topic>IS elements</topic><topic>nodulation</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0168-6496</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">18034835</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000251504000013</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1111/j.1574-6941.2007.00399.x</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>63</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">118-131</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Kuhn S, Stiens M, Pühler A, Schlüter A (2008) &lt;br /&gt;Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains.&lt;br /&gt;FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY 63(1): 118-131.</bio1>
<aps> S.  Kuhn, et al., Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains, FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY &lt;strong&gt;63&lt;/strong&gt;, 118-131 (2008).</aps>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kuhn, S., Stiens, M., Pühler, A. &amp;amp; Schlüter, A. (2008). Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains. &lt;em&gt;FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;63&lt;/em&gt;(1), 118-131. BLACKWELL PUBLISHING. doi:10.1111/j.1574-6941.2007.00399.x.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Kuhn S, Stiens M, Pühler A, Schlüter A. Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains. &lt;em&gt;FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. 2008;63(1):118-131.</ama>
<harvard1>Kuhn, S., et al., 2008. Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains. &lt;em&gt;FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 63(1), p 118-131.</harvard1>
<default>Kuhn S, Stiens M, Pühler A, Schlüter A (2008) &lt;br /&gt;FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY 63(1): 118-131.</default>
<wels>Kuhn, S.; Stiens, M.; Pühler, A.; Schlüter, A. (2008): Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains &lt;em&gt;FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,63:(1): 118-131.</wels>
<lncs> Kuhn, S., Stiens, M., Pühler, A., Schlüter, A.: Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains. FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY. 63, 118-131 (2008).</lncs>
<mla>Kuhn, Stefanie, Stiens, Michael, Pühler, Alfred, and Schlüter, Andreas. “Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains”. &lt;em&gt;FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 63.1 (2008): 118-131.</mla>
<ieee> S. Kuhn, et al., “Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains”, &lt;em&gt;FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 63, 2008,  pp. 118-131.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kuhn, S., Stiens, M., Pühler, A., &amp;amp; Schlüter, A. (2008). Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains. &lt;em&gt;FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;63&lt;/em&gt;(1), 118-131.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Kuhn, S., Stiens, M., Pühler, A., and Schlüter, A. (2008). Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains. &lt;em&gt;FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 63, 118-131.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kuhn, M.  Stiens, A.  Pühler, and A.  Schlüter, “Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains”, &lt;em&gt;FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;63&lt;/em&gt;, 118-131.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Kuhn, S., Stiens, M., Pühler, A., &amp;amp; Schlüter, A. (2008). Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains. &lt;em&gt;FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;63&lt;/em&gt;(1), 118-131.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kuhn, Stefanie, Stiens, Michael, Pühler, Alfred, and Schlüter, Andreas. 2008. “Prevalence of pSmeSM11a-like plasmids in indigenous Sinorhizobium meliloti strains isolated in the course of a field release experiment with genetically modified S-meliloti strains”. &lt;em&gt;FEMS MICROBIOLOGY ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 63 (1): 118-131.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1631126</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:05:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-08-02T13:16:45Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1631126</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1631126</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
