<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Naoufal</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bahlawane</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">71184</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-1094-2512</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ulf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Struckmeier</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">170948</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tina S.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kasper</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Patrick</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Oßwald</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">150940</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-2257-2988</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17978</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Chemical vapor deposition (CVD) and metal-organic chemical vapor deposition (MOCVD) have been employed to develop alumina thin films in order to protect thermocouples from catalytic overheating in flames and to minimize the intrusion presented to the combustion process. Alumina films obtained with a CVD process using AlCl3 as the precursor are dense, not contaminated, and crystallize in the corundum structure, while MOCVD using Al(acetyl acetone)(3) allows the growth of corundum alumina with improved growth rates. These films, however, present a porous columnar structure and show some carbon contamination. Therefore, coated thermocouples using AlCl3-CVD were judged more suitable for flame temperature measurements and were tested in different fuels over a typical range of stoichiometries. Coated thermocouples exhibit satisfactory measurement reproducibility, no temporal drifts, and do not suffer from catalytic effects. Furthermore, their increased radiative heat loss (observed by infrared spectroscopy) allows temperature measurements over a wider range when compared to uncoated thermocouples. A flame with a well-known temperature profile established with laser-based techniques was used to determine the radiative heat loss correction to account for the difference between the apparent temperature measured by the coated thermocouple and the true flame temperature. The validity of the correction term was confirmed with temperature profile measurements for several flames previously studied in different laboratories with laser-based techniques. (c) 2007 American Institute of Physics.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0034-6748</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">17503931</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000243892300033</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1063/1.2426876</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>78</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Bahlawane, Naoufal, Struckmeier, Ulf, Kasper, Tina S., and Oßwald, Patrick. “Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements”. &lt;em&gt;REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS&lt;/em&gt; 78.1 (2007): 013905.</mla>
<lncs> Bahlawane, N., Struckmeier, U., Kasper, T.S., Oßwald, P.: Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements. REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS. 78, : 013905 (2007).</lncs>
<ieee> N. Bahlawane, et al., “Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements”, &lt;em&gt;REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 78, 2007, : 013905.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Bahlawane, N., Struckmeier, U., Kasper, T. S., &amp;amp; Oßwald, P. (2007). Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements. &lt;em&gt;REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;78&lt;/em&gt;(1): 013905.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Bahlawane, N., Struckmeier, U., Kasper, T. S., and Oßwald, P. (2007). Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements. &lt;em&gt;REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS&lt;/em&gt; 78:013905.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>N.  Bahlawane, U.  Struckmeier, T. S.  Kasper, and P.  Oßwald, “Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements”, &lt;em&gt;REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;78&lt;/em&gt;, : 013905.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Bahlawane, N., Struckmeier, U., Kasper, T. S., &amp;amp; Oßwald, P. (2007). Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements. &lt;em&gt;REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;78&lt;/em&gt;(1): 013905.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Bahlawane, Naoufal, Struckmeier, Ulf, Kasper, Tina S., and Oßwald, Patrick. 2007. “Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements”. &lt;em&gt;REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS&lt;/em&gt; 78 (1): 013905.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<aps> N.  Bahlawane, et al., Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements, REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS &lt;strong&gt;78&lt;/strong&gt;, (2007).</aps>
<bio1>Bahlawane N, Struckmeier U, Kasper TS, Oßwald P (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements.&lt;br /&gt;REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS 78(1): 013905.</bio1>
<ama>Bahlawane N, Struckmeier U, Kasper TS, Oßwald P. Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements. &lt;em&gt;REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS&lt;/em&gt;. 2007;78(1): 013905.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Bahlawane, N., Struckmeier, U., Kasper, T.S. &amp;amp; Oßwald, P. (2007). Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements. &lt;em&gt;REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;78&lt;/em&gt;(1): 013905. AMER INST PHYSICS. doi:10.1063/1.2426876.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Bahlawane, N., et al., 2007. Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements. &lt;em&gt;REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS&lt;/em&gt;, 78(1): 013905.</harvard1>
<default>Bahlawane N, Struckmeier U, Kasper TS, Oßwald P (2007) &lt;br /&gt;REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS 78(1): 013905.</default>
<wels>Bahlawane, N.; Struckmeier, U.; Kasper, T. S.; Oßwald, P. (2007): Noncatalytic thermocouple coatings produced with chemical vapor deposition for flame temperature measurements &lt;em&gt;REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS&lt;/em&gt;,78:(1):013905</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1595933</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:16:52Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-10-18T09:20:55Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1595933</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1595933</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
