<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ilse-Dore</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Adler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Angelo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Carere</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ursula</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eichenlaub-Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22132</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Francesca</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pacchierotti</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Gentechnologie/Mikrobiologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2685250</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Germ cell mutagenicity testing provides experimental data to quantify genetic risk for exposed human populations. The majority of tests are performed with exposure of males, and female data are relatively rare. The reason for this paucity lies in the differences between male and female germ cell biology. Male germ cells are produced throughout reproductive life and all developmental stages can be ascertained by appropriate breeding schemes. In contrast, the female germ cell pool is limited, meiosis begins during embryogenesis and oocytes are arrested over long periods of time until maturation processes start for small numbers of oocytes during the oestrus cycle in mature females. The literature data are reviewed to point out possible gender differences of germ cells to exogenous agents such as chemicals or ionizing radiation. From the limited information, it can be concluded that male germ cells are more sensitive than female germ cells to the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations. However, exceptions are described which shed doubt on the extrapolation of experimental data from male rodents to the genetic risk of the human population. Furthermore, the female genome may be more sensitive to mutation induction during peri-conceptional stages compared to the male genome of the zygote. With few exceptions, germ cell experiments have been carried out under high acute exposure to optimize the effects and to compensate for the limited sample size in animal experiments. Human exposure to environmental agents, on the other hand, is usually chronic and involves low doses. Under these conditions, gender differences may become apparent that have not been studied so far. Additionally, data are reviewed that suggest a false impression of safety when responses are negative under high acute exposure of male rodents while a mutational response is induced by low chronic exposure. The classical (morphological) germ cell mutation tests are not performed anymore because they are animal and time consuming. Nevertheless, information is needed to place genetic risk extrapolations on more solid grounds and thereby to prevent an increased genetic burden to future generations. It is pointed out that modern molecular methodologies are available now to experimentally address the open questions. (c) 2006 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS INC ELSEVIER SCIENCE</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>germ cell mutagenesis</topic><topic>progeny testing</topic><topic>rodents</topic><topic>stage specificity</topic><topic>gender differences</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0013-9351</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">17052706</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000246409200005</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2006.08.010</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>104</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">37-45</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Adler I-D, Carere A, Eichenlaub-Ritter U, Pacchierotti F (2007) &lt;br /&gt;ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH 104(1): 37-45.</default>
<wels>Adler, I. - D.; Carere, A.; Eichenlaub-Ritter, U.; Pacchierotti, F. (2007): Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells &lt;em&gt;ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;,104:(1): 37-45.</wels>
<bio1>Adler I-D, Carere A, Eichenlaub-Ritter U, Pacchierotti F (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells.&lt;br /&gt;ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH 104(1): 37-45.</bio1>
<aps>I. - D.  Adler, et al., Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells, ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH &lt;strong&gt;104&lt;/strong&gt;, 37-45 (2007).</aps>
<ama>Adler I-D, Carere A, Eichenlaub-Ritter U, Pacchierotti F. Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells. &lt;em&gt;ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;. 2007;104(1):37-45.</ama>
<harvard1>Adler, I.-D., et al., 2007. Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells. &lt;em&gt;ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, 104(1), p 37-45.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Adler, I.-D., Carere, A., Eichenlaub-Ritter, U. &amp;amp; Pacchierotti, F. (2007). Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells. &lt;em&gt;ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;104&lt;/em&gt;(1), 37-45. ACADEMIC PRESS INC ELSEVIER SCIENCE. doi:10.1016/j.envres.2006.08.010.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Adler, I. - D., Carere, A., Eichenlaub-Ritter, U., and Pacchierotti, F. (2007). Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells. &lt;em&gt;ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt; 104, 37-45.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>I. - D.  Adler, A.  Carere, U.  Eichenlaub-Ritter, and F.  Pacchierotti, “Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells”, &lt;em&gt;ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;104&lt;/em&gt;, 37-45.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Adler, I. - D., Carere, A., Eichenlaub-Ritter, U., &amp;amp; Pacchierotti, F. (2007). Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells. &lt;em&gt;ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;104&lt;/em&gt;(1), 37-45.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Adler, Ilse-Dore, Carere, Angelo, Eichenlaub-Ritter, Ursula, and Pacchierotti, Francesca. 2007. “Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells”. &lt;em&gt;ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt; 104 (1): 37-45.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Adler, Ilse-Dore, Carere, Angelo, Eichenlaub-Ritter, Ursula, and Pacchierotti, Francesca. “Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells”. &lt;em&gt;ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt; 104.1 (2007): 37-45.</mla>
<lncs>Adler, I.-D., Carere, A., Eichenlaub-Ritter, U., Pacchierotti, F.: Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells. ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH. 104, 37-45 (2007).</lncs>
<ieee>I.-D. Adler, et al., “Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells”, &lt;em&gt;ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 104, 2007,  pp. 37-45.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Adler, I. - D., Carere, A., Eichenlaub-Ritter, U., &amp;amp; Pacchierotti, F. (2007). Gender differences in the induction of chromosomal aberrations and gene mutations in rodent germ cells. &lt;em&gt;ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;104&lt;/em&gt;(1), 37-45.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1593932</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:16:06Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-01-25T18:01:04Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1593932</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1593932</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
