<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Markowitsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">59726756</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">G</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">WeberLuxemburger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">K</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ewald</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kessler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">WD</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Heiss</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Abteilung für Psychologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10026</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Equating the condition after cardiac arrest with that of medial temporal damage, and consequently medial temporal lobe amnesia, is questioned on the basis of results from a patient who was studied neuropsychologically as well as with static and dynamic imaging methods (MRI, PET) 6-9 months after a heart attack. The patient manifested severe and persistent anterograde and retrograde amnesia, as well as further cognitive deteriorations. While MRI only indicated non-specific cortical atrophy, PET revealed a severe bilateral affection of the thalamus and of both medial and lateral temporal cortices as well as occipito-parietal hypometabolism. The neuropsychological status indicates that patients with a diagnosis of cardiac arrest may suffer very severe and persistent cognitive deficits; the imaging analysers show that cardiac arrests may lead to quite severe and widespread brain damage which, however, may not be visible with current magnetic resonance imaging technology, but which is clearly apparent from positron emission tomography. These data suggest that patients with a condition after a heart attack may not be valid models for pure hippocampal--or even medial temporal lobe--pathology, as they may suffer much more widespread brain damage.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>RAPID SCIENCE PUBLISHERS</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1997</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>medial temporal lobe amnesia</topic><topic>PET</topic><topic>heart attack</topic><topic>memory</topic><topic>hippocampus</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1351-5101</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">24283911</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1997XC95700015</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1111/j.1468-1331.1997.tb00324.x</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>4</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">178-184</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Markowitsch, H.J., et al., 1997. Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 4(2), p 178-184.</harvard1>
<ama>Markowitsch HJ, WeberLuxemburger G, Ewald K, Kessler J, Heiss WD. Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. 1997;4(2):178-184.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Markowitsch, H.J., WeberLuxemburger, G., Ewald, K., Kessler, J. &amp;amp; Heiss, W.D. (1997). Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;(2), 178-184. RAPID SCIENCE PUBLISHERS. doi:10.1111/j.1468-1331.1997.tb00324.x.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Markowitsch HJ, WeberLuxemburger G, Ewald K, Kessler J, Heiss WD (1997) &lt;br /&gt;Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research.&lt;br /&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY 4(2): 178-184.</bio1>
<aps>H. J.  Markowitsch, et al., Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research, EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;, 178-184 (1997).</aps>
<wels>Markowitsch, H. J.; WeberLuxemburger, G.; Ewald, K.; Kessler, J.; Heiss, W. D. (1997): Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,4:(2): 178-184.</wels>
<default>Markowitsch HJ, WeberLuxemburger G, Ewald K, Kessler J, Heiss WD (1997) &lt;br /&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY 4(2): 178-184.</default>
<ieee>H.J. Markowitsch, et al., “Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research”, &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 4, 1997,  pp. 178-184.</ieee>
<mla>Markowitsch, Hans J., WeberLuxemburger, G, Ewald, K, Kessler, J, and Heiss, WD. “Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research”. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 4.2 (1997): 178-184.</mla>
<lncs>Markowitsch, H.J., WeberLuxemburger, G., Ewald, K., Kessler, J., Heiss, W.D.: Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research. EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY. 4, 178-184 (1997).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Markowitsch, H. J., WeberLuxemburger, G., Ewald, K., Kessler, J., &amp;amp; Heiss, W. D. (1997). Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;(2), 178-184.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>H. J.  Markowitsch, G.  WeberLuxemburger, K.  Ewald, J.  Kessler, and W. D.  Heiss, “Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research”, &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1997&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;, 178-184.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Markowitsch, H. J., WeberLuxemburger, G., Ewald, K., Kessler, J., &amp;amp; Heiss, W. D. (1997). Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt;(2), 178-184.</apa>
<frontiers>Markowitsch, H. J., WeberLuxemburger, G., Ewald, K., Kessler, J., and Heiss, W. D. (1997). Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 4, 178-184.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Markowitsch, Hans J., WeberLuxemburger, G, Ewald, K, Kessler, J, and Heiss, WD. 1997. “Patients with heart attacks are not valid models for medial temporal lobe amnesia. A neuropsychological and FDG-PET study with consequences for memory research”. &lt;em&gt;EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 4 (2): 178-184.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1636862</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:14:00Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-12-16T09:59:18Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1636862</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1636862</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
