<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Farhard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Faisal</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">40255</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">U</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schwengelbeck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Physik</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10028</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>AG Theoretische Atom-, Molekül- und Laserphysik</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">23470672</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">A recently developed unified theory of classical and quantum chaos, based on the de Broglie-Bohm (Hamilton-Jacobi) formulation of quantum mechanics is presented and its consequences are discussed. The quantum dynamics is rigorously defined to be chaotic if the Lyapunov number, associated with the quantum trajectories in de Broglie-Bohm phase space, is positive definite. This definition of quantum chaos which under classical conditions goes over to the well-known definition of classical chaos in terms of positivity of Lyapunov numbers, provides a rigorous unified definition of chaos on the same footing for both the dynamics. A demonstration of the existence of positive Lyapunov numbers in a simple quantum system is given analytically, proving the existence of quantum chaos. Breaking of the time-reversal symmetry in the corresponding quantum dynamics under chaotic evolution is demonstrated. It is shown that the rigorous deterministic quantum chaos provides an intrinsic mechanism towards irreversibility of the Schrodinger evolution of the wave function, without invoking &apos;wave function collapse&apos; or &apos;measurements&apos;.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1998</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>de Broglie Bohm quantum mechanics</topic><topic>time-reversal invariance</topic><topic>Lyapunov numbers</topic><topic>quantum chaos</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0304-4289</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000078009400005</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/BF02827450</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>51</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>5</number></detail><extent unit="pages">585-595</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<aps>F.  Faisal and U.  Schwengelbeck, de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance, in &lt;em&gt;PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;51&lt;/strong&gt; (INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES, 1998), p. 585-595.</aps>
<bio1>Faisal F, Schwengelbeck U (1998) &lt;br /&gt;de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance. &lt;br /&gt;In:  PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS. 51. INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES:  585-595.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Faisal, F. &amp;amp; Schwengelbeck, U. (1998). de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance. &lt;em&gt;PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt; (S. 585-595). INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES. doi:10.1007/BF02827450.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Faisal F, Schwengelbeck U. de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance. In:  &lt;em&gt;PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 51. INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES;  1998: 585-595.</ama>
<harvard1>Faisal, F., &amp;amp; Schwengelbeck, U., 1998. de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance. In &lt;em&gt;PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;. no.51  INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES, pp. 585-595.</harvard1>
<default>Faisal F, Schwengelbeck U (1998)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS. 51. INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES:  585-595.</default>
<wels>Faisal, F.; Schwengelbeck, U. (1998): de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance. In: PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS. INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES. (51).  S. 585-595.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Faisal, F., &amp;amp; Schwengelbeck, U. (1998). de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance. &lt;em&gt;PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;51&lt;/em&gt;(5), 585-595.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Faisal, Farhard, and Schwengelbeck, U. “de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance”. &lt;em&gt;PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;. INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES, 1998.Vol. 51. 585-595.</mla>
<lncs>Faisal, F., Schwengelbeck, U.: de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance. PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS. 51, p. 585-595. INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES (1998).</lncs>
<ieee>F. Faisal and U. Schwengelbeck, “de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance”, &lt;em&gt;PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 51, INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES, 1998,  pp.585-595.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Faisal, Farhard, and Schwengelbeck, U. 1998. “de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance”. In &lt;em&gt;PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, 51:585-595. INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Faisal, F., and Schwengelbeck, U. (1998). “de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance” in &lt;em&gt;PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 51, (INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES), 585-595.</frontiers>
<apa>Faisal, F., &amp;amp; Schwengelbeck, U. (1998). de Broglie-Bohm formulation of quantum mechanics, quantum chaos and breaking of time-reversal invariance. &lt;em&gt;PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;51&lt;/em&gt;(5), 585-595.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>F.  Faisal, and U.  Schwengelbeck, in &lt;em&gt;PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS&lt;/em&gt;, Indian Academy Sciences, &lt;strong&gt;1998&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 585-595.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1623705</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:06:13Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-04T10:03:48Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1623705</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1623705</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
