<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christiane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Werner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22053</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7676-9057</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Nils</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hasenbein</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rodrigo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Maia</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wolfram</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Beyschlag</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21931</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Cristina</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Maguas</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2685201</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Recent insights into fractionation during dark respiration and rapid dynamics in isotope signatures of leaf- and ecosystem-respired CO2 indicate the need for new methods for high time-resolved measurements of the isotopic signature of respired CO2 (delta C-13(res)). We present a rapid and simple method to analyse delta C-13(res) using an in-tube incubation technique and an autosampler for small septum-capped vials. The effect of storage on the delta O-18 and delta C-13 ratios of ambient CO2 concentrations was tested with different humidity and temperatures. delta C-13 ratios remained stable over 72 h, whereas delta O-18 ratios decreased after 24 h. Storage at VC improved the storage time for delta O-18. Leaves or leaf discs were incubated in the vials, flushed with CO2-free air and respired CO2 was automatically sampled within 5 min on a mu Gas autosampler interfaced to a GV-Isoprime isotope ratio mass spectrometer. Results were validated by simultaneous on-line gas-exchange measurements of delta C-13(res) of attached leaves. This method was used to evaluate the short-term (5-60 min) and diurnal dynamics of delta C-13(res) in an evergreen oak (Quercus ilex) and a herb (Tolpis barbata). An immediate depletion of 2-4 parts per thousand from the initial delta C-13(res) value occurred during the first 30 min of darkening. Q. ilex exhibited further a substantial diurnal enrichment in delta C-13(res) of 8 parts per thousand, followed by a progressive depletion during the night. In contrast, T. barbata did not exhibit a distinct diurnal pattern. This is in accordance with recent theory on fractionation in metabolic pathways and may be related to the different utilisation of the respiratory substrate in the fast-growing herb and the evergreen oak. These data indicate substantial and rapid dynamics (within minutes to hours) in delta C-13(res), which differed between species and probably the growth status of the plant. The in-tube incubation method enables both high time-resolved analysis and extensive sampling across different organs, species and functional types. Copyright (C) 2007 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0951-4198</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1097-0231</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">17348086</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000245915700002</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/rcm.2970</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>21</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>8</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1352-1360</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<angewandte-chemie>C.  Werner, N.  Hasenbein, R.  Maia, W.  Beyschlag, and C.  Maguas, “Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique”, &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;, 1352-1360.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Werner, C., Hasenbein, N., Maia, R., Beyschlag, W., &amp;amp; Maguas, C. (2007). Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;(8), 1352-1360.</apa>
<frontiers>Werner, C., Hasenbein, N., Maia, R., Beyschlag, W., and Maguas, C. (2007). Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt; 21, 1352-1360.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Werner, Christiane, Hasenbein, Nils, Maia, Rodrigo, Beyschlag, Wolfram, and Maguas, Cristina. 2007. “Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique”. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt; 21 (8): 1352-1360.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee> C. Werner, et al., “Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique”, &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 21, 2007,  pp. 1352-1360.</ieee>
<mla>Werner, Christiane, Hasenbein, Nils, Maia, Rodrigo, Beyschlag, Wolfram, and Maguas, Cristina. “Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique”. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt; 21.8 (2007): 1352-1360.</mla>
<lncs> Werner, C., Hasenbein, N., Maia, R., Beyschlag, W., Maguas, C.: Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique. RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY. 21, 1352-1360 (2007).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Werner, C., Hasenbein, N., Maia, R., Beyschlag, W., &amp;amp; Maguas, C. (2007). Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;(8), 1352-1360.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Werner, C.; Hasenbein, N.; Maia, R.; Beyschlag, W.; Maguas, C. (2007): Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;,21:(8): 1352-1360.</wels>
<default>Werner C, Hasenbein N, Maia R, Beyschlag W, Maguas C (2007) &lt;br /&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY 21(8): 1352-1360.</default>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Werner, C., Hasenbein, N., Maia, R., Beyschlag, W. &amp;amp; Maguas, C. (2007). Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;21&lt;/em&gt;(8), 1352-1360. JOHN WILEY &amp;amp; SONS LTD. doi:10.1002/rcm.2970.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Werner, C., et al., 2007. Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;, 21(8), p 1352-1360.</harvard1>
<ama>Werner C, Hasenbein N, Maia R, Beyschlag W, Maguas C. Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique. &lt;em&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY&lt;/em&gt;. 2007;21(8):1352-1360.</ama>
<aps> C.  Werner, et al., Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique, RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY &lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt;, 1352-1360 (2007).</aps>
<bio1>Werner C, Hasenbein N, Maia R, Beyschlag W, Maguas C (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Evaluating high time-resolved changes in carbon isotope ratio of respired CO2 by a rapid in-tube incubation technique.&lt;br /&gt;RAPID COMMUNICATIONS IN MASS SPECTROMETRY 21(8): 1352-1360.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1594065</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:16:09Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-10-18T09:57:12Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1594065</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1594065</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
