<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Küster</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">HJ</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Quandt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">I</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Broer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">AM</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Perlick</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pühler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21937</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Biologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">We recently reported on the broad bean gene VfENOD-GRP3 encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin. This gene was predominantly expressed in the interzone II-III region of Vicia faba root nodules. The VfENOD-GRP3 promoter contained several sequence motifs potentially involved in the regulation of gene expression. To investigate the molecular basis for the specific VfENOD-GRP3 expression, defined VfENOD-GRP3 promoter fragments were fused to an intron-containing gusAint gene. Agrobacterium rhizogenes ARqual strains carrying these fusions integrated into the TL DNA were used to generate hairy roots on Vicia hirsuta, which subsequently were nodulated. Histochemical analysis of transgenic nodules indicated that a strong gusAint expression in the interzone II-III region was mediated by the -1252/+10 VfENOD-GRP3 promoter region. This reporter gene expression in V. hirsuta was comparable to the location of VfENOD-GRP3 transcripts in V. faba nodules. An analysis of defined promoter fragments revealed that a strong gusAint expression in the interzone II-III region was also mediated by the -737/+10 promoter, whereas the -239/+10 promoter only mediated a weak gusAint expression in the interzone II-III region. Since the -239/+10 promoter fragment did not resemble published nodulin gene promoters, we propose that it contains new sequence motifs involved in mediating gene expression in the interzone II-III region of Vicia nodules.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>KLUWER ACADEMIC PUBL</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1995</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>interzone II-III predominant expression</topic><topic>TL</topic><topic>glycine-rich early nodulin</topic><topic>DNA integration vector</topic><topic>Vicia hirsuta</topic><topic>transgenic root nodules</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0167-4412</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1573-5028</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">8541502</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1995TL29900013</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/BF00041166</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>29</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>4</number></detail><extent unit="pages">759-772</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Küster, H., Quandt, H. J., Broer, I., Perlick, A. M., &amp;amp; Pühler, A. (1995). The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules. &lt;em&gt;PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;(4), 759-772.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>H. Küster, et al., “The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules”, &lt;em&gt;PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 29, 1995,  pp. 759-772.</ieee>
<lncs>Küster, H., Quandt, H.J., Broer, I., Perlick, A.M., Pühler, A.: The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules. PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY. 29, 759-772 (1995).</lncs>
<mla>Küster, Helge, Quandt, HJ, Broer, I, Perlick, AM, and Pühler, Alfred. “The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules”. &lt;em&gt;PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 29.4 (1995): 759-772.</mla>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Küster, Helge, Quandt, HJ, Broer, I, Perlick, AM, and Pühler, Alfred. 1995. “The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules”. &lt;em&gt;PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 29 (4): 759-772.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Küster, H. J.  Quandt, I.  Broer, A. M.  Perlick, and A.  Pühler, “The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules”, &lt;em&gt;PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1995&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;, 759-772.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Küster, H., Quandt, H. J., Broer, I., Perlick, A. M., &amp;amp; Pühler, A. (1995). The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules. &lt;em&gt;PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;(4), 759-772.</apa>
<frontiers>Küster, H., Quandt, H. J., Broer, I., Perlick, A. M., and Pühler, A. (1995). The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules. &lt;em&gt;PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 29, 759-772.</frontiers>
<harvard1>Küster, H., et al., 1995. The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules. &lt;em&gt;PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 29(4), p 759-772.</harvard1>
<ama>Küster H, Quandt HJ, Broer I, Perlick AM, Pühler A. The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules. &lt;em&gt;PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. 1995;29(4):759-772.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Küster, H., Quandt, H.J., Broer, I., Perlick, A.M. &amp;amp; Pühler, A. (1995). The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules. &lt;em&gt;PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;29&lt;/em&gt;(4), 759-772. KLUWER ACADEMIC PUBL. doi:10.1007/BF00041166.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Küster H, Quandt HJ, Broer I, Perlick AM, Pühler A (1995) &lt;br /&gt;The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules.&lt;br /&gt;PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY 29(4): 759-772.</bio1>
<aps>H.  Küster, et al., The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules, PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY &lt;strong&gt;29&lt;/strong&gt;, 759-772 (1995).</aps>
<wels>Küster, H.; Quandt, H. J.; Broer, I.; Perlick, A. M.; Pühler, A. (1995): The promoter of the Vicia faba L VfENOD-GRP3 gene encoding a glycine-rich early nodulin mediates a predominant gene expression in the interzone II-III region of transgenic Vicia hirsuta root nodules &lt;em&gt;PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,29:(4): 759-772.</wels>
<default>Küster H, Quandt HJ, Broer I, Perlick AM, Pühler A (1995) &lt;br /&gt;PLANT MOLECULAR BIOLOGY 29(4): 759-772.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1629166</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:26:43Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-07-14T14:25:34Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1629166</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1629166</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
