<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Jokeit</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ebner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Holthausen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Markowitsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">59726756</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Moch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pannek</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">R</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schulz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">I</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tuxhorn</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Abteilung für Psychologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10026</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Prognostic variables for individual memory outcome after left anterior temporal lobectomy (ATL) were studied in 27 patients with refractory temporal lobe epilepsy. The difference between pre-and postoperative performance in the delayed recall of two prose passages (Story A and B) from the Wechsler Memory Scale served as measure of postoperative memory change. Fifteen independent clinical, neuropsychological, and electrophysiological variables were submitted to a multiple linear regression analysis. Preoperative immediate and delayed recall of story content and right hemisphere Wada memory performance for pictorial and verbal items explained very well postoperative memory changes in recall of Story B. Delayed recall of Story B, but not of Story A, had high concurrent validity to other measures of memory. Patients who became seizure-free did not differ in memory change from patients who continued to have seizures after ATL. The variables age at epilepsy onset and probable age at temporal lobe damage provided complementary information for individual prediction but with less effectiveness than Wada test data. Our model confirmed that good preoperative memory functioning and impaired right hemispheric Wada memory performance for pictorial items predict a high risk of memory loss after left ATL. The analyses demonstrate that the combination of independent measures delivers more information than Wada test performance or any other variable alone. The suggested function can be used routinely to estimate the individual severity of verbal episodic memory impairment that might occur after left-sided ATL and offers a rational basis for the counseling of patients.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>LIPPINCOTT-RAVEN PUBL</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1997</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>NEUROLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0028-3878</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">9270581</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1997XR93700027</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>49</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">481-487</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Jokeit H, Ebner A, Holthausen H, Markowitsch HJ, Moch A, Pannek H, Schulz R, Tuxhorn I (1997)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  NEUROLOGY. 49. LIPPINCOTT-RAVEN PUBL:  481-487.</default>
<wels>Jokeit, H.; Ebner, A.; Holthausen, H.; Markowitsch, H. J.; Moch, A.; Pannek, H.; Schulz, R.; Tuxhorn, I. (1997): Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy. In: NEUROLOGY. LIPPINCOTT-RAVEN PUBL. (49).  S. 481-487.</wels>
<bio1>Jokeit H, Ebner A, Holthausen H, Markowitsch HJ, Moch A, Pannek H, Schulz R, Tuxhorn I (1997) &lt;br /&gt;Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy. &lt;br /&gt;In:  NEUROLOGY. 49. LIPPINCOTT-RAVEN PUBL:  481-487.</bio1>
<aps>H.  Jokeit, et al., Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy, in &lt;em&gt;NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;49&lt;/strong&gt; (LIPPINCOTT-RAVEN PUBL, 1997), p. 481-487.</aps>
<ama>Jokeit H, Ebner A, Holthausen H, et al. Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy. In:  &lt;em&gt;NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 49. LIPPINCOTT-RAVEN PUBL;  1997: 481-487.</ama>
<harvard1>Jokeit, H., et al., 1997. Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy. In &lt;em&gt;NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. no.49  LIPPINCOTT-RAVEN PUBL, pp. 481-487.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Jokeit, H., Ebner, A., Holthausen, H., Markowitsch, H.J., Moch, A., Pannek, H., Schulz, R. &amp;amp; Tuxhorn, I. (1997). Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy. &lt;em&gt;NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt; (S. 481-487). LIPPINCOTT-RAVEN PUBL.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Jokeit, H, Ebner, A, Holthausen, H, Markowitsch, Hans J., Moch, A, Pannek, H, Schulz, R, and Tuxhorn, I. 1997. “Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy”. In &lt;em&gt;NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 49:481-487. LIPPINCOTT-RAVEN PUBL.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Jokeit, H., Ebner, A., Holthausen, H., Markowitsch, H. J., Moch, A., Pannek, H., Schulz, R., and Tuxhorn, I. (1997). “Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy” in &lt;em&gt;NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 49, (LIPPINCOTT-RAVEN PUBL), 481-487.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>H.  Jokeit, A.  Ebner, H.  Holthausen, H. J.  Markowitsch, A.  Moch, H.  Pannek, R.  Schulz, and I.  Tuxhorn, in &lt;em&gt;NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, Lippincott-Raven Publ, &lt;strong&gt;1997&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 481-487.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Jokeit, H., Ebner, A., Holthausen, H., Markowitsch, H. J., Moch, A., Pannek, H., Schulz, R., et al. (1997). Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy. &lt;em&gt;NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;49&lt;/em&gt;(2), 481-487.</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Jokeit, H., Ebner, A., Holthausen, H., Markowitsch, H. J., Moch, A., Pannek, H., Schulz, R., et al. (1997). Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy. &lt;em&gt;NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;49&lt;/em&gt;(2), 481-487.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs>Jokeit, H., Ebner, A., Holthausen, H., Markowitsch, H.J., Moch, A., Pannek, H., Schulz, R., Tuxhorn, I.: Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy. NEUROLOGY. 49, p. 481-487. LIPPINCOTT-RAVEN PUBL (1997).</lncs>
<mla>Jokeit, H, Ebner, A, Holthausen, H, Markowitsch, Hans J., Moch, A, Pannek, H, Schulz, R, and Tuxhorn, I. “Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy”. &lt;em&gt;NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. LIPPINCOTT-RAVEN PUBL, 1997.Vol. 49. 481-487.</mla>
<ieee>H. Jokeit, et al., “Individual prediction of change in delayed recall of prose passages after left-sided anterior temporal lobectomy”, &lt;em&gt;NEUROLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 49, LIPPINCOTT-RAVEN PUBL, 1997,  pp.481-487.</ieee>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1627635</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:22:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-01-05T16:04:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1627635</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1627635</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
