<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">P</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">BUDDE</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">N</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">BEWARDER</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">V</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">WEINRICH</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">O</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">SCHULZECK</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jürgen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Frey</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">20196</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Biochemie II</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17968</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Human B cells express two closely related immunoglobulin G receptors, FcRIIb1 and FcRIIb2, which differ by a 19 amino acid insertion in the cytoplasmic tail of FcRIIb1. The cytoplasmic tails of both isoforms contain a conserved sequence motif (AENTITYSLL) essential for mediating endocytosis via FcRIIb2. Truncation of this motif abolished endocytosis, while replacement of tyrosine (Tyr-(273)) in FcRIIba by phenylalanine had no effect on the amount and kinetics of ligand uptake. Co-crosslinking of FcRIIb1 or FcRIIb2 with the antigen receptor on B cells led to an abortive calcium signal. Neither isoform interfered with the early intracellular calcium mobilization, but both prevented the opening of a plasma membrane calcium channel essential for a sustained elevated intracellular calcium level. Modulation of calcium channel activity is mediated by the same sequence motif essential for endocytosis but requires the pres- ence of Tyr(292) in FcRIIb1 and Tyr(273) in, FcRIIb2. Co-crosslinking of FcRIIb1 with surface IgG is associated with tyrosine phosphorylation of Tyr(292), whereas Tyr(272) in FcRIIb2 was not phosphorylated. Thus, FcRIIb phosphorylation is probably not directly involved in the modulation of the calcium signal but may be essential for further diversification of signals transduced via the coexpressed isoforms FcRIIb1 and FcRIIb2.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>AMER SOC BIOCHEMISTRY MOLECULAR BIOLOGY INC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1994</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0021-9258</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">7527034</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1994PU52500091</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>269</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>48</number></detail><extent unit="pages">30636-30644</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;BUDDE, P, BEWARDER, N, WEINRICH, V, SCHULZECK, O, and Frey, Jürgen. 1994. “TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 269 (48): 30636-30644.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<angewandte-chemie>P.  BUDDE, N.  BEWARDER, V.  WEINRICH, O.  SCHULZECK, and J.  Frey, “TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1994&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;269&lt;/em&gt;, 30636-30644.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>BUDDE, P., BEWARDER, N., WEINRICH, V., SCHULZECK, O., &amp;amp; Frey, J. (1994). TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;269&lt;/em&gt;(48), 30636-30644.</apa>
<frontiers>BUDDE, P., BEWARDER, N., WEINRICH, V., SCHULZECK, O., and Frey, J. (1994). TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 269, 30636-30644.</frontiers>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;BUDDE, P., BEWARDER, N., WEINRICH, V., SCHULZECK, O., &amp;amp; Frey, J. (1994). TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;269&lt;/em&gt;(48), 30636-30644.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>P. BUDDE, et al., “TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 269, 1994,  pp. 30636-30644.</ieee>
<lncs>BUDDE, P., BEWARDER, N., WEINRICH, V., SCHULZECK, O., Frey, J.: TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS. JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY. 269, 30636-30644 (1994).</lncs>
<mla>BUDDE, P, BEWARDER, N, WEINRICH, V, SCHULZECK, O, and Frey, Jürgen. “TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 269.48 (1994): 30636-30644.</mla>
<wels>BUDDE, P.; BEWARDER, N.; WEINRICH, V.; SCHULZECK, O.; Frey, J. (1994): TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;,269:(48): 30636-30644.</wels>
<default>BUDDE P, BEWARDER N, WEINRICH V, SCHULZECK O, Frey J (1994) &lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY 269(48): 30636-30644.</default>
<ama>BUDDE P, BEWARDER N, WEINRICH V, SCHULZECK O, Frey J. TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;. 1994;269(48):30636-30644.</ama>
<harvard1>BUDDE, P., et al., 1994. TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, 269(48), p 30636-30644.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;BUDDE, P., BEWARDER, N., WEINRICH, V., SCHULZECK, O. &amp;amp; Frey, J. (1994). TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;269&lt;/em&gt;(48), 30636-30644. AMER SOC BIOCHEMISTRY MOLECULAR BIOLOGY INC.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<aps>P.  BUDDE, et al., TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS, JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY &lt;strong&gt;269&lt;/strong&gt;, 30636-30644 (1994).</aps>
<bio1>BUDDE P, BEWARDER N, WEINRICH V, SCHULZECK O, Frey J (1994) &lt;br /&gt;TYROSINE-CONTAINING SEQUENCE MOTIFS OF THE HUMAN-IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G RECEPTORS FCRIIB1 AND FCRIIB2 ESSENTIAL FOR ENDOCYTOSIS AND REGULATION OF CALCIUM FLUX IN B-CELLS.&lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY 269(48): 30636-30644.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1642066</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:27:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-11-08T10:23:31Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1642066</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1642066</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
