<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Werner</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Selbitschka</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22010</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pühler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21937</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">R.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Simon</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Biologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">A vector system was developed employing the recA genes of Rhizobium meliloti and Rhizobiurn leguminosarum biovar. viciae as target sequences for the stable genomic integration of foreign DNA. The plasmid vectors can be used either as integration vectors (single cross-over), or as gene replacement vectors (double cross-over). Gene replacement results in the antibiotic-marker-free integration of cloned DNA into the recA genes of R. meliloti and R. leguminosarum bv. viciae. Consequently, the recombinant strains become recombination deficient (RecA(-)). The expression of integrated genes is under the control of the neomycin phosphotransferase II (nptII) promoter of transposon Tn5. The system was used to construct recA mutant strains of R. meliloti and R. leguminosarum bv. viciae, carrying the Escherichia coli gusA gene encoding beta-glucuronidase as well as the firefly (Photinus pyralis) luc gene encoding luciferase as marker genes. The GUS activity in the constructed strains was found to be absolutely stable over more than 100 generations of non-selective growth in liquid culture. The stability was also confirmed in root-nodule passages. In addition, the potential use of the luc gene as a stable genetic marker in the unequivocal identification of tagged strains among indigenous microbes in non-sterile soil was demonstrated. It is proposed to use bioluminescent recA mutants as model organisms in risk assessment studies with genetically engineered Rhizobium strains.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL PUBLISHING, INC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1992</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>luciferase</topic><topic>recA</topic><topic>Rhizobium</topic><topic>meliloti</topic><topic>Rhizobium leguminosarum biovar. viciae</topic><topic>beta-glucuronidase</topic><topic>integration vector</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>MOLECULAR ECOLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0962-1083</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1365-294X</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000003907500003</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1111/j.1365-294X.1992.tb00150.x</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>1</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">9-19</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee>W. Selbitschka, A. Pühler, and R. Simon, “The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies”, &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 1, 1992,  pp. 9-19.</ieee>
<mla>Selbitschka, Werner, Pühler, Alfred, and Simon, R. “The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies”. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 1.1 (1992): 9-19.</mla>
<lncs>Selbitschka, W., Pühler, A., Simon, R.: The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies. MOLECULAR ECOLOGY. 1, 9-19 (1992).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Selbitschka, W., Pühler, A., &amp;amp; Simon, R. (1992). The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;(1), 9-19.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<apa>Selbitschka, W., Pühler, A., &amp;amp; Simon, R. (1992). The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;(1), 9-19.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>W.  Selbitschka, A.  Pühler, and R.  Simon, “The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies”, &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1992&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;, 9-19.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Selbitschka, W., Pühler, A., and Simon, R. (1992). The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 1, 9-19.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Selbitschka, Werner, Pühler, Alfred, and Simon, R. 1992. “The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies”. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 1 (1): 9-19.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<harvard1>Selbitschka, W., Pühler, A., &amp;amp; Simon, R., 1992. The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 1(1), p 9-19.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Selbitschka, W., Pühler, A. &amp;amp; Simon, R. (1992). The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;(1), 9-19. WILEY-BLACKWELL PUBLISHING, INC. doi:10.1111/j.1365-294X.1992.tb00150.x.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Selbitschka W, Pühler A, Simon R. The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies. &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. 1992;1(1):9-19.</ama>
<aps>W.  Selbitschka, A.  Pühler, and R.  Simon, The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies, MOLECULAR ECOLOGY &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;, 9-19 (1992).</aps>
<bio1>Selbitschka W, Pühler A, Simon R (1992) &lt;br /&gt;The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies.&lt;br /&gt;MOLECULAR ECOLOGY 1(1): 9-19.</bio1>
<wels>Selbitschka, W.; Pühler, A.; Simon, R. (1992): The construction of recA-deficient Rhizobium meliloti and R. leguminosarum strains marked with gusA or luc cassettes for use in risk-assessment studies &lt;em&gt;MOLECULAR ECOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,1:(1): 9-19.</wels>
<default>Selbitschka W, Pühler A, Simon R (1992) &lt;br /&gt;MOLECULAR ECOLOGY 1(1): 9-19.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1629777</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:28:47Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-09T10:17:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1629777</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1629777</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
