<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Julia</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Beckmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">3654622</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">F.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lehr</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">G.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Finazzi</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">B.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hankamer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">C.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Posten</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Lutz</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wobbe</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">3654602</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Olaf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kruse</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22124</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Research Group  O. Kruse</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">33086312</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Institut für Biochemie und Biotechnik</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">4838684</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Algenbiotechnologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">4833667</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The efficient use of microalgae to convert sun light energy into biomass is limited by losses during high light illumination of dense cell cultures in closed bioreactors. Uneven light distribution can be overcome by using cell cultures with smaller antenna sizes packed to high cell density cultures, thus allowing good light penetration into the inner sections of the reactor. We engineered a new small PSII antenna size Chlamydomonas reinhardtii strain with improved photon conversion efficiency and increased growth rates under high light conditions. We achieved this goal by transformation of a permanently active variant NAB1* of the LHC translation repressor NAB1* to reduce antenna size via translation repression. NAB1* expression was demonstrated in Stm6Glc477(T7), leading to a reduction of LHC antenna size by 10-17%. T7 showed a similar to 50% increase of photosynthetic efficiency (Phi PSII) at saturating light intensity compared to the parental strain. T7 converted light to biomass with much higher efficiencies with a similar to 50% improved mid log growth phase. Moreover, T7 cultures reached higher densities when grown in large-scale bioreactors. Thus, the phenotype of strain T7 may have important implications for biotechnological applications in which photosynthetic microalgae are used for large-scale culturing as an alternative plant biomass source. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>Reinhardtii</topic><topic>Bioreactor</topic><topic>Translation repression</topic><topic>Biomass</topic><topic>Light harvesting</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0168-1656</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">19480949</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000267452700010</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/j.jbiotec.2009.02.015</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>142</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">70-77</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<mla>Beckmann, Julia, Lehr, F., Finazzi, G., Hankamer, B., Posten, C., Wobbe, Lutz, and Kruse, Olaf. “Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV, 2009.Vol. 142. 70-77.</mla>
<lncs>Beckmann, J., Lehr, F., Finazzi, G., Hankamer, B., Posten, C., Wobbe, L., Kruse, O.: Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii. JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY. 142, p. 70-77. ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV (2009).</lncs>
<ieee>J. Beckmann, et al., “Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 142, ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV, 2009,  pp.70-77.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Beckmann, J., Lehr, F., Finazzi, G., Hankamer, B., Posten, C., Wobbe, L., &amp;amp; Kruse, O. (2009). Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;142&lt;/em&gt;(1), 70-77.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<frontiers>Beckmann, J., Lehr, F., Finazzi, G., Hankamer, B., Posten, C., Wobbe, L., and Kruse, O. (2009). “Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii” in &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 142, (ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV), 70-77.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Beckmann, F.  Lehr, G.  Finazzi, B.  Hankamer, C.  Posten, L.  Wobbe, and O.  Kruse, in &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, Elsevier Science Bv, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 70-77.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Beckmann, J., Lehr, F., Finazzi, G., Hankamer, B., Posten, C., Wobbe, L., &amp;amp; Kruse, O. (2009). Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;142&lt;/em&gt;(1), 70-77.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Beckmann, Julia, Lehr, F., Finazzi, G., Hankamer, B., Posten, C., Wobbe, Lutz, and Kruse, Olaf. 2009. “Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii”. In &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 142:70-77. ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<bio1>Beckmann J, Lehr F, Finazzi G, Hankamer B, Posten C, Wobbe L, Kruse O (2009) &lt;br /&gt;Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii. &lt;br /&gt;In:  JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY. 142. ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV:  70-77.</bio1>
<aps>J.  Beckmann, et al., Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii, in &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;142&lt;/strong&gt; (ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV, 2009), p. 70-77.</aps>
<ama>Beckmann J, Lehr F, Finazzi G, et al. Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii. In:  &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 142. ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV;  2009: 70-77.</ama>
<harvard1>Beckmann, J., et al., 2009. Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii. In &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. no.142  ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV, pp. 70-77.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Beckmann, J., Lehr, F., Finazzi, G., Hankamer, B., Posten, C., Wobbe, L. &amp;amp; Kruse, O. (2009). Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; (S. 70-77). ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV. doi:10.1016/j.jbiotec.2009.02.015.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Beckmann J, Lehr F, Finazzi G, Hankamer B, Posten C, Wobbe L, Kruse O (2009)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY. 142. ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV:  70-77.</default>
<wels>Beckmann, J.; Lehr, F.; Finazzi, G.; Hankamer, B.; Posten, C.; Wobbe, L.; Kruse, O. (2009): Improvement of light to biomass conversion by de-regulation of light-harvesting protein translation in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii. In: JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY. ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV. (142).  S. 70-77.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1591857</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-26T09:46:03Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-20T12:30:08Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1591857</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1591857</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
