<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vasilache</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">9367332</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">José Luis</namePart><namePart type="family">de Sales Marques</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Reimund</namePart><namePart type="family">Seidelmann</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart><namePart type="family">Vasilache</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">89044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">5656050</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>Nomos</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2009</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">978-3-8329-3960-1</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">59-77</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Vasilache A (2009)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues. de Sales Marques JL, Seidelmann  R, Vasilache A (Eds);Baden-Baden: Nomos:  59-77.</default>
<wels>Vasilache, A. (2009): The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion. In: José Luis de Sales Marques; Reimund Seidelmann; Andreas Vasilache (Hrsg.):  Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues. Baden-Baden: Nomos.  S. 59-77.</wels>
<bio1>Vasilache A (2009) &lt;br /&gt;The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues. de Sales Marques JL, Seidelmann  R, Vasilache A (Eds); Baden-Baden: Nomos:  59-77.</bio1>
<aps>A.  Vasilache, The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion, in &lt;em&gt;Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues&lt;/em&gt;, edited by J. L.  de Sales Marques, et al. (Nomos, Baden-Baden, 2009), p. 59-77.</aps>
<ama>Vasilache A. The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion. In: de Sales Marques JL, Seidelmann  R, Vasilache A, eds. &lt;em&gt;Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues&lt;/em&gt;. Baden-Baden: Nomos;  2009: 59-77.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Vasilache, A. (2009). The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion. &lt;em&gt;Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues&lt;/em&gt; (S. 59-77). Baden-Baden: Nomos.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Vasilache, A., 2009. The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion. In J. L.  de Sales Marques, R.  Seidelmann, &amp;amp; A.  Vasilache, eds. &lt;em&gt;Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues&lt;/em&gt;.  Baden-Baden: Nomos, pp. 59-77.</harvard1>
<frontiers>Vasilache, A. (2009). “The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion” in &lt;em&gt;Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues&lt;/em&gt;, ed. J. L.  de Sales Marques, R.  Seidelmann, and A.  Vasilache (Baden-Baden: Nomos), 59-77.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Vasilache, in &lt;em&gt;Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J.L. de Sales Marques, R. Seidelmann, A. Vasilache), Nomos, Baden-Baden, &lt;strong&gt;2009&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 59-77.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Vasilache, A. (2009). The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion. In J. L.  de Sales Marques, R.  Seidelmann, &amp;amp; A.  Vasilache (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 59-77). Baden-Baden: Nomos.</apa>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Vasilache, Andreas. 2009. “The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion”. In &lt;em&gt;Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues&lt;/em&gt;, ed. José Luis de Sales Marques, Reimund Seidelmann, and Andreas Vasilache, 59-77. Baden-Baden: Nomos.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs>Vasilache, A.: The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion. In: de Sales Marques, J.L., Seidelmann , R., and Vasilache, A. (eds.) Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues. p. 59-77. Nomos, Baden-Baden (2009).</lncs>
<mla>Vasilache, Andreas. “The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion”. &lt;em&gt;Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. José Luis de Sales Marques, Reimund Seidelmann, and Andreas Vasilache. Baden-Baden: Nomos, 2009. 59-77.</mla>
<ieee>A. Vasilache, “The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion”, &lt;em&gt;Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues&lt;/em&gt;, J.L. de Sales Marques, R. Seidelmann, and A. Vasilache, eds.,  Baden-Baden: Nomos, 2009,  pp.59-77.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Vasilache, A. (2009). The Normative and Analytical Limits of Governance. A Conceptual Intervention and a Poststructuralist Suggestion. In J. L.  de Sales Marques, R.  Seidelmann, &amp;amp; A.  Vasilache (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Asia and Europe. Dynamics of Inter- and Intra-Regional Dialogues&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 59-77). Baden-Baden: Nomos.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1858421</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-02-05T13:13:11Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-05-20T22:09:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1858421</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1858421</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
