<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Andreas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tauch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22082</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">S</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Götker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pühler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21937</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jörn</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kalinowski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">147567</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">G</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Thierbach</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The potential of the alanine racemase gene alr from Corynebacterium glutamicum ATCC 13032 to substitute for antibiotic resistance determinants in cloning systems has been investigated. The alr gene was identified by a PCR technique and its nucleotide sequence was determined. The deduced protein revealed the highest amino acid sequence similarity to the Alr protein from Mycobacterium smegmatis with 45% identical and 58% similar amino acids. A defined alr deletion mutant of C. glutamicum displayed a strict dependence on the presence of D-alanine for growth on complex and minimal medium. The alr gene was placed on a novel C. glutamicum vector which is completely free of antibiotic resistance genes. In vivo complementation of the chromosomal alr deletion with alr-carrying vectors permitted growth of the mutant strain in the absence of external D-alanine and provided strong selective pressure to maintain the plasmid. The alr gene enabled the selection of C. glutamicum transformants with a similar efficiency as the tetracycline resistance gene tetA (33). These data provided experimental evidence that the alr gene can be applied as an alternative selection marker to antibiotic resistance genes in industrial C. glutamicum strains. In an application example, the novel Deltaalr host-alr(+) vector-system for C. glutamicum was used to overproduce the vitamin D-pantothenic acid. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2002</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>alanine racemase</topic><topic>Corynebacterium glutamicum</topic><topic>self-cloning</topic><topic>pantothenate production</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0168-1656</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">12204559</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000178484900006</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/S0168-1656(02)00159-1</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>99</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail><extent unit="pages">79-91</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Tauch, A., Götker, S., Pühler, A., Kalinowski, J., &amp;amp; Thierbach, G. (2002). The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;99&lt;/em&gt;(1), 79-91.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Tauch, S.  Götker, A.  Pühler, J.  Kalinowski, and G.  Thierbach, “The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;99&lt;/em&gt;, 79-91.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Tauch, A., Götker, S., Pühler, A., Kalinowski, J., and Thierbach, G. (2002). The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 99, 79-91.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tauch, Andreas, Götker, S, Pühler, Alfred, Kalinowski, Jörn, and Thierbach, G. 2002. “The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 99 (1): 79-91.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee> A. Tauch, et al., “The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 99, 2002,  pp. 79-91.</ieee>
<lncs> Tauch, A., Götker, S., Pühler, A., Kalinowski, J., Thierbach, G.: The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains. JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY. 99, 79-91 (2002).</lncs>
<mla>Tauch, Andreas, Götker, S, Pühler, Alfred, Kalinowski, Jörn, and Thierbach, G. “The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 99.1 (2002): 79-91.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tauch, A., Götker, S., Pühler, A., Kalinowski, J., &amp;amp; Thierbach, G. (2002). The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;99&lt;/em&gt;(1), 79-91.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Tauch, A.; Götker, S.; Pühler, A.; Kalinowski, J.; Thierbach, G. (2002): The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,99:(1): 79-91.</wels>
<default>Tauch A, Götker S, Pühler A, Kalinowski J, Thierbach G (2002) &lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY 99(1): 79-91.</default>
<harvard1>Tauch, A., et al., 2002. The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 99(1), p 79-91.</harvard1>
<ama>Tauch A, Götker S, Pühler A, Kalinowski J, Thierbach G. The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. 2002;99(1):79-91.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Tauch, A., Götker, S., Pühler, A., Kalinowski, J. &amp;amp; Thierbach, G. (2002). The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;99&lt;/em&gt;(1), 79-91. ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV. doi:10.1016/S0168-1656(02)00159-1.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Tauch A, Götker S, Pühler A, Kalinowski J, Thierbach G (2002) &lt;br /&gt;The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains.&lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY 99(1): 79-91.</bio1>
<aps> A.  Tauch, et al., The alanine racemase gene alr is an alternative to antibiotic resistance genes in cloning systems for industrial Corynebacterium glutamicum strains, JOURNAL OF BIOTECHNOLOGY &lt;strong&gt;99&lt;/strong&gt;, 79-91 (2002).</aps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1613526</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:00:40Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-09-21T12:12:05Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1613526</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1613526</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
