<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Number line representations of fractions</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Merlyn J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Behr</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">George W.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bright</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">73476</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Sigrid</namePart><namePart type="family">Wagner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Technische Fakultät</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>AG Wissensbasierte Systeme</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The study explored students&apos; interpretations of representations of fractions on number lines and the effect of instruction on those interpretations. Subjects were five fourth-graders, and instruction was a four-day unit on the use of number lines. A 16-item, multiple-choice pre- and posttest was used along with videotaped interviews. Performance improved except when students had to associate a reduced fraction symbol with an equivalent, unreduced fraction representation on a number line. The difficulty at &apos;&apos;unpartitioning&apos;&apos; a representation suggests that care needs to be given to developing a concept of equivalent fractions. Further, translations among various models of fraction might foster better performance.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Wachsmuth_67.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1779321/2312658</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription><accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Univ. of Georgia</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1982</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education</title></titleInfo><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-18332</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">106-112</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Behr MJ, Bright GW, Wachsmuth I (1982)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Wagner S (Ed);Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia:  106-112.</default>
<wels>Behr, M. J.; Bright, G. W.; Wachsmuth, I. (1982): Number line representations of fractions. In: Sigrid Wagner (Hrsg.):  Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia.  S. 106-112.</wels>
<bio1>Behr MJ, Bright GW, Wachsmuth I (1982) &lt;br /&gt;Number line representations of fractions. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. Wagner S (Ed); Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia:  106-112.</bio1>
<aps>M. J.  Behr, G. W.  Bright, and I.  Wachsmuth, Number line representations of fractions, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, edited by S.  Wagner (Univ. of Georgia, Athens, Ga., 1982), p. 106-112.</aps>
<ama>Behr MJ, Bright GW, Wachsmuth I. Number line representations of fractions. In: Wagner S, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;. Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia;  1982: 106-112.</ama>
<harvard1>Behr, M.J., Bright, G.W., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 1982. Number line representations of fractions. In S.  Wagner, ed. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;.  Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia, pp. 106-112.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Behr, M.J., Bright, G.W. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1982). Number line representations of fractions. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (S. 106-112). Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<frontiers>Behr, M. J., Bright, G. W., and Wachsmuth, I. (1982). “Number line representations of fractions” in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, ed. S.  Wagner (Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia), 106-112.</frontiers>
<apa>Behr, M. J., Bright, G. W., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1982). Number line representations of fractions. In S.  Wagner (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 106-112). Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>M. J.  Behr, G. W.  Bright, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: S. Wagner), Univ. Of Georgia, Athens, Ga., &lt;strong&gt;1982&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 106-112.</angewandte-chemie>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Behr, Merlyn J., Bright, George W., and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1982. “Number line representations of fractions”. In &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Sigrid Wagner, 106-112. Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs>Behr, M.J., Bright, G.W., Wachsmuth, I.: Number line representations of fractions. In: Wagner, S. (ed.) Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education. p. 106-112. Univ. of Georgia, Athens, Ga. (1982).</lncs>
<mla>Behr, Merlyn J., Bright, George W., and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Number line representations of fractions”. &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Sigrid Wagner. Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia, 1982. 106-112.</mla>
<ieee>M.J. Behr, G.W. Bright, and I. Wachsmuth, “Number line representations of fractions”, &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt;, S. Wagner, ed.,  Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia, 1982,  pp.106-112.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Behr, M. J., Bright, G. W., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1982). Number line representations of fractions. In S.  Wagner (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the North American Chapter of the International Group for the Psychology of Mathematics Education&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 106-112). Athens, Ga.: Univ. of Georgia.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1779321</recordIdentifier><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-11-18T22:06:34Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1779321</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1779321</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
