<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Udo</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Werner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">111104</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">VN</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kondratyev</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hans Otto</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lutz</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">40149</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>AG Physik supramolekularer Systeme und Oberflächen</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">29103248</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The multiple ionization and fragmentation of small polyatomic molecules and clusters, e.g. H2O, CH4, and C-60 by fast H+, He+, and Oq+ ions were studied utilizing a position-and time-sensitive multiparticle detector which allows the coincident measurement of the momenta of correlated fragments. Thereby, a kinematically complete image of the molecular break-up can be derived for each individual event. Of special interest are the &quot;Coulomb explosion&quot; processes, like H2O --&gt; H++H++Oq+ where the measured dissociation energies and angular correlations show significant deviations from the pure Coulomb explosion model. For larger molecules and clusters, new phenomena may be expected. For example, using a classical molecular dynamics simulation, we have studied the break-up of hot Ar-n (n greater than or equal to 100) clusters. For initial temperatures around 500 K various analytical tools consistently indicate critical behaviour in the expansion phase.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>EDITRICE COMPOSITORI BOLOGNA</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1997</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0369-3546</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000073184000043</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1007/BF03035966</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>110</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>9-10</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1215-1222</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee>U. Werner, V.N. Kondratyev, and H.O. Lutz, “Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters”, &lt;em&gt;NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 110, EDITRICE COMPOSITORI BOLOGNA, 1997,  pp.1215-1222.</ieee>
<lncs>Werner, U., Kondratyev, V.N., Lutz, H.O.: Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters. NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS. 110, p. 1215-1222. EDITRICE COMPOSITORI BOLOGNA (1997).</lncs>
<mla>Werner, Udo, Kondratyev, VN, and Lutz, Hans Otto. “Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters”. &lt;em&gt;NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS&lt;/em&gt;. EDITRICE COMPOSITORI BOLOGNA, 1997.Vol. 110. 1215-1222.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Werner, U., Kondratyev, V. N., &amp;amp; Lutz, H. O. (1997). Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters. &lt;em&gt;NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;110&lt;/em&gt;(9-10), 1215-1222.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>U.  Werner, V. N.  Kondratyev, and H. O.  Lutz, in &lt;em&gt;NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS&lt;/em&gt;, Editrice Compositori Bologna, &lt;strong&gt;1997&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 1215-1222.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Werner, U., Kondratyev, V. N., &amp;amp; Lutz, H. O. (1997). Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters. &lt;em&gt;NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;110&lt;/em&gt;(9-10), 1215-1222.</apa>
<frontiers>Werner, U., Kondratyev, V. N., and Lutz, H. O. (1997). “Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters” in &lt;em&gt;NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 110, (EDITRICE COMPOSITORI BOLOGNA), 1215-1222.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Werner, Udo, Kondratyev, VN, and Lutz, Hans Otto. 1997. “Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters”. In &lt;em&gt;NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS&lt;/em&gt;, 110:1215-1222. EDITRICE COMPOSITORI BOLOGNA.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<harvard1>Werner, U., Kondratyev, V.N., &amp;amp; Lutz, H.O., 1997. Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters. In &lt;em&gt;NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS&lt;/em&gt;. no.110  EDITRICE COMPOSITORI BOLOGNA, pp. 1215-1222.</harvard1>
<ama>Werner U, Kondratyev VN, Lutz HO. Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters. In:  &lt;em&gt;NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 110. EDITRICE COMPOSITORI BOLOGNA;  1997: 1215-1222.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Werner, U., Kondratyev, V.N. &amp;amp; Lutz, H.O. (1997). Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters. &lt;em&gt;NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS&lt;/em&gt; (S. 1215-1222). EDITRICE COMPOSITORI BOLOGNA. doi:10.1007/BF03035966.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Werner U, Kondratyev VN, Lutz HO (1997) &lt;br /&gt;Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters. &lt;br /&gt;In:  NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS. 110. EDITRICE COMPOSITORI BOLOGNA:  1215-1222.</bio1>
<aps>U.  Werner, V. N.  Kondratyev, and H. O.  Lutz, Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters, in &lt;em&gt;NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;110&lt;/strong&gt; (EDITRICE COMPOSITORI BOLOGNA, 1997), p. 1215-1222.</aps>
<wels>Werner, U.; Kondratyev, V. N.; Lutz, H. O. (1997): Multifragmentation of molecules and clusters. In: NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS. EDITRICE COMPOSITORI BOLOGNA. (110).  S. 1215-1222.</wels>
<default>Werner U, Kondratyev VN, Lutz HO (1997)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  NUOVO CIMENTO DELLA SOCIETA ITALIANA DI FISICA A-NUCLEI PARTICLES AND FIELDS. 110. EDITRICE COMPOSITORI BOLOGNA:  1215-1222.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1625726</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:20:49Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-03T11:44:36Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1625726</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1625726</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
