<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kanak</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Stobiecki</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">V.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Drewello</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Jan-Michael</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schmalhorst</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">40191</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Günter</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Reiss</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">40207</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-0918-5940</description></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>AG Dünne Schichten &amp; Physik der Nanostrukturen</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">28536538</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Research Group  G. Reiss</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">33079602</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Institut für Biophysik und Nanowissenschaften</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2161137</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The influence of seed-buffer layers on the texture and tunneling parameters was investigated. The spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions (SV-MTJs) were deposited onto thermally oxidized Si wafers by magnetron sputtering in the following sequence of layers: substrate Si(100)/SiO2 47 nm/buffer layers/Ir17Mn83 10 nm/CoFeB 3 nm/MgO 2 nm/CoFeB 4 nm/top layers. The following buffer systems have been used in order to induce different degree of the texture: (A) low textured buffer Cu 25 nm and (B) high textured buffer Ta 5 nm/Cu 25 nm. The type of buffer layers strongly influences the texture of IrMn anti-ferromagnetic layer and induces roughness of magnetic layers and MgO barrier. The highest TMR ratio 141 % was obtained for sample with small roughness annealed in vacuum at 350 degrees C. A strong influence of the roughness, due to the barrier thickness fluctuations, on the resistance-area product (RA) of the junctions is discussed. The Neel coupling field increases in case of high textured and rough layers and it becomes small for smooth interfaces. The proper design of the composition of the buffer layers allows to improve the magnetic and tunneling properties of MTJs. (c) 2007 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0031-8965</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000252309600007</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/pssa.200777107</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>204</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>12</number></detail><extent unit="pages">3942-3945</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Kanak J, Stobiecki T, Drewello V, Schmalhorst J-M, Reiss G (2007)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE. 204. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH:  3942-3945.</default>
<wels>Kanak, J.; Stobiecki, T.; Drewello, V.; Schmalhorst, J. - M.; Reiss, G. (2007): The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes. In: PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH. (204).  S. 3942-3945.</wels>
<bio1>Kanak J, Stobiecki T, Drewello V, Schmalhorst J-M, Reiss G (2007) &lt;br /&gt;The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes. &lt;br /&gt;In:  PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE. 204. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH:  3942-3945.</bio1>
<aps>J.  Kanak, et al., The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes, in &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;204&lt;/strong&gt; (WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH, 2007), p. 3942-3945.</aps>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kanak, J., Stobiecki, T., Drewello, V., Schmalhorst, J.-M. &amp;amp; Reiss, G. (2007). The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes. &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt; (S. 3942-3945). WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH. doi:10.1002/pssa.200777107.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Kanak, J., et al., 2007. The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes. In &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;. no.204  WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH, pp. 3942-3945.</harvard1>
<ama>Kanak J, Stobiecki T, Drewello V, Schmalhorst J-M, Reiss G. The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes. In:  &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 204. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH;  2007: 3942-3945.</ama>
<frontiers>Kanak, J., Stobiecki, T., Drewello, V., Schmalhorst, J. - M., and Reiss, G. (2007). “The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes” in &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 204, (WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH), 3942-3945.</frontiers>
<apa>Kanak, J., Stobiecki, T., Drewello, V., Schmalhorst, J. - M., &amp;amp; Reiss, G. (2007). The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes. &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;204&lt;/em&gt;(12), 3942-3945.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>J.  Kanak, T.  Stobiecki, V.  Drewello, J. - M.  Schmalhorst, and G.  Reiss, in &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, Wiley-V C H Verlag Gmbh, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 3942-3945.</angewandte-chemie>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kanak, J., Stobiecki, T., Drewello, V., Schmalhorst, Jan-Michael, and Reiss, Günter. 2007. “The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes”. In &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, 204:3942-3945. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Kanak, J., Stobiecki, T., Drewello, V., Schmalhorst, Jan-Michael, and Reiss, Günter. “The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes”. &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH, 2007.Vol. 204. 3942-3945.</mla>
<lncs>Kanak, J., Stobiecki, T., Drewello, V., Schmalhorst, J.-M., Reiss, G.: The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes. PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE. 204, p. 3942-3945. WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH (2007).</lncs>
<ieee>J. Kanak, et al., “The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes”, &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 204, WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH, 2007,  pp.3942-3945.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kanak, J., Stobiecki, T., Drewello, V., Schmalhorst, J. - M., &amp;amp; Reiss, G. (2007). The influence of the texture on properties of IrMn spin valve magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barrier and CoFeB electrodes. &lt;em&gt;PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI A-APPLICATIONS AND MATERIALS SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;204&lt;/em&gt;(12), 3942-3945.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1630724</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:05:10Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-12-16T09:52:02Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1630724</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1630724</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
