<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference abstract</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields.</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Sergej</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kakorin</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">20316</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Liese</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Eberhard</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Neumann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">20317</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17981</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2003</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0065-7727</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000187917803227</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>225</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Kakorin, S., Liese, T., &amp;amp; Neumann, E., 2003. Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields. In &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;. no.225  AMER CHEMICAL SOC.</harvard1>
<ama>Kakorin S, Liese T, Neumann E. Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields. In:  &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;. Vol 225. AMER CHEMICAL SOC;  2003.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kakorin, S., Liese, T. &amp;amp; Neumann, E. (2003). Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields. &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;. AMER CHEMICAL SOC.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<bio1>Kakorin S, Liese T, Neumann E (2003) &lt;br /&gt;Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields. &lt;br /&gt;In:  ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY. 225. AMER CHEMICAL SOC.</bio1>
<aps> S.  Kakorin, T.  Liese, and E.  Neumann, Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields., in &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;225&lt;/strong&gt; (AMER CHEMICAL SOC, 2003).</aps>
<wels>Kakorin, S.; Liese, T.; Neumann, E. (2003): Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields. In: ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY. AMER CHEMICAL SOC. (225).</wels>
<default>Kakorin S, Liese T, Neumann E (2003)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY. 225. AMER CHEMICAL SOC.</default>
<ieee> S. Kakorin, T. Liese, and E. Neumann, “Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields.”, &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 225, AMER CHEMICAL SOC, 2003.</ieee>
<mla>Kakorin, Sergej, Liese, T, and Neumann, Eberhard. “Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields.”. &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;. AMER CHEMICAL SOC, 2003.Vol. 225.</mla>
<lncs> Kakorin, S., Liese, T., Neumann, E.: Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields. ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY. 225,  AMER CHEMICAL SOC (2003).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kakorin, S., Liese, T., &amp;amp; Neumann, E. (2003). Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields. &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;225&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Kakorin, T.  Liese, and E.  Neumann, in &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;, Amer Chemical Soc, &lt;strong&gt;2003&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Kakorin, S., Liese, T., &amp;amp; Neumann, E. (2003). Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields. &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;225&lt;/em&gt;.</apa>
<frontiers>Kakorin, S., Liese, T., and Neumann, E. (2003). “Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields.” in &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 225, (AMER CHEMICAL SOC).</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Kakorin, Sergej, Liese, T, and Neumann, Eberhard. 2003. “Kinetics of optical membrane probes for lipid vesicle elongation and electroporation in high electric fields.”. In &lt;em&gt;ABSTRACTS OF PAPERS OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY&lt;/em&gt;. Vol. 225. AMER CHEMICAL SOC: 478-COLL.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1607954</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:57:40Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-10-24T11:54:51Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1607954</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1607954</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
