<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">F. W.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Busch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T. B.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pilgrim</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krämer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21463</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0003-2774-7860</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">G.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ehninger</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>AG 2 Biomedizinische Grundlagen und Bevölkerungsmedizin</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">21332</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Granulocyte colony-stimulating factor (G-CSF) is considered to play a pivotal role in hemopoietic regulation, Its pharmacological application is reported to shorten chemotherapy-induced neutropenia as well as time to engraftment in patients after bone marrow transplantation (BRIT), In order possibly to establish further rationale for G-CSF treatment strategies in patients undergoing BMT, me evaluated G-CSF plasma levels of 89 patients after allogeneic BMT for chronic myeloid leukemia (Chit), EDTA anti-coagulated plasma samples were collected starting on day -1 (before grafting) and thereafter twice weekly for four consecutive weeks, G-CSF levels were estimated by enzyme immunoassay. Patients with late (&gt;30 days) bone marrow engraftment had consistently higher G-CSF levels at day +1 (after grafting) compared to patients with early (less than or equal to 30 days) engraftment, while all patients had low plasma levels on day -1/0. Mean G-CSF plasma levels and time to engraftment were correlated (r = 0.79), In univariate analyses, high G-CSF levels at days +1, +4, +7, +10 and several clinical variables (such as TBI, unrelated donor transplant, state of disease) were predictive of late engraftment, Further analysis by multivariate Cos regression resulted in the following predictive model: high G-CSF plasma levels at day +7 and +10 (after grafting), in combination with a blastic phase of the disease were highly predictive of late engraftment, The significantly higher G-CSF levels in patients with impaired engraftment may reflect early compensating mechanisms of the hemopoietic system, which should be investigated further.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>STOCKTON PRESS</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1997</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>G-CSF</topic><topic>CML</topic><topic>bone marrow transplantation</topic><topic>plasma levels</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Bone Marrow Transplantation</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0268-3369</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">9156241</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">A1997WU19100003</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1038/sj.bmt.1700722</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>19</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>7</number></detail><extent unit="pages">653-659</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Busch, F. W., Pilgrim, T. B., Krämer, Alexander, and Ehninger, G. 1997. “Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow”. &lt;em&gt;Bone Marrow Transplantation&lt;/em&gt; 19 (7): 653-659.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Busch, F. W., Pilgrim, T. B., Krämer, A., and Ehninger, G. (1997). Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow. &lt;em&gt;Bone Marrow Transplantation&lt;/em&gt; 19, 653-659.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>F. W.  Busch, T. B.  Pilgrim, A.  Krämer, and G.  Ehninger, “Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow”, &lt;em&gt;Bone Marrow Transplantation&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1997&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;, 653-659.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Busch, F. W., Pilgrim, T. B., Krämer, A., &amp;amp; Ehninger, G. (1997). Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow. &lt;em&gt;Bone Marrow Transplantation&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;(7), 653-659.</apa>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Busch, F. W., Pilgrim, T. B., Krämer, A., &amp;amp; Ehninger, G. (1997). Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow. &lt;em&gt;Bone Marrow Transplantation&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;(7), 653-659.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs>Busch, F.W., Pilgrim, T.B., Krämer, A., Ehninger, G.: Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow. Bone Marrow Transplantation. 19, 653-659 (1997).</lncs>
<mla>Busch, F. W., Pilgrim, T. B., Krämer, Alexander, and Ehninger, G. “Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow”. &lt;em&gt;Bone Marrow Transplantation&lt;/em&gt; 19.7 (1997): 653-659.</mla>
<ieee>F.W. Busch, et al., “Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow”, &lt;em&gt;Bone Marrow Transplantation&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 19, 1997,  pp. 653-659.</ieee>
<default>Busch FW, Pilgrim TB, Krämer A, Ehninger G (1997) &lt;br /&gt;Bone Marrow Transplantation 19(7): 653-659.</default>
<wels>Busch, F. W.; Pilgrim, T. B.; Krämer, A.; Ehninger, G. (1997): Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow &lt;em&gt;Bone Marrow Transplantation&lt;/em&gt;,19:(7): 653-659.</wels>
<bio1>Busch FW, Pilgrim TB, Krämer A, Ehninger G (1997) &lt;br /&gt;Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow.&lt;br /&gt;Bone Marrow Transplantation 19(7): 653-659.</bio1>
<aps>F. W.  Busch, et al., Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow, Bone Marrow Transplantation &lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt;, 653-659 (1997).</aps>
<ama>Busch FW, Pilgrim TB, Krämer A, Ehninger G. Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow. &lt;em&gt;Bone Marrow Transplantation&lt;/em&gt;. 1997;19(7):653-659.</ama>
<harvard1>Busch, F.W., et al., 1997. Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow. &lt;em&gt;Bone Marrow Transplantation&lt;/em&gt;, 19(7), p 653-659.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Busch, F.W., Pilgrim, T.B., Krämer, A. &amp;amp; Ehninger, G. (1997). Plasma levels of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor in patients after allogeneic bone marrow transplantation for chronic myeloid leukemia correlate with engraftment of transplanted marrow. &lt;em&gt;Bone Marrow Transplantation&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;19&lt;/em&gt;(7), 653-659. STOCKTON PRESS. doi:10.1038/sj.bmt.1700722.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1637416</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:14:13Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2013-12-18T15:01:06Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1637416</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1637416</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
