<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">FM</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Spinath</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alois</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Angleitner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">33671</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">P</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Borkenau</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Rainer</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Riemann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">5381445</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">H</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wolf</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10026</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">T he German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT) is the largest population-based observational twin study in Germany to date. Embedded in the Bielefeld Longitudinal Study of Adult Twins (BiLSAT), it addresses the etiology of personality, temperament and cognitive ability in a sample of 300 monozygotic (MZ) and dizygotic (DZ) adult twin pairs between 18 and 70 years of age. A major aim of the GOSAT lies in the utilization of different modes of measurement, (i.e., peer reports and observational data), in addition to self-reports which have been used predominantly in past behavioral genetic research on personality and temperament in adults. Participants completed a full day assessment at the University of Bielefeld including videotaped social interactions and presentations, psychometric intelligence tests and computerized elementary cognitive tasks as well as objective measures and unobtrusive behavior counts. The research design of the GOSAT was devised to reduce the potential impact of systematic rater bias on estimates of genetic and environmental influences to a minimum. In combination with extensive self and peer report data on key personality and personality related dimensions available from the BiLSAT, the GOSAT provides a rich dataset, which currently includes DNA samples from 80% of its participants.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>AUSTRALIAN ACAD PRESS</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2002</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>TWIN RESEARCH</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1369-0523</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">0000-0000</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">12537861</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000179240200011</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1375/136905202320906110</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>5</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>5</number></detail><extent unit="pages">372-375</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee> F.M. Spinath, et al., “German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability”, &lt;em&gt;TWIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 5, 2002,  pp. 372-375.</ieee>
<lncs> Spinath, F.M., Angleitner, A., Borkenau, P., Riemann, R., Wolf, H.: German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability. TWIN RESEARCH. 5, 372-375 (2002).</lncs>
<mla>Spinath, FM, Angleitner, Alois, Borkenau, P, Riemann, Rainer, and Wolf, H. “German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability”. &lt;em&gt;TWIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt; 5.5 (2002): 372-375.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Spinath, F. M., Angleitner, A., Borkenau, P., Riemann, R., &amp;amp; Wolf, H. (2002). German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability. &lt;em&gt;TWIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;(5), 372-375.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<apa>Spinath, F. M., Angleitner, A., Borkenau, P., Riemann, R., &amp;amp; Wolf, H. (2002). German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability. &lt;em&gt;TWIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;(5), 372-375.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>F. M.  Spinath, A.  Angleitner, P.  Borkenau, R.  Riemann, and H.  Wolf, “German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability”, &lt;em&gt;TWIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;, 372-375.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Spinath, F. M., Angleitner, A., Borkenau, P., Riemann, R., and Wolf, H. (2002). German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability. &lt;em&gt;TWIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt; 5, 372-375.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Spinath, FM, Angleitner, Alois, Borkenau, P, Riemann, Rainer, and Wolf, H. 2002. “German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability”. &lt;em&gt;TWIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt; 5 (5): 372-375.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<harvard1>Spinath, F.M., et al., 2002. German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability. &lt;em&gt;TWIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, 5(5), p 372-375.</harvard1>
<ama>Spinath FM, Angleitner A, Borkenau P, Riemann R, Wolf H. German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability. &lt;em&gt;TWIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;. 2002;5(5):372-375.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Spinath, F.M., Angleitner, A., Borkenau, P., Riemann, R. &amp;amp; Wolf, H. (2002). German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability. &lt;em&gt;TWIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;5&lt;/em&gt;(5), 372-375. AUSTRALIAN ACAD PRESS. doi:10.1375/136905202320906110.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<aps> F. M.  Spinath, et al., German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability, TWIN RESEARCH &lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;, 372-375 (2002).</aps>
<bio1>Spinath FM, Angleitner A, Borkenau P, Riemann R, Wolf H (2002) &lt;br /&gt;German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability.&lt;br /&gt;TWIN RESEARCH 5(5): 372-375.</bio1>
<wels>Spinath, F. M.; Angleitner, A.; Borkenau, P.; Riemann, R.; Wolf, H. (2002): German Observational Study of Adult Twins (GOSAT): A multimodal investigation of personality, temperament and cognitive ability &lt;em&gt;TWIN RESEARCH&lt;/em&gt;,5:(5): 372-375.</wels>
<default>Spinath FM, Angleitner A, Borkenau P, Riemann R, Wolf H (2002) &lt;br /&gt;TWIN RESEARCH 5(5): 372-375.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1613186</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:00:29Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-09-21T12:50:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1613186</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1613186</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
