<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Merlyn J.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Behr</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas R.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Post</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ipke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wachsmuth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">73476</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Alan</namePart><namePart type="family">Bell</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Technische Fakultät</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10036</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>AG Wissensbasierte Systeme</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10044</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">The question of how children perceive the &quot;bigness&quot; of rational numbers is of importance. Addition of fractions like1/3 and 3/5 does not make sense to a child without a quantitative notion of each addend. In order for children to perceive the size of a fraction, it seems necessary that they perceive the ordered pair such as 3/4; as one conceptual entity. This note describes, and summarizes results from several tasks the Rational Number Project has used to investigate children&apos;s perception of fractions, and especially of the size of a fraction. The Rational Number Project has involved fourth- and fifth-grade children in extensive teaching experiments. The teaching milieu of these experiments is especially manipulative rich, concept oriented, and involves small groups of children.</abstract>

<relatedItem type="constituent">
  <location>
    <url displayLabel="Wachsmuth_56.pdf">https://pub.uni-bielefeld.de/download/1779314/2312655</url>
  </location>
  <physicalDescription><internetMediaType>application/pdf</internetMediaType></physicalDescription><accessCondition type="restrictionOnAccess">no</accessCondition>
</relatedItem>
<originInfo><publisher>Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1984</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>


<relatedItem type="host"><location><url>http://www.cehd.umn.edu/ci/rationalnumberproject/84_1.html</url></location></relatedItem>

<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="isbn">0-906126-29-0</identifier><identifier type="urn">urn:nbn:de:0070-bipr-18302</identifier>
<part><extent unit="pages">179-185</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>

<note type="nonBielefeld">yes</note>
<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<harvard1>Behr, M.J., Post, T.R., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I., 1984. Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction. In A.  Bell, ed. &lt;em&gt;Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984&lt;/em&gt;.  Nottingham: Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham, pp. 179-185.</harvard1>
<ama>Behr MJ, Post TR, Wachsmuth I. Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction. In: Bell A, ed. &lt;em&gt;Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984&lt;/em&gt;. Nottingham: Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham;  1984: 179-185.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Behr, M.J., Post, T.R. &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1984). Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction. &lt;em&gt;Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984&lt;/em&gt; (S. 179-185). Nottingham: Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<aps>M. J.  Behr, T. R.  Post, and I.  Wachsmuth, Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction, in &lt;em&gt;Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984&lt;/em&gt;, edited by A.  Bell (Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, 1984), p. 179-185.</aps>
<bio1>Behr MJ, Post TR, Wachsmuth I (1984) &lt;br /&gt;Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction. &lt;br /&gt;In:  Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984. Bell A (Ed); Nottingham: Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham:  179-185.</bio1>
<wels>Behr, M. J.; Post, T. R.; Wachsmuth, I. (1984): Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction. In: Alan Bell (Hrsg.):  Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984. Nottingham: Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham.  S. 179-185.</wels>
<default>Behr MJ, Post TR, Wachsmuth I (1984)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984. Bell A (Ed);Nottingham: Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham:  179-185.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Behr, M. J., Post, T. R., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1984). Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction. In A.  Bell (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 179-185). Nottingham: Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>M.J. Behr, T.R. Post, and I. Wachsmuth, “Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction”, &lt;em&gt;Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984&lt;/em&gt;, A. Bell, ed.,  Nottingham: Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham, 1984,  pp.179-185.</ieee>
<mla>Behr, Merlyn J., Post, Thomas R., and Wachsmuth, Ipke. “Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction”. &lt;em&gt;Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Alan Bell. Nottingham: Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham, 1984. 179-185.</mla>
<lncs>Behr, M.J., Post, T.R., Wachsmuth, I.: Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction. In: Bell, A. (ed.) Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984. p. 179-185. Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham, Nottingham (1984).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Behr, Merlyn J., Post, Thomas R., and Wachsmuth, Ipke. 1984. “Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction”. In &lt;em&gt;Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Alan Bell, 179-185. Nottingham: Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<apa>Behr, M. J., Post, T. R., &amp;amp; Wachsmuth, I. (1984). Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction. In A.  Bell (Ed.), &lt;em&gt;Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 179-185). Nottingham: Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>M. J.  Behr, T. R.  Post, and I.  Wachsmuth, in &lt;em&gt;Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984&lt;/em&gt; (Ed.: A. Bell), Shell Centre For Mathematical Education, University Of Nottingham, Nottingham, &lt;strong&gt;1984&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 179-185.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Behr, M. J., Post, T. R., and Wachsmuth, I. (1984). “Tasks to assess children&apos;s perception of the size of a fraction” in &lt;em&gt;Theory, research and practice in mathematical education: 5th International Congress on Mathematical Education, Adelaide, South Australia, August 1984&lt;/em&gt;, ed. A.  Bell (Nottingham: Shell Centre for Mathematical Education, University of Nottingham), 179-185.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1779314</recordIdentifier><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2014-03-29T01:13:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1779314</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1779314</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
