<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Oyunbileg</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Nyamsuren</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christian</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Firnhaber</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Natalija</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hohnjec</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anke</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Becker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Helge</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Küster</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Franziska</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krajinski</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">During the parasitic interaction between the model legume Medicago truncatula and the oomycete Aphanomyces euteiches, a plant protease inhibitor (PI)-encoding gene, MtTi2, was found to be induced. Sequence and database analyses showed that MtTi2 belongs to a group of at least four PIs, which are all specifically expressed upon pathogen infection or elicitor treatment. Reporter analysis showed that the MtTi2 promoter is activated in infected root tissues and revealed a distinct promoter area involved in this transcriptional induction. In order to elucidate the function of MtTi2, RNAi-mediated silencing experiments were carried out. After introduction of double-stranded MtTi2 RNA into M. truncatula roots, no endogenous transcripts were observed, indicating efficient gene suppression. Since some plant protease inhibitors were shown to suppress pathogen growth, the MtTi2i-phenotype was analyzed with respect to pathogen spreading after root infection. No altered pathogen development was observed in MtMi-roots as compared to control roots, indicating that MtTi2 does not directly influence the pathogen. In order to investigate whether suppression of MtTi2 results in transcriptional changes, transcriptome profiles of MtTi2i roots and control roots were analyzed using an 8000 gene M. truncatula microarray. A cluster analysis of genes regulated in roots upon infection in two MtTi2-lines or two vector lines revealed groups of genes showing different regulation in MtTi2i- and wild type roots. Hence, it is likely that MtTi2 has endogenous functions other than directly suppressing the pathogen. Furthermore, the transcriptome approach revealed insight into the transcriptional changes in response to A. euteiches infection. (c) 2007 Elsevier Ireland Ltd. All rights reserved.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>ELSEVIER IRELAND LTD</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>protease</topic><topic>Medicago truncatula</topic><topic>microarrays</topic><topic>Aphanomyces euteiches</topic><topic>RNAi</topic><topic>inhibitor</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>PLANT SCIENCE</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0168-9452</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000248264400002</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/j.plantsci.2007.04.002</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>173</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>2</number></detail><extent unit="pages">84-95</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<bio1>Nyamsuren O, Firnhaber C, Hohnjec N, Becker A, Küster H, Krajinski F (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots.&lt;br /&gt;PLANT SCIENCE 173(2): 84-95.</bio1>
<aps> O.  Nyamsuren, et al., Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots, PLANT SCIENCE &lt;strong&gt;173&lt;/strong&gt;, 84-95 (2007).</aps>
<ama>Nyamsuren O, Firnhaber C, Hohnjec N, Becker A, Küster H, Krajinski F. Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots. &lt;em&gt;PLANT SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;. 2007;173(2):84-95.</ama>
<harvard1>Nyamsuren, O., et al., 2007. Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots. &lt;em&gt;PLANT SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, 173(2), p 84-95.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Nyamsuren, O., Firnhaber, C., Hohnjec, N., Becker, A., Küster, H. &amp;amp; Krajinski, F. (2007). Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots. &lt;em&gt;PLANT SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;173&lt;/em&gt;(2), 84-95. ELSEVIER IRELAND LTD. doi:10.1016/j.plantsci.2007.04.002.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Nyamsuren O, Firnhaber C, Hohnjec N, Becker A, Küster H, Krajinski F (2007) &lt;br /&gt;PLANT SCIENCE 173(2): 84-95.</default>
<wels>Nyamsuren, O.; Firnhaber, C.; Hohnjec, N.; Becker, A.; Küster, H.; Krajinski, F. (2007): Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots &lt;em&gt;PLANT SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;,173:(2): 84-95.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Nyamsuren, O., Firnhaber, C., Hohnjec, N., Becker, A., Küster, H., &amp;amp; Krajinski, F. (2007). Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots. &lt;em&gt;PLANT SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;173&lt;/em&gt;(2), 84-95.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Nyamsuren, Oyunbileg, Firnhaber, Christian, Hohnjec, Natalija, Becker, Anke, Küster, Helge, and Krajinski, Franziska. “Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots”. &lt;em&gt;PLANT SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt; 173.2 (2007): 84-95.</mla>
<lncs> Nyamsuren, O., Firnhaber, C., Hohnjec, N., Becker, A., Küster, H., Krajinski, F.: Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots. PLANT SCIENCE. 173, 84-95 (2007).</lncs>
<ieee> O. Nyamsuren, et al., “Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots”, &lt;em&gt;PLANT SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 173, 2007,  pp. 84-95.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Nyamsuren, Oyunbileg, Firnhaber, Christian, Hohnjec, Natalija, Becker, Anke, Küster, Helge, and Krajinski, Franziska. 2007. “Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots”. &lt;em&gt;PLANT SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt; 173 (2): 84-95.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Nyamsuren, O., Firnhaber, C., Hohnjec, N., Becker, A., Küster, H., and Krajinski, F. (2007). Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots. &lt;em&gt;PLANT SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt; 173, 84-95.</frontiers>
<apa>Nyamsuren, O., Firnhaber, C., Hohnjec, N., Becker, A., Küster, H., &amp;amp; Krajinski, F. (2007). Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots. &lt;em&gt;PLANT SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;173&lt;/em&gt;(2), 84-95.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>O.  Nyamsuren, C.  Firnhaber, N.  Hohnjec, A.  Becker, H.  Küster, and F.  Krajinski, “Suppression of the pathogen-inducible Medicago truncatula putative protease-inhibitor MtTi2 does not influence root infection by Aphanomyces euteiches but results in transcriptional changes from wildtype roots”, &lt;em&gt;PLANT SCIENCE&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;173&lt;/em&gt;, 84-95.</angewandte-chemie>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1632901</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:06:23Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-10-24T12:26:07Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1632901</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1632901</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
