<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Tao</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Wang</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Qin-Qing</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hou</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Qing-Feng</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Teng</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Xiao-Jun</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Yao</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wen-Xue</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Niu</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Xiao-Ping</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cao</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Dietmar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kuck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">20254</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Organische Chemie I</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17975</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Enantiomerically pure tribenzotriquinacenes (TBTQs) bearing two monofunctionalized aromatic nuclei were synthesized for the first time and their optical properties and absolute configuration determined. A remarkably regioselective bis-formylation of the fully bridgehead methylated parent TBTQ hydrocarbon with MeOCHCl2/TiCl4 afforded a mixture of two C-s-symmetrical (achiral) difunctionalized derivatives together with one C-1-symmetrical (chiral) isomer. Reduction and subsequent column chromatography furnished the three respective benzylic TBTQ dialcohols. Optical resolution of the racemic 2,6-bis(hydroxymethyl) derivative was achieved via the diastereomeric (R)-1,1&apos;-bi-2-naphthol ethers and the absolute configuration of the enantiomers was determined by CD exciton model analysis. The electronic circular dichroism (ECD) spectra and the specific rotation of the enantiomers were found to agree with the results of DFT calculations. Among the C-s-symmetrical isomers, the &quot;proximal&quot; 2,11-dialdehyde and the corresponding benzylic dialcohol were identified by 2D NMR spectroscopy and X-ray crystallographic analysis, respectively, and used as the starting point for the synthesis of several novel dithiametacyclophanes. These include the first &quot;dimeric&quot; tribenzotriquinacene-based cyclophanes bearing the bowls of the two TBTQ units attached to each other in a syn (concave-concave) or anti (convex-concave) configuration. The usefulness of such thiacyclophanes as fluorescent chemosensors for different metal ions is also demonstrated.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>Wiley-Blackwell</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>formylation</topic><topic>configuration determination</topic><topic>regioselectivity</topic><topic>synthetic</topic><topic>methods</topic><topic>tribenzotriquinacenes</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0947-6539</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">20853291</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000284061400020</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1002/chem.201001620</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>16</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>41</number></detail><extent unit="pages">12412-12424</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<default>Wang T, Hou Q-Q, Teng Q-F, Yao X-J, Niu W-X, Cao X-P, Kuck D (2010) &lt;br /&gt;CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL 16(41): 12412-12424.</default>
<wels>Wang, T.; Hou, Q. - Q.; Teng, Q. - F.; Yao, X. - J.; Niu, W. - X.; Cao, X. - P.; Kuck, D. (2010): Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers &lt;em&gt;CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;,16:(41): 12412-12424.</wels>
<bio1>Wang T, Hou Q-Q, Teng Q-F, Yao X-J, Niu W-X, Cao X-P, Kuck D (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers.&lt;br /&gt;CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL 16(41): 12412-12424.</bio1>
<aps>T.  Wang, et al., Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers, CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL &lt;strong&gt;16&lt;/strong&gt;, 12412-12424 (2010).</aps>
<ama>Wang T, Hou Q-Q, Teng Q-F, et al. Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers. &lt;em&gt;CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;. 2010;16(41):12412-12424.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Wang, T., Hou, Q.-Q., Teng, Q.-F., Yao, X.-J., Niu, W.-X., Cao, X.-P. &amp;amp; Kuck, D. (2010). Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers. &lt;em&gt;CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(41), 12412-12424. Wiley-Blackwell. doi:10.1002/chem.201001620.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Wang, T., et al., 2010. Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers. &lt;em&gt;CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, 16(41), p 12412-12424.</harvard1>
<frontiers>Wang, T., Hou, Q. - Q., Teng, Q. - F., Yao, X. - J., Niu, W. - X., Cao, X. - P., and Kuck, D. (2010). Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers. &lt;em&gt;CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt; 16, 12412-12424.</frontiers>
<apa>Wang, T., Hou, Q. - Q., Teng, Q. - F., Yao, X. - J., Niu, W. - X., Cao, X. - P., &amp;amp; Kuck, D. (2010). Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers. &lt;em&gt;CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(41), 12412-12424.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Wang, Q. - Q.  Hou, Q. - F.  Teng, X. - J.  Yao, W. - X.  Niu, X. - P.  Cao, and D.  Kuck, “Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers”, &lt;em&gt;CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;, 12412-12424.</angewandte-chemie>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Wang, Tao, Hou, Qin-Qing, Teng, Qing-Feng, Yao, Xiao-Jun, Niu, Wen-Xue, Cao, Xiao-Ping, and Kuck, Dietmar. 2010. “Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers”. &lt;em&gt;CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt; 16 (41): 12412-12424.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<mla>Wang, Tao, Hou, Qin-Qing, Teng, Qing-Feng, Yao, Xiao-Jun, Niu, Wen-Xue, Cao, Xiao-Ping, and Kuck, Dietmar. “Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers”. &lt;em&gt;CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt; 16.41 (2010): 12412-12424.</mla>
<lncs>Wang, T., Hou, Q.-Q., Teng, Q.-F., Yao, X.-J., Niu, W.-X., Cao, X.-P., Kuck, D.: Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers. CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL. 16, 12412-12424 (2010).</lncs>
<ieee>T. Wang, et al., “Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers”, &lt;em&gt;CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 16, 2010,  pp. 12412-12424.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Wang, T., Hou, Q. - Q., Teng, Q. - F., Yao, X. - J., Niu, W. - X., Cao, X. - P., &amp;amp; Kuck, D. (2010). Tribenzotriquinacenes Based on Regioselective Bis-formylation: Optical Resolution and Absolute Configuration of Inherently Chiral Derivatives and Synthesis of the First Cyclophane-Type Tribenzotriquinacene Dimers. &lt;em&gt;CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;16&lt;/em&gt;(41), 12412-12424.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1929210</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-12-07T10:47:05Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-10-11T10:08:04Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1929210</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1929210</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
