<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Agim</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ballvora</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Anika</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Joecker</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Prisca</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Viehöver</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">159120</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Hirofumi</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Ishihara</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Juergen</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Paal</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Khalid</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Meksem</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Remy</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Bruggmann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Heiko</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schoof</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Bernd</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Weisshaar</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">86212</identifier><description xsi:type="identifierDefinition" type="orcid">0000-0002-7635-3473</description></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Christiane</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gebhardt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">441929</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2684836</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">33070678</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Background: Quantitative phenotypic variation of agronomic characters in crop plants is controlled by environmental
and genetic factors (quantitative trait loci = QTL). To understand the molecular basis of such QTL, the identification of
the underlying genes is of primary interest and DNA sequence analysis of the genomic regions harboring QTL is a
prerequisite for that. QTL mapping in potato (Solanum tuberosum) has identified a region on chromosome V tagged by
DNA markers GP21 and GP179, which contains a number of important QTL, among others QTL for resistance to late
blight caused by the oomycete Phytophthora infestans and to root cyst nematodes.
Results: To obtain genomic sequence for the targeted region on chromosome V, two local BAC (bacterial artificial
chromosome) contigs were constructed and sequenced, which corresponded to parts of the homologous chromosomes
of the diploid, heterozygous genotype P6/210. Two contiguous sequences of 417,445 and 202,781 base pairs were
assembled and annotated. Gene-by-gene co-linearity was disrupted by non-allelic insertions of retrotransposon elements,
stretches of diverged intergenic sequences, differences in gene content and gene order. The latter was caused by
inversion of a 70 kbp genomic fragment. These features were also found in comparison to orthologous sequence contigs
from three homeologous chromosomes of Solanum demissum, a wild tuber bearing species. Functional annotation of the
sequence identified 48 putative open reading frames (ORF) in one contig and 22 in the other, with an average of one
ORF every 9 kbp. Ten ORFs were classified as resistance-gene-like, 11 as F-box-containing genes, 13 as transposable
elements and three as transcription factors. Comparing potato to Arabidopsis thaliana annotated proteins revealed five
micro-syntenic blocks of three to seven ORFs with A. thaliana chromosomes 1, 3 and 5.
Conclusion: Comparative sequence analysis revealed highly conserved collinear regions that flank regions showing high
variability and tandem duplicated genes. Sequence annotation revealed that the majority of the ORFs were members of
multiple gene families. Comparing potato to Arabidopsis thaliana annotated proteins suggested fragmented structural
conservation between these distantly related plant species</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>Biomed Central Ltd</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BMC Genomics</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">1471-2164</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">17474978</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000247013400001</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1186/1471-2164-8-112</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>8</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>1</number></detail>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<aps>A.  Ballvora, et al., Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments, BMC Genomics &lt;strong&gt;8&lt;/strong&gt;, (2007).</aps>
<bio1>Ballvora A, Joecker A, Viehöver P, Ishihara H, Paal J, Meksem K, Bruggmann R, Schoof H, Weisshaar B, Gebhardt C (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments.&lt;br /&gt;BMC Genomics 8(1): 112.</bio1>
<ama>Ballvora A, Joecker A, Viehöver P, et al. Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;. 2007;8(1): 112.</ama>
<harvard1>Ballvora, A., et al., 2007. Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, 8(1): 112.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Ballvora, A., Joecker, A., Viehöver, P., Ishihara, H., Paal, J., Meksem, K., Bruggmann, R., Schoof, H., Weisshaar, B. &amp;amp; Gebhardt, C. (2007). Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(1): 112. Biomed Central Ltd. doi:10.1186/1471-2164-8-112.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Ballvora A, Joecker A, Viehöver P, Ishihara H, Paal J, Meksem K, Bruggmann R, Schoof H, Weisshaar B, Gebhardt C (2007) &lt;br /&gt;BMC Genomics 8(1): 112.</default>
<wels>Ballvora, A.; Joecker, A.; Viehöver, P.; Ishihara, H.; Paal, J.; Meksem, K.; Bruggmann, R.; Schoof, H.; Weisshaar, B.; Gebhardt, C. (2007): Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;,8:(1):112</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Ballvora, A., Joecker, A., Viehöver, P., Ishihara, H., Paal, J., Meksem, K., Bruggmann, R., et al. (2007). Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(1): 112.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<lncs>Ballvora, A., Joecker, A., Viehöver, P., Ishihara, H., Paal, J., Meksem, K., Bruggmann, R., Schoof, H., Weisshaar, B., Gebhardt, C.: Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments. BMC Genomics. 8, : 112 (2007).</lncs>
<mla>Ballvora, Agim, Joecker, Anika, Viehöver, Prisca, Ishihara, Hirofumi, Paal, Juergen, Meksem, Khalid, Bruggmann, Remy, Schoof, Heiko, Weisshaar, Bernd, and Gebhardt, Christiane. “Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 8.1 (2007): 112.</mla>
<ieee>A. Ballvora, et al., “Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 8, 2007, : 112.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Ballvora, Agim, Joecker, Anika, Viehöver, Prisca, Ishihara, Hirofumi, Paal, Juergen, Meksem, Khalid, Bruggmann, Remy, Schoof, Heiko, Weisshaar, Bernd, and Gebhardt, Christiane. 2007. “Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments”. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 8 (1): 112.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Ballvora, A., Joecker, A., Viehöver, P., Ishihara, H., Paal, J., Meksem, K., Bruggmann, R., Schoof, H., Weisshaar, B., and Gebhardt, C. (2007). Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt; 8:112.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Ballvora, A.  Joecker, P.  Viehöver, H.  Ishihara, J.  Paal, K.  Meksem, R.  Bruggmann, H.  Schoof, B.  Weisshaar, and C.  Gebhardt, “Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments”, &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;, : 112.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Ballvora, A., Joecker, A., Viehöver, P., Ishihara, H., Paal, J., Meksem, K., Bruggmann, R., et al. (2007). Comparative sequence analysis of Solanum and Arabidopsis in a hot spot for pathogen resistance on potato chromosome V reveals a patchwork of conserved and rapidly evolving genome segments. &lt;em&gt;BMC Genomics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;8&lt;/em&gt;(1): 112.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1593770</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:16:01Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-02-11T10:26:24Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1593770</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1593770</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
