<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference abstract</genre>

<titleInfo><title>TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">C. M.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Dintsios</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hagen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ansgar</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gerhardus</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">180567</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">C.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Krauth</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart></namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10046</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>BLACKWELL PUBLISHING</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2008</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
  <identifier type="issn">1098-3015</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000260054700214</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1016/S1098-3015(10)66378-4</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>11</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>6</number></detail><extent unit="pages">A406-A406</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Dintsios, C.M., Hagen, A., Gerhardus, A. &amp;amp; Krauth, C. (2008). TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA (VALUE IN HEALTH) (S. A406-A406). BLACKWELL PUBLISHING. doi:10.1016/S1098-3015(10)66378-4.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Dintsios CM, Hagen A, Gerhardus A, Krauth C. TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA.</ama>
<harvard1>Dintsios, C.M., et al., 2008. TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA.</harvard1>
<bio1>Dintsios CM, Hagen A, Gerhardus A, Krauth C (2008) &lt;br /&gt;TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA.</bio1>
<aps> C. M.  Dintsios, et al., TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA, VALUE IN HEALTH, &lt;strong&gt;11&lt;/strong&gt; (BLACKWELL PUBLISHING, 2008), p. A406-A406.</aps>
<wels>Dintsios, C. M.; Hagen, A.; Gerhardus, A.; Krauth, C. (2008): TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA. BLACKWELL PUBLISHING. (VALUE IN HEALTH, 11).  S. A406-A406.</wels>
<default>Dintsios CM, Hagen A, Gerhardus A, Krauth C (2008) .</default>
<ieee> C.M. Dintsios, et al., “TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA”, BLACKWELL PUBLISHING, 2008.</ieee>
<lncs> Dintsios, C.M., Hagen, A., Gerhardus, A., Krauth, C.: TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA. (2008).</lncs>
<mla>Dintsios, C. M., Hagen, A., Gerhardus, Ansgar, and Krauth, C. “TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA”., BLACKWELL PUBLISHING, 2008.</mla>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Dintsios, C. M., Hagen, A., Gerhardus, A., &amp;amp; Krauth, C. (2008). &lt;em&gt;TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the .&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<apa>Dintsios, C. M., Hagen, A., Gerhardus, A., &amp;amp; Krauth, C. (2008). &lt;em&gt;TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA&lt;/em&gt;. Presented at the .</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>C. M.  Dintsios, A.  Hagen, A.  Gerhardus, and C.  Krauth, Blackwell Publishing, &lt;strong&gt;2008&lt;/strong&gt;, p. A406-A406.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Dintsios, C. M., Hagen, A., Gerhardus, A., and Krauth, C. (2008).“TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA”.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Dintsios, C. M., Hagen, A., Gerhardus, Ansgar, and Krauth, C. 2008. “TISSUE ENGINEERING OF VALVED VENOUS CONDUITS (VVC) VERSUS CONSERVATIVE THERAPY IN PATIENTS WITH CHRONIC VENOUS INSUFFICIENCY (CVI). A DECISION ANALYTIC MODEL USING EXPERT ESTIMATED UTILITIES BASED ON DERIVED DATA FROM ANIMAL STUDIES AS A PRE-MARKETING TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT APPROACH WITH GERMAN DATA”. Presented at the , 11:A406-A406. VALUE IN HEALTH. BLACKWELL PUBLISHING.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1636293</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-29T13:08:02Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2016-10-06T12:01:09Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1636293</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1636293</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
