<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Gaillard</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">T</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vallaeys</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Frank-Jörg</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vorhölter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">177016</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Minoia</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">C</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Werlen</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">V</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Sentchilo</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alfred</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pühler</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">21937</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">JR</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">van der Meer</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Research Group  A. Pühler</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">33070639</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Fakultät für Biologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10017</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Pseudomonas sp. strain B13 is a bacterium known to degrade chloroaromatic compounds. The properties to use 3- and 4-chlorocatechol are determined by a self-transferable DNA element, the clc element, which normally resides at two locations in the cell&apos;s chromosome. Here we report the complete nucleotide sequence of the clc element, demonstrating the unique catabolic properties while showing its relatedness to genomic islands and integrative and conjugative elements rather than to other known catabolic plasmids. As far as catabolic functions, the clc element harbored, in addition to the genes for chlorocatechol degradation, a complete functional operon for 2-aminophenol degradation and genes for a putative aromatic compound transport protein and for a multicomponent aromatic ring dioxygenase similar to anthranilate hydroxylase. The genes for catabolic functions were inducible under various conditions, suggesting a network of catabolic pathway induction. For about half of the open reading frames (OPFs) on the clc element, no clear functional prediction could be given, although some indications were found for functions that were similar to plasmid conjugation. The region in which these ORFs were situated displayed a high overall conservation of nucleotide sequence and gene order to genomic regions in other recently completed bacterial genomes or to other genomic islands. Most notably, except for two discrete regions, the clc element was almost 100% identical over the whole length to a chromosomal region in Burkholderia xenovorans LB400. This indicates the dynamic evolution of this type of element and the continued transition between elements with a more pathogenic character and those with catabolic properties.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>AMER SOC MICROBIOLOGY</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2006</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0021-9193</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">16484212</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000235819200035</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1128/JB.188.5.1999-2013.2006</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>188</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>5</number></detail><extent unit="pages">1999-2013</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Gaillard, M., Vallaeys, T., Vorhölter, F. - J., Minoia, M., Werlen, C., Sentchilo, V., Pühler, A., et al. (2006). The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;188&lt;/em&gt;(5), 1999-2013.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Gaillard, M, Vallaeys, T, Vorhölter, Frank-Jörg, Minoia, M, Werlen, C, Sentchilo, V, Pühler, Alfred, and van der Meer, JR. “The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 188.5 (2006): 1999-2013.</mla>
<lncs>Gaillard, M., Vallaeys, T., Vorhölter, F.-J., Minoia, M., Werlen, C., Sentchilo, V., Pühler, A., van der Meer, J.R.: The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties. JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY. 188, 1999-2013 (2006).</lncs>
<ieee>M. Gaillard, et al., “The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 188, 2006,  pp. 1999-2013.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Gaillard, M, Vallaeys, T, Vorhölter, Frank-Jörg, Minoia, M, Werlen, C, Sentchilo, V, Pühler, Alfred, and van der Meer, JR. 2006. “The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties”. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 188 (5): 1999-2013.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Gaillard, M., Vallaeys, T., Vorhölter, F. - J., Minoia, M., Werlen, C., Sentchilo, V., Pühler, A., and van der Meer, J. R. (2006). The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt; 188, 1999-2013.</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Gaillard, T.  Vallaeys, F. - J.  Vorhölter, M.  Minoia, C.  Werlen, V.  Sentchilo, A.  Pühler, and J. R.  van der Meer, “The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties”, &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2006&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;188&lt;/em&gt;, 1999-2013.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Gaillard, M., Vallaeys, T., Vorhölter, F. - J., Minoia, M., Werlen, C., Sentchilo, V., Pühler, A., et al. (2006). The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;188&lt;/em&gt;(5), 1999-2013.</apa>
<aps>M.  Gaillard, et al., The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties, JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY &lt;strong&gt;188&lt;/strong&gt;, 1999-2013 (2006).</aps>
<bio1>Gaillard M, Vallaeys T, Vorhölter F-J, Minoia M, Werlen C, Sentchilo V, Pühler A, van der Meer JR (2006) &lt;br /&gt;The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties.&lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY 188(5): 1999-2013.</bio1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Gaillard, M., Vallaeys, T., Vorhölter, F.-J., Minoia, M., Werlen, C., Sentchilo, V., Pühler, A. &amp;amp; van der Meer, J.R. (2006). The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;188&lt;/em&gt;(5), 1999-2013. AMER SOC MICROBIOLOGY. doi:10.1128/JB.188.5.1999-2013.2006.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Gaillard M, Vallaeys T, Vorhölter F-J, et al. The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;. 2006;188(5):1999-2013.</ama>
<harvard1>Gaillard, M., et al., 2006. The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties. &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;, 188(5), p 1999-2013.</harvard1>
<default>Gaillard M, Vallaeys T, Vorhölter F-J, Minoia M, Werlen C, Sentchilo V, Pühler A, van der Meer JR (2006) &lt;br /&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY 188(5): 1999-2013.</default>
<wels>Gaillard, M.; Vallaeys, T.; Vorhölter, F. - J.; Minoia, M.; Werlen, C.; Sentchilo, V.; Pühler, A.; van der Meer, J. R. (2006): The clc element of Pseudomonas sp strain B13, a genomic island with various catabolic properties &lt;em&gt;JOURNAL OF BACTERIOLOGY&lt;/em&gt;,188:(5): 1999-2013.</wels>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1600185</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:31:08Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-01-06T09:54:28Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1600185</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1600185</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
