<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book</genre>

<titleInfo><title>A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ralf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Möller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">94532</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>AG Technische Informatik</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10040</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2002</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host">
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<ieee>R. Möller, &lt;em&gt;A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies&lt;/em&gt;, Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich.,  Universität Zürich: 2002.</ieee>
<mla>Möller, Ralf. &lt;em&gt;A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies&lt;/em&gt;. Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich. Universität Zürich, 2002.</mla>
<lncs>Möller, R.: A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies. Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich. Universität Zürich (2002).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Möller, R. (2002).  &lt;em&gt;A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies&lt;/em&gt; Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich. Universität Zürich.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<apa>Möller, R. (2002).  &lt;em&gt;A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies&lt;/em&gt; Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich. Universität Zürich.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>R.  Möller, &lt;em&gt;A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies&lt;/em&gt;, Universität Zürich, &lt;strong&gt;2002&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Möller, R. (2002). A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies. Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich. Universität Zürich.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Möller, Ralf. 2002. &lt;em&gt;A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies&lt;/em&gt;. Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich. Universität Zürich.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ama>Möller R. &lt;em&gt;A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies&lt;/em&gt;.  Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich. Universität Zürich; 2002.</ama>
<harvard1>Möller, R., 2002. &lt;em&gt;A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies&lt;/em&gt;, Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich., Universität Zürich.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Möller, R. (2002). &lt;em&gt;A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies&lt;/em&gt; (Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich.). Universität Zürich.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<aps>R.  Möller, A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies, Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich (Universität Zürich, 2002).</aps>
<bio1>Möller R (2002) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies&lt;/em&gt;., Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich.&lt;br /&gt;Universität Zürich.</bio1>
<wels>Möller, R. (2002): A Biorobotics Approach to the Study of Insect Visual Homing Strategies. Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich.  Universität Zürich.</wels>
<default>Möller R (2002) , Habilitationsschrift angenommen von der Wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultät der Universität Zürich.&lt;br /&gt;Universität Zürich.</default>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1936924</recordIdentifier><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-12-09T08:24:37Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1936924</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1936924</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
