<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>conference paper</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Wolfram</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Schenck</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">106076</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ralph</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Welsch</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">8831724</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Alexander</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Kaiser</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">8273659</identifier></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ralf</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Möller</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">94532</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Center of Excellence - Cognitive Interaction Technology CITEC</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">8014655</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>AG Technische Informatik</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10040</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>



<name type="conference">
  <namePart>ESANN 2010</namePart>
</name>







<originInfo><publisher>d-side publications</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2010</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks</title></titleInfo>
<part><extent unit="pages">213-218</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<apa>Schenck, W., Welsch, R., Kaiser, A., &amp;amp; Möller, R. (2010). Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis. &lt;em&gt;ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks&lt;/em&gt;, 213-218.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>W.  Schenck, R.  Welsch, A.  Kaiser, and R.  Möller, in &lt;em&gt;ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks&lt;/em&gt;, D-Side Publications, Bruges (Belgium), &lt;strong&gt;2010&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 213-218.</angewandte-chemie>
<frontiers>Schenck, W., Welsch, R., Kaiser, A., and Möller, R. (2010). “Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis” in &lt;em&gt;ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks&lt;/em&gt; (Bruges (Belgium): d-side publications), 213-218.</frontiers>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Schenck, Wolfram, Welsch, Ralph, Kaiser, Alexander, and Möller, Ralf. 2010. “Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis”. In &lt;em&gt;ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks&lt;/em&gt;, 213-218. Bruges (Belgium): d-side publications.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<ieee>W. Schenck, et al., “Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis”, &lt;em&gt;ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks&lt;/em&gt;,  Bruges (Belgium): d-side publications, 2010,  pp.213-218.</ieee>
<mla>Schenck, Wolfram, Welsch, Ralph, Kaiser, Alexander, and Möller, Ralf. “Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis”. &lt;em&gt;ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks&lt;/em&gt;. Bruges (Belgium): d-side publications, 2010. 213-218.</mla>
<lncs>Schenck, W., Welsch, R., Kaiser, A., Möller, R.: Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis. ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks. p. 213-218. d-side publications, Bruges (Belgium) (2010).</lncs>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Schenck, W., Welsch, R., Kaiser, A., &amp;amp; Möller, R. (2010). Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis. &lt;em&gt;ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks&lt;/em&gt;, 213-218.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<wels>Schenck, W.; Welsch, R.; Kaiser, A.; Möller, R. (2010): Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis. In: ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks. Bruges (Belgium): d-side publications.  S. 213-218.</wels>
<default>Schenck W, Welsch R, Kaiser A, Möller R (2010)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks. Bruges (Belgium): d-side publications:  213-218.</default>
<harvard1>Schenck, W., et al., 2010. Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis. In &lt;em&gt;ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks&lt;/em&gt;.  Bruges (Belgium): d-side publications, pp. 213-218.</harvard1>
<ama>Schenck W, Welsch R, Kaiser A, Möller R. Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis. In:  &lt;em&gt;ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks&lt;/em&gt;. Bruges (Belgium): d-side publications;  2010: 213-218.</ama>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Schenck, W., Welsch, R., Kaiser, A. &amp;amp; Möller, R. (2010). Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis. &lt;em&gt;ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks&lt;/em&gt; (S. 213-218). Gehalten auf der ESANN 2010, Bruges (Belgium): d-side publications.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<aps>W.  Schenck, et al., Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis, in &lt;em&gt;ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks&lt;/em&gt; (d-side publications, Bruges (Belgium), 2010), p. 213-218.</aps>
<bio1>Schenck W, Welsch R, Kaiser A, Möller R (2010) &lt;br /&gt;Adaptive learning rate control for neural gas principal component analysis. &lt;br /&gt;In:  ESANN 2010 proceedings - European Symposium on Artificial Neural Networks.  Bruges (Belgium): d-side publications:  213-218.</bio1>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1936796</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-12-08T15:36:13Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-06-15T08:12:19Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1936796</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1936796</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
