<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">S.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Cukurcam</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">I.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Betzendahl</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">G.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Michel</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">E.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Vogt</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">C.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Hegele-Hartung</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">B.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Lindenthal</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Ursula</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Eichenlaub-Ritter</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">22132</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Gentechnologie/Mikrobiologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">2685250</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">BACKGROUND: Follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol (FF-MAS) protects young oocytes from precocious chromatid separation (predivision). Reduced expression of cohesion and checkpoint proteins and predivision has been hypothesized to occur in age-related aneuploidy in oocytes. METHODS: To know whether FF-MAS also protects aged oocytes from predivision and from age-related non-disjunction, we analysed chromosome constitution in mouse oocytes matured spontaneously with or without 10 mu M FF-MAS and in hypoxanthine (HX)-arrested young and aged oocytes induced to resume maturation by FF-MAS. Messenger RNA for checkpoint protein MAD2 and cohesion protein SMC1 beta was compared between oocytes matured with or without FF-MAS. RESULTS: Aged oocytes possessed many bivalents with single distal chiasma at meiosis I. Predivision was especially high in aged oocytes cultured sub-optimally to metaphase II in alpha-minimum essential medium (alpha-MEM). FF-MAS reduced predivision significantly (P &lt; 0.001) but neither reduced non-disjunction nor induced aneuploidy in aged oocytes. Polyploidy was high in FF-MAS-stimulated maturation, in particular in the aged oocytes (P &gt; 0.001). Relative levels of Smc1 beta mRNA appeared increased by maturation in FF-MAS, and mitochondrial clustering was restored. CONCLUSIONS: Sister chromatids of aged oocytes appear to be highly susceptible to precocious chromatid separation, especially when maturation is under sub-optimal conditions, e.g. in the absence of cumulus and FF-MAS. This may relate to some loss of chromatid cohesion during ageing. FF-MAS protects aged oocytes from predivision during maturation, possibly by supporting Smc1 beta expression, thus reducing risks of meiotic errors, but it cannot prevent age-related non-disjunction. Aged oocytes appear prone to loss of co-ordination between nuclear maturation and cytokinesis suggesting age-related relaxed cell cycle control.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>OXFORD UNIV PRESS</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2007</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>

<subject><topic>maturation</topic><topic>oocyte</topic><topic>meiosis</topic><topic>non-disjunction</topic><topic>age</topic>
</subject>


<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>HUMAN REPRODUCTION</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0268-1161</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1460-2350</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">17114196</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000245011700025</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1093/humrep/del442</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>22</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>3</number></detail><extent unit="pages">815-828</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Cukurcam, S., Betzendahl, I., Michel, G., Vogt, E., Hegele-Hartung, C., Lindenthal, B. &amp;amp; Eichenlaub-Ritter, U. (2007). Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes. &lt;em&gt;HUMAN REPRODUCTION&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;22&lt;/em&gt;(3), 815-828. OXFORD UNIV PRESS. doi:10.1093/humrep/del442.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<ama>Cukurcam S, Betzendahl I, Michel G, et al. Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes. &lt;em&gt;HUMAN REPRODUCTION&lt;/em&gt;. 2007;22(3):815-828.</ama>
<harvard1>Cukurcam, S., et al., 2007. Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes. &lt;em&gt;HUMAN REPRODUCTION&lt;/em&gt;, 22(3), p 815-828.</harvard1>
<bio1>Cukurcam S, Betzendahl I, Michel G, Vogt E, Hegele-Hartung C, Lindenthal B, Eichenlaub-Ritter U (2007) &lt;br /&gt;Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes.&lt;br /&gt;HUMAN REPRODUCTION 22(3): 815-828.</bio1>
<aps>S.  Cukurcam, et al., Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes, HUMAN REPRODUCTION &lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt;, 815-828 (2007).</aps>
<wels>Cukurcam, S.; Betzendahl, I.; Michel, G.; Vogt, E.; Hegele-Hartung, C.; Lindenthal, B.; Eichenlaub-Ritter, U. (2007): Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes &lt;em&gt;HUMAN REPRODUCTION&lt;/em&gt;,22:(3): 815-828.</wels>
<default>Cukurcam S, Betzendahl I, Michel G, Vogt E, Hegele-Hartung C, Lindenthal B, Eichenlaub-Ritter U (2007) &lt;br /&gt;HUMAN REPRODUCTION 22(3): 815-828.</default>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Cukurcam, S., Betzendahl, I., Michel, G., Vogt, E., Hegele-Hartung, C., Lindenthal, B., &amp;amp; Eichenlaub-Ritter, U. (2007). Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes. &lt;em&gt;HUMAN REPRODUCTION&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;22&lt;/em&gt;(3), 815-828.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<ieee>S. Cukurcam, et al., “Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes”, &lt;em&gt;HUMAN REPRODUCTION&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 22, 2007,  pp. 815-828.</ieee>
<mla>Cukurcam, S., Betzendahl, I., Michel, G., Vogt, E., Hegele-Hartung, C., Lindenthal, B., and Eichenlaub-Ritter, Ursula. “Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes”. &lt;em&gt;HUMAN REPRODUCTION&lt;/em&gt; 22.3 (2007): 815-828.</mla>
<lncs>Cukurcam, S., Betzendahl, I., Michel, G., Vogt, E., Hegele-Hartung, C., Lindenthal, B., Eichenlaub-Ritter, U.: Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes. HUMAN REPRODUCTION. 22, 815-828 (2007).</lncs>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Cukurcam, S., Betzendahl, I., Michel, G., Vogt, E., Hegele-Hartung, C., Lindenthal, B., and Eichenlaub-Ritter, Ursula. 2007. “Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes”. &lt;em&gt;HUMAN REPRODUCTION&lt;/em&gt; 22 (3): 815-828.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<angewandte-chemie>S.  Cukurcam, I.  Betzendahl, G.  Michel, E.  Vogt, C.  Hegele-Hartung, B.  Lindenthal, and U.  Eichenlaub-Ritter, “Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes”, &lt;em&gt;HUMAN REPRODUCTION&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;2007&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;22&lt;/em&gt;, 815-828.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Cukurcam, S., Betzendahl, I., Michel, G., Vogt, E., Hegele-Hartung, C., Lindenthal, B., &amp;amp; Eichenlaub-Ritter, U. (2007). Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes. &lt;em&gt;HUMAN REPRODUCTION&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;22&lt;/em&gt;(3), 815-828.</apa>
<frontiers>Cukurcam, S., Betzendahl, I., Michel, G., Vogt, E., Hegele-Hartung, C., Lindenthal, B., and Eichenlaub-Ritter, U. (2007). Influence of follicular fluid meiosis-activating sterol on aneuploidy rate and precocious chromatid segregation in aged mouse oocytes. &lt;em&gt;HUMAN REPRODUCTION&lt;/em&gt; 22, 815-828.</frontiers>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1595044</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T12:16:32Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-01-25T18:01:15Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1595044</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1595044</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
