<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Thomas</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Welskopp</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">123889</identifier></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Ignacio</namePart><namePart type="family">Olábarri</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">Francisco J.</namePart><namePart type="family">Caspistegui</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Schule für Historische Forschung</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">3652153</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Bielefeld Graduate School in History and Sociology</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">6747229</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>

<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Geschichte moderner Gesellschaften</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">3791091</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>Ediciones Universidad de Navarra</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">2005</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002)</title></titleInfo>
<part><extent unit="pages">103-128</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Welskopp, T. (2005). “Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries” in &lt;em&gt;The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. I.  Olábarri and F. J.  Caspistegui (Barañàin (Navarra): Ediciones Universidad de Navarra), 103-128.</frontiers>
<apa>Welskopp, T. (2005). Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries. In I.  Olábarri &amp;amp; F. J.  Caspistegui (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 103-128). Barañàin (Navarra): Ediciones Universidad de Navarra.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>T.  Welskopp, in &lt;em&gt;The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002)&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: I. Olábarri, F.J. Caspistegui), Ediciones Universidad De Navarra, Barañàin (Navarra), &lt;strong&gt;2005&lt;/strong&gt;, p. 103-128.</angewandte-chemie>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Welskopp, Thomas. 2005. “Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries”. In &lt;em&gt;The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002)&lt;/em&gt;, ed. Ignacio Olábarri and Francisco J. Caspistegui, 103-128. Barañàin (Navarra): Ediciones Universidad de Navarra.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs>Welskopp, T.: Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries. In: Olábarri, I. and Caspistegui, F.J. (eds.) The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002). p. 103-128. Ediciones Universidad de Navarra, Barañàin (Navarra) (2005).</lncs>
<mla>Welskopp, Thomas. “Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries”. &lt;em&gt;The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002)&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. Ignacio Olábarri and Francisco J. Caspistegui. Barañàin (Navarra): Ediciones Universidad de Navarra, 2005. 103-128.</mla>
<ieee>T. Welskopp, “Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries”, &lt;em&gt;The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002)&lt;/em&gt;, I. Olábarri and F.J. Caspistegui, eds.,  Barañàin (Navarra): Ediciones Universidad de Navarra, 2005,  pp.103-128.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Welskopp, T. (2005). Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries. In I.  Olábarri &amp;amp; F. J.  Caspistegui (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002)&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 103-128). Barañàin (Navarra): Ediciones Universidad de Navarra.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Welskopp T (2005)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002). Olábarri I, Caspistegui FJ (Eds);Barañàin (Navarra): Ediciones Universidad de Navarra:  103-128.</default>
<wels>Welskopp, T. (2005): Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries. In: Ignacio Olábarri; Francisco J. Caspistegui (Hrsg.):  The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002). Barañàin (Navarra): Ediciones Universidad de Navarra.  S. 103-128.</wels>
<bio1>Welskopp T (2005) &lt;br /&gt;Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries. &lt;br /&gt;In:  The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002). Olábarri I, Caspistegui FJ (Eds); Barañàin (Navarra): Ediciones Universidad de Navarra:  103-128.</bio1>
<aps>T.  Welskopp, Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries, in &lt;em&gt;The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002)&lt;/em&gt;, edited by I.  Olábarri and F. J.  Caspistegui (Ediciones Universidad de Navarra, Barañàin (Navarra), 2005), p. 103-128.</aps>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Welskopp, T. (2005). Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries. &lt;em&gt;The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002)&lt;/em&gt; (S. 103-128). Barañàin (Navarra): Ediciones Universidad de Navarra.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<harvard1>Welskopp, T., 2005. Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries. In I.  Olábarri &amp;amp; F. J.  Caspistegui, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002)&lt;/em&gt;.  Barañàin (Navarra): Ediciones Universidad de Navarra, pp. 103-128.</harvard1>
<ama>Welskopp T. Alien Allies. The Relations between History, Sociology, and Economics in Germany, 19th-20th Centuries. In: Olábarri I, Caspistegui FJ, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Strengh of History at the Doors of the New Millenium. History and the other Social and Human Sciences along XXth Century (1899-2002)&lt;/em&gt;. Barañàin (Navarra): Ediciones Universidad de Navarra;  2005: 103-128.</ama>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1857182</recordIdentifier><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2012-08-27T09:17:30Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1857182</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1857182</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
