<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>article</genre>

<titleInfo><title>The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>


<note type="qualityControlled">yes</note>

<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Farr</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">M</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Pieper</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">J</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Calvete</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">Harald</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Tschesche</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role><identifier type="unibi">19406</identifier></name>







<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Biochemie I</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">17967</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>








<abstract lang="eng">Tissue inhibitors of metalloproteinases (TIMPs) are the physiological, specific inhibitors of matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs) forming tight, noncovalent complexes. Therefore they control the proteolytic activity of MMPs toward the extracellular matrix. To analyze the inhibition of the &quot;activated&quot; and &quot;superactivated&quot; variants of human neutrophil collagenase (MMP-8) by TIMP-2, we determined complex dissociation constants using biomolecular interaction analysis (BIA). As it is known that the association rate constants can exceed the limits of the BIA instruments, the biomolecular interaction analysis was used to examine the equlibrium situation. The dissociation constants were determined by fitting the parameters of the mathematical term for the binding of collagenase onto the TIMP-coupled sensor chip surface to the saturation curve derived from individual sensorgrams. The resulting values are in the nanomolar range and correlate with the results of fluorescence kinetics. These data reveal that TIMP-2 (the recombinant inhibitory domain of human TIMP-2 and bovine TIMP-2 isolated from seminal plama) is a better inhibitor of the activated neutrophil collagenase than of the superactivated variant (the recombinant catalytic domain of human MMP-8). It has been demonstrated by X-ray analysis that the N-terminal heptapeptide only of superactivated MMP-8 is attached by a salt bridge and hydrophobic interaction to the C-terminal helix. Because these interactions have to be disrupted in the complex formation with TIMP we assume that the activated variant enables higher flexibility and a tighter induced fit in the complex formation. Therefore superactivation of MMP-8 correlates with weaker inhibition by TIMP-2.</abstract>

<originInfo><publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1999</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>BIOCHEMISTRY</title></titleInfo>
  <identifier type="issn">0006-2960</identifier>
  <identifier type="eIssn">1520-4995</identifier>
  <identifier type="MEDLINE">10353844</identifier>
  <identifier type="ISI">000080691200036</identifier><identifier type="doi">10.1021/bi982618f</identifier>
<part><detail type="volume"><number>38</number></detail><detail type="issue"><number>22</number></detail><extent unit="pages">7332-7338</extent>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<frontiers>Farr, M., Pieper, M., Calvete, J., and Tschesche, H. (1999). The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis. &lt;em&gt;BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 38, 7332-7338.</frontiers>
<apa>Farr, M., Pieper, M., Calvete, J., &amp;amp; Tschesche, H. (1999). The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis. &lt;em&gt;BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;38&lt;/em&gt;(22), 7332-7338.</apa>
<angewandte-chemie>M.  Farr, M.  Pieper, J.  Calvete, and H.  Tschesche, “The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis”, &lt;em&gt;BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;1999&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;38&lt;/em&gt;, 7332-7338.</angewandte-chemie>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Farr, M, Pieper, M, Calvete, J, and Tschesche, Harald. 1999. “The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis”. &lt;em&gt;BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 38 (22): 7332-7338.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<lncs>Farr, M., Pieper, M., Calvete, J., Tschesche, H.: The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis. BIOCHEMISTRY. 38, 7332-7338 (1999).</lncs>
<mla>Farr, M, Pieper, M, Calvete, J, and Tschesche, Harald. “The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis”. &lt;em&gt;BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt; 38.22 (1999): 7332-7338.</mla>
<ieee>M. Farr, et al., “The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis”, &lt;em&gt;BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;,  vol. 38, 1999,  pp. 7332-7338.</ieee>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Farr, M., Pieper, M., Calvete, J., &amp;amp; Tschesche, H. (1999). The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis. &lt;em&gt;BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;38&lt;/em&gt;(22), 7332-7338.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<default>Farr M, Pieper M, Calvete J, Tschesche H (1999) &lt;br /&gt;BIOCHEMISTRY 38(22): 7332-7338.</default>
<wels>Farr, M.; Pieper, M.; Calvete, J.; Tschesche, H. (1999): The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis &lt;em&gt;BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;,38:(22): 7332-7338.</wels>
<aps>M.  Farr, et al., The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis, BIOCHEMISTRY &lt;strong&gt;38&lt;/strong&gt;, 7332-7338 (1999).</aps>
<bio1>Farr M, Pieper M, Calvete J, Tschesche H (1999) &lt;br /&gt;The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis.&lt;br /&gt;BIOCHEMISTRY 38(22): 7332-7338.</bio1>
<ama>Farr M, Pieper M, Calvete J, Tschesche H. The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis. &lt;em&gt;BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;. 1999;38(22):7332-7338.</ama>
<harvard1>Farr, M., et al., 1999. The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis. &lt;em&gt;BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, 38(22), p 7332-7338.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Farr, M., Pieper, M., Calvete, J. &amp;amp; Tschesche, H. (1999). The N-terminus of collagenase MMP-8 determines superactivity and inhibition: A relation of structure and function analyzed by biomolecular interaction analysis. &lt;em&gt;BIOCHEMISTRY&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;38&lt;/em&gt;(22), 7332-7338. AMER CHEMICAL SOC. doi:10.1021/bi982618f.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1622935</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-04-28T13:05:54Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2011-12-08T12:43:46Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1622935</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1622935</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
