<?xml version='1.0'?>

<searchRetrieveResponse xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
<version>1.1</version>
<numberOfRecords>1</numberOfRecords>
<records>
<record><recordSchema>info:srw/schema/1/mods-v3.3</recordSchema><recordPacking>xml</recordPacking><recordData>
<mods version="3.3"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd">
<genre>book chapter</genre>

<titleInfo><title>What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories?</title></titleInfo>


<note type="publicationStatus">published</note>



<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">A.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Angleitner</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal">
  <namePart type="given">R.</namePart>
  <namePart type="family">Riemann</namePart>
  <role><roleTerm type="text">author</roleTerm> </role></name>



<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">J.</namePart><namePart type="family">Strelau</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>
<name type="personal"><namePart type="given">A.</namePart><namePart type="family">Angleitner</namePart>
  <role> <roleTerm type="text">editor</roleTerm> </role></name>




<name type="corporate">
  <namePart>Abteilung für Psychologie</namePart>
  <identifier type="unibi">10026</identifier>
  <role>
    <roleTerm type="text">department</roleTerm>
  </role>
</name>









<originInfo><publisher>Plenum Press</publisher><dateIssued encoding="w3cdtf">1991</dateIssued>
</originInfo>
<language><languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
</language>



<relatedItem type="host"><titleInfo><title>Explorations in Temperament</title></titleInfo>
<part>
</part>
</relatedItem>


<extension>
<bibliographicCitation>
<aps>A.  Angleitner and R.  Riemann, What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories?, in &lt;em&gt;Explorations in Temperament&lt;/em&gt;, edited by J.  Strelau and A.   Angleitner (Plenum Press, New York, 1991).</aps>
<bio1>Angleitner A, Riemann R (1991) &lt;br /&gt;What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? &lt;br /&gt;In:  Explorations in Temperament. Strelau J, Angleitner A (Eds); New York: Plenum Press.</bio1>
<ama>Angleitner A, Riemann R. What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? In: Strelau J, Angleitner A, eds. &lt;em&gt;Explorations in Temperament&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Plenum Press;  1991.</ama>
<harvard1>Angleitner, A., &amp;amp; Riemann, R., 1991. What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? In J.  Strelau &amp;amp; A.   Angleitner, eds. &lt;em&gt;Explorations in Temperament&lt;/em&gt;.  New York: Plenum Press.</harvard1>
<dgps>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Angleitner, A. &amp;amp; Riemann, R. (1991). What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? &lt;em&gt;Explorations in Temperament&lt;/em&gt;. New York: Plenum Press.&lt;/div&gt;</dgps>
<default>Angleitner A, Riemann R (1991)  &lt;br /&gt;In:  Explorations in Temperament. Strelau J, Angleitner A (Eds);New York: Plenum Press.</default>
<wels>Angleitner, A.; Riemann, R. (1991): What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? In: J. Strelau; A.  Angleitner (Hrsg.):  Explorations in Temperament. New York: Plenum Press.</wels>
<apa_indent>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Angleitner, A., &amp;amp; Riemann, R. (1991). What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? In J.  Strelau &amp;amp; A.   Angleitner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Explorations in Temperament&lt;/em&gt; New York: Plenum Press.&lt;/div&gt;</apa_indent>
<mla>Angleitner, A., and Riemann, R. “What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories?”. &lt;em&gt;Explorations in Temperament&lt;/em&gt;. Ed. J. Strelau and A.  Angleitner. New York: Plenum Press, 1991.</mla>
<lncs>Angleitner, A., Riemann, R.: What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? In: Strelau, J. and Angleitner, A. (eds.) Explorations in Temperament.  Plenum Press, New York (1991).</lncs>
<ieee>A. Angleitner and R. Riemann, “What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories?”, &lt;em&gt;Explorations in Temperament&lt;/em&gt;, J. Strelau and A.  Angleitner, eds.,  New York: Plenum Press, 1991.</ieee>
<chicago>&lt;div style=&quot;text-indent:-25px; padding-left:25px;padding-bottom:0px;&quot;&gt;Angleitner, A., and Riemann, R. 1991. “What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories?”. In &lt;em&gt;Explorations in Temperament&lt;/em&gt;, ed. J. Strelau and A.  Angleitner. New York: Plenum Press.&lt;/div&gt;</chicago>
<frontiers>Angleitner, A., and Riemann, R. (1991). “What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories?” in &lt;em&gt;Explorations in Temperament&lt;/em&gt;, ed. J.  Strelau and A.   Angleitner (New York: Plenum Press).</frontiers>
<angewandte-chemie>A.  Angleitner, and R.  Riemann, in &lt;em&gt;Explorations in Temperament&lt;/em&gt; (Eds.: J. Strelau, A.  Angleitner), Plenum Press, New York, &lt;strong&gt;1991&lt;/strong&gt;.</angewandte-chemie>
<apa>Angleitner, A., &amp;amp; Riemann, R. (1991). What can we learn from the discussion of personality questionnaires for the construction of temperament inventories? In J.  Strelau &amp;amp; A.   Angleitner (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Explorations in Temperament&lt;/em&gt; New York: Plenum Press.</apa>
</bibliographicCitation>
</extension>
<recordInfo><recordIdentifier>1917450</recordIdentifier><recordCreationDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-17T09:21:31Z</recordCreationDate><recordChangeDate encoding="w3cdtf">2010-11-17T09:29:57Z</recordChangeDate>
</recordInfo>
</mods>
</recordData><recordPosition>1</recordPosition></record>
</records>

<extraResponseData></extraResponseData> 
<echoedSearchRetrieveRequest><version>1.1</version><query>id=1917450</query><xQuery><searchClause xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/zing/cql/xcql/"><index>id</index><relation><value>=</value></relation><term>1917450</term></searchClause></xQuery></echoedSearchRetrieveRequest>
</searchRetrieveResponse>
